<rss xmlns:atom="http://w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/" version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</title>
      <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      <description>Table of Contents for ChemBioChem. List of articles from both the latest and EarlyView issues.</description>
      <language>en-US</language>
      <copyright>&#169; Wiley-VCH GmbH, Weinheim</copyright>
      <managingEditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com (Chemistry Europe)</managingEditor>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 07:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 07:15:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>Atypon&#174; Literatum&#8482;</generator>
      <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <ttl>10080</ttl>
      <dc:title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
      <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</prism:publicationName>
      <atom:link href="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
      <image>
         <title>Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</title>
         <url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/14397633.jpg</url>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      </image>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500444</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500444</guid>
         <title>Investigating the Interaction Profile of Unconjugated Ubiquitin: Chemical Biology and Affinity Enrichment Mass Spectrometric Approaches</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
This mini review provides insights into the synergistic power of chemical biology techniques for generating defined ubiquitin (Ub) variants and the use of affinity enrichment mass spectrometry to decipher the Ub code. It focuses on unconjugated Ub variants, which have emerged as additional signaling molecules in the Ub lexicon. Furthermore, it outlines the use of this approach with Ub&#8208;like proteins. (Figure created in BioRender. (2025) https://BioRender.com/7vby989).

The covalent attachment of ubiquitin (Ub) to target proteins (ubiquitylation) represents one of the most versatile post&#8208;translational modifications (PTM) in eukaryotic cells. Substrate modifications range from a single Ub moiety being attached to a target protein to complex Ub chains that can also contain Ubls (Ub&#8208;like proteins) or chemical modifications like acetylation or phosphorylation. The entirety of this complex system is entitled as &#8220;the Ub code&#8221;. To regulate the Ub code, cells have an arsenal of enzymes to install, translate, and reverse these modifications. However, deciphering the Ub code is challenging due to the difficulty of generating defined Ub/Ubl&#8722;protein conjugates. In this mini review, an overview of chemical biology techniques for the generation of defined Ub variants and their subsequent application in affinity enrichment experiments to identify interacting proteins by mass spectrometry is provided. The main focus is on unconjugated Ub variants since they are not well understood even though a &#8220;second messenger&#8221;&#8208;like function of those have been found. Finally, the opportunities to expand this approach to Ubl proteins are briefly discussed.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/734ff4c4-7820-4391-9633-4f847a999121/cbic70051-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Investigating the Interaction Profile of Unconjugated Ubiquitin: Chemical Biology and Affinity Enrichment Mass Spectrometric Approaches"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mini review provides insights into the synergistic power of chemical biology techniques for generating defined ubiquitin (Ub) variants and the use of affinity enrichment mass spectrometry to decipher the Ub code. It focuses on unconjugated Ub variants, which have emerged as additional signaling molecules in the Ub lexicon. Furthermore, it outlines the use of this approach with Ub-like proteins. (Figure created in BioRender. (2025) &lt;a target="_blank"
   title="Link to external resource"
   href="https://BioRender.com/7vby989"&gt;https://BioRender.com/7vby989&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The covalent attachment of ubiquitin (Ub) to target proteins (ubiquitylation) represents one of the most versatile post-translational modifications (PTM) in eukaryotic cells. Substrate modifications range from a single Ub moiety being attached to a target protein to complex Ub chains that can also contain Ubls (Ub-like proteins) or chemical modifications like acetylation or phosphorylation. The entirety of this complex system is entitled as &#8220;the Ub code&#8221;. To regulate the Ub code, cells have an arsenal of enzymes to install, translate, and reverse these modifications. However, deciphering the Ub code is challenging due to the difficulty of generating defined Ub/Ubl&#8722;protein conjugates. In this mini review, an overview of chemical biology techniques for the generation of defined Ub variants and their subsequent application in affinity enrichment experiments to identify interacting proteins by mass spectrometry is provided. The main focus is on unconjugated Ub variants since they are not well understood even though a &#8220;second messenger&#8221;-like function of those have been found. Finally, the opportunities to expand this approach to Ubl proteins are briefly discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Simon Maria Kienle, 
Katrin Stuber
</dc:creator>
         <category>Concept</category>
         <dc:title>Investigating the Interaction Profile of Unconjugated Ubiquitin: Chemical Biology and Affinity Enrichment Mass Spectrometric Approaches</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500444</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500444</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500444</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Concept</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500328</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500328</guid>
         <title>Biofilm Eradication Using Water&#8208;Soluble Silver(I) Coumarin Complexes</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Coumarin&#8208;based silver complexes have excellent antimicrobial activity, but such complexes are typically insoluble in water and unstable under ambient light conditions. Herein, a water soluble coumarin&#8208;silver(I) complex is successfully prepared with the ability to eradicate preformed MRSA biofilms. A triphenylphosphine adduct of the complex lost all antimicrobial activity, though an improvement in solubility and light stability are noted.

Water&#8208;soluble photostable coumarin acetate complexes of silver(I) are successfully synthesized and characterized and found to have the ability to eradicate preformed MRSA biofilms. Substitution with short PEG chains at the 4&#8208;position of the coumarin ring allows the subsequent synthesis of water&#8208;soluble coumarin oxyacetate ligands which successfully allowed silver(I) complex formation. The new complexes are characterized by IR and NMR spectroscopy, microanalysis and high&#8208;resolution mass spectrometry where possible. Previous unPEGylated analogs has shown excellent antimicrobial activity against the pathogenic bacteria MRSA, Escherichia coli and Pseudomonas aeruginosa and that activity is maintained in the PEGylated complexes. However, the solubility of the un&#8208;PEGylated analogs is limited to DMSO, and those silver(I) complexes are unstable in ambient light conditions. Both issues are resolved with the new PEGylated complexes reported here and importantly the ability to eradicate preformed biofilms of MRSA is demonstrated. In addition, a triphenylphosphine adduct complex is also synthesized, but this complex has reduced activity compared to the simple PEGylated complex.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/1a4fd255-7a8d-4cb5-839d-5b40d6ebb1a9/cbic70029-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Biofilm Eradication Using Water-Soluble Silver(I) Coumarin Complexes"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coumarin-based silver complexes have excellent antimicrobial activity, but such complexes are typically insoluble in water and unstable under ambient light conditions. Herein, a water soluble coumarin-silver(I) complex is successfully prepared with the ability to eradicate preformed MRSA biofilms. A triphenylphosphine adduct of the complex lost all antimicrobial activity, though an improvement in solubility and light stability are noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water-soluble photostable coumarin acetate complexes of silver(I) are successfully synthesized and characterized and found to have the ability to eradicate preformed MRSA biofilms. Substitution with short PEG chains at the 4-position of the coumarin ring allows the subsequent synthesis of water-soluble coumarin oxyacetate ligands which successfully allowed silver(I) complex formation. The new complexes are characterized by IR and NMR spectroscopy, microanalysis and high-resolution mass spectrometry where possible. Previous unPEGylated analogs has shown excellent antimicrobial activity against the pathogenic bacteria MRSA, &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/i&gt; and that activity is maintained in the PEGylated complexes. However, the solubility of the un-PEGylated analogs is limited to DMSO, and those silver(I) complexes are unstable in ambient light conditions. Both issues are resolved with the new PEGylated complexes reported here and importantly the ability to eradicate preformed biofilms of MRSA is demonstrated. In addition, a triphenylphosphine adduct complex is also synthesized, but this complex has reduced activity compared to the simple PEGylated complex.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Erika Mooney, 
Gordon Cooke, 
Emma Caraher, 
Fintan Kelleher, 
Bernadette S. Creaven
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Biofilm Eradication Using Water&#8208;Soluble Silver(I) Coumarin Complexes</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500328</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500328</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500328</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500359</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500359</guid>
         <title>Microbial Synthesis of Six Rosmarinic Acid Derivatives</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
This study engineers Escherichia coli for the biosynthesis of six rosmarinic acid (RA) derivatives (IA, isorinic acid; CPLA, caffeoyl phenyllactic acid; PSA, p&#8208;coumaroyl salvianic acid; P4PLA, p&#8208;coumaroyl 4&#8208;hydroxyphenyllactic acid; PPLA, p&#8208;coumaroyl phenyllactic acid). Three process strategies: single&#8208;cell, stepwise, and coculture synthesis are&#160;evaluated to optimize production. Results show that the optimal bioprocess is compound&#8208;dependent: single&#8208;cell for PPLA/P4PLA, stepwise for CPLA/PSA/RA, and coculture for IA.

Rosmarinic acid (RA) is a phytochemical that exhibits a variety of biological activities. The biological synthesis pathway of RA has been well&#8208;established in plants. In this study, the shikimate pathway is engineered to enhance the availability of precursor substrates and the biosynthetic pathway is reconstructed to produce six RA derivatives: p&#8208;coumaroyl phenyllactic acid (PPLA), p&#8208;coumaroyl 4&#8208;hydroxyphenyllactic acid (P4PLA), caffeoyl phenyllactic acid (CPLA), p&#8208;coumaroyl salvinic acid (PSA), rosmarinic acid (RA), and isorinic acid (IA). To identify the optimal method for maximizing the production of the target compounds while minimizing the formation of unwanted byproducts, single&#8208;cell, stepwise, and coculture approaches are employed. Using the single&#8208;cell method, 145.1&#8201;mg L&#8722;1 of PPLA and 361.6&#8201;mg L&#8722;1 of P4PLA&#160;are&#160;synthesized. The stepwise method yields 28.0&#8201;mg&#8201;L&#8722;1 of CPLA, 23.4&#8201;mg&#8201;L&#8722;1 of PSA (which contains synthesized IA), and 10.9&#8201;mg&#8201;L&#8722;1 of RA. Finally, the coculture method results in the synthesis of 40.2&#8201;mg&#8201;L&#8722;1 of IA (which contains synthesized PSA).
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/55288892-ad1f-4e02-9c63-9cc737a566f1/cbic70028-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Microbial Synthesis of Six Rosmarinic Acid Derivatives"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study engineers &lt;i&gt;Escherichia&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;coli&lt;/i&gt; for the biosynthesis of six rosmarinic acid (RA) derivatives (IA, isorinic acid; CPLA, caffeoyl phenyllactic acid; PSA, &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-coumaroyl salvianic acid; P4PLA, &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-coumaroyl 4-hydroxyphenyllactic acid; PPLA, &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-coumaroyl phenyllactic acid). Three process strategies: single-cell, stepwise, and coculture synthesis are&#160;evaluated to optimize production. Results show that the optimal bioprocess is compound-dependent: single-cell for PPLA/P4PLA, stepwise for CPLA/PSA/RA, and coculture for IA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosmarinic acid (RA) is a phytochemical that exhibits a variety of biological activities. The biological synthesis pathway of RA has been well-established in plants. In this study, the shikimate pathway is engineered to enhance the availability of precursor substrates and the biosynthetic pathway is reconstructed to produce six RA derivatives: &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-coumaroyl phenyllactic acid (PPLA), &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-coumaroyl 4-hydroxyphenyllactic acid (P4PLA), caffeoyl phenyllactic acid (CPLA), &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-coumaroyl salvinic acid (PSA), rosmarinic acid (RA), and isorinic acid (IA). To identify the optimal method for maximizing the production of the target compounds while minimizing the formation of unwanted byproducts, single-cell, stepwise, and coculture approaches are employed. Using the single-cell method, 145.1&#8201;mg L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; of PPLA and 361.6&#8201;mg L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; of P4PLA&#160;are&#160;synthesized. The stepwise method yields 28.0&#8201;mg&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; of CPLA, 23.4&#8201;mg&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; of PSA (which contains synthesized IA), and 10.9&#8201;mg&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; of RA. Finally, the coculture method results in the synthesis of 40.2&#8201;mg&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; of IA (which contains synthesized PSA).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Seung Hoon An, 
Hyun Ji Kang, 
Bong&#8208;Gyu Kim, 
Joong&#8208;Hoon Ahn
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Microbial Synthesis of Six Rosmarinic Acid Derivatives</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500359</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500359</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500359</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500376</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500376</guid>
         <title>Novel Platinum(II) Tetrazine Complex Capable of Live&#8208;Cell IEDDA Reaction</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
The first Pt(II) tetrazine complex, trans&#8208;[PtCl2(dmso)(CH3&#8208;Tz&#8208;Bz&#8208;NH2)] (1), is reported, showing good cytotoxicity against MDA&#8208;MB&#8208;231 cells and undergoing IEDDA reactions with TCO and BCN derivatives. A live&#8208;cell IEDDA reaction in MDA&#8208;MB&#8208;231 cells with a BCN&#8208;bearing BF2&#8208;azadipyrromethene fluorophore is tracked via FLIM, owing to a 0.3&#8201;ns lifetime shift.

The development of the first Pt(II) tetrazine complex, trans&#8208;[Pt(II)Cl2(dmso)(CH3&#8208;Tz&#8208;Bz&#8208;NH2)] (1), is reported, which exhibits good in&#8201;vitro cytotoxicity against MDA&#8208;MB&#8208;231 cells and succesfully undergoes inverse electron demand Diels&#8211;Alder (IEDDA) reactions with trans&#8208;cyclooctene (TCO) and bicyclononyne (BCN) derivates in solution. We demonstrate a live&#8208;cell IEDDA reaction of 1 with a BF2&#8208;azadipyrromethene fluorophore (NIR&#8208;AZA) posessing a BCN handle. A live&#8208;cell bioorthogonal reaction is established using fluorescence lifetime imaging microscopy (FLIM), through a fluorescence lifetime change of 0.3&#8201;ns from BF2&#8208;azadipyrromethene fluorophore starting material to IEDDA Pt fluorophore reaction product. As there is a distinct difference in fluorescence lifetimes between starting material and product, this approach removes the necessity for designing challenging off to on fluorogenic Pt probes and washing steps when developing bioorthogonal cell&#8208;imaging strategies for Pt complexes.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/b02f4cd7-1e9f-4a7f-ac71-b11493ba6f1c/cbic70048-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Novel Platinum(II) Tetrazine Complex Capable of Live-Cell IEDDA Reaction"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Pt(II) tetrazine complex, &lt;i&gt;trans&lt;/i&gt;-[PtCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(dmso)(CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Tz-Bz-NH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)] (1), is reported, showing good cytotoxicity against MDA-MB-231 cells and undergoing IEDDA reactions with TCO and BCN derivatives. A live-cell IEDDA reaction in MDA-MB-231 cells with a BCN-bearing BF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-azadipyrromethene fluorophore is tracked via FLIM, owing to a 0.3&#8201;ns lifetime shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of the first Pt(II) tetrazine complex, &lt;i&gt;trans-&lt;/i&gt;[Pt(II)Cl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(dmso)(CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Tz-Bz-NH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)] (&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;), is reported, which exhibits good in&#8201;vitro cytotoxicity against MDA-MB-231 cells and succesfully undergoes inverse electron demand Diels&#8211;Alder (IEDDA) reactions with &lt;i&gt;trans&lt;/i&gt;-cyclooctene (TCO) and bicyclononyne (BCN) derivates in solution. We demonstrate a live-cell IEDDA reaction of &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; with a BF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-azadipyrromethene fluorophore (NIR-AZA) posessing a BCN handle. A live-cell bioorthogonal reaction is established using fluorescence lifetime imaging microscopy (FLIM), through a fluorescence lifetime change of 0.3&#8201;ns from BF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-azadipyrromethene fluorophore starting material to IEDDA Pt fluorophore reaction product. As there is a distinct difference in fluorescence lifetimes between starting material and product, this approach removes the necessity for designing challenging off to on fluorogenic Pt probes and washing steps when developing bioorthogonal cell-imaging strategies for Pt complexes.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Paul D. O&#8217;Dowd, 
Dan Wu, 
Alby Benny, 
Ellen King, 
Alice Harford, 
Brendan Twamley, 
Olga Piskareva, 
Donal F. O&#8217;Shea, 
Darren M. Griffith
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Novel Platinum(II) Tetrazine Complex Capable of Live&#8208;Cell IEDDA Reaction</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500376</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500376</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500376</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500391</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500391</guid>
         <title>Direct Cytosolic Uptake of Cell Penetrating Peptides with Shortened Sidechains</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
The shorter, the better: Herein, the arginine octamer analog mR8 is demonstrated, which features a shortened sidechain relative to R8 and homoR8, and enters cells via direct translocation. In contrast, peptides R8 and homoR8 primarily utilize endocytosis for cellular entry under the same conditions.

Endocytosis and direct translocation serve as the primary mechanisms by which cell&#8208;penetrating peptides (CPPs) enter cells. Understanding these pathways is vital for unraveling the complexities of cellular uptake, which bears significant relevance to progress in various fields. In this study, the intracellular distribution of arginine octamer analogs is demonstrated to correlate with the length of their side chains. Specifically, peptides with elongated sidechains exhibit enhanced cellular uptake efficiency and a preferential endosomal distribution, whereas mR8&#8212;a peptide with a shortened sidechain&#8212;primarily enters cells via direct translocation and displays cytosolic/nuclear localization. It is further revealed that these structurally analogous peptides exhibit distinct diffusion characteristics and complexation behaviors with model glycosaminoglycans. These findings contribute to a deeper molecular understanding of the cellular uptake mechanisms of peptides.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/bd63e8fc-d8a8-464c-a267-f6989d974ae4/cbic70039-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Direct Cytosolic Uptake of Cell Penetrating Peptides with Shortened Sidechains"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shorter, the better: Herein, the arginine octamer analog &lt;b&gt;mR8&lt;/b&gt; is demonstrated, which features a shortened sidechain relative to &lt;b&gt;R8&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;homoR8&lt;/b&gt;, and enters cells via direct translocation. In contrast, peptides &lt;b&gt;R8&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;homoR8&lt;/b&gt; primarily utilize endocytosis for cellular entry under the same conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endocytosis and direct translocation serve as the primary mechanisms by which cell-penetrating peptides (CPPs) enter cells. Understanding these pathways is vital for unraveling the complexities of cellular uptake, which bears significant relevance to progress in various fields. In this study, the intracellular distribution of arginine octamer analogs is demonstrated to correlate with the length of their side chains. Specifically, peptides with elongated sidechains exhibit enhanced cellular uptake efficiency and a preferential endosomal distribution, whereas mR8&#8212;a peptide with a shortened sidechain&#8212;primarily enters cells via direct translocation and displays cytosolic/nuclear localization. It is further revealed that these structurally analogous peptides exhibit distinct diffusion characteristics and complexation behaviors with model glycosaminoglycans. These findings contribute to a deeper molecular understanding of the cellular uptake mechanisms of peptides.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Dejing Liu, 
Meiying Zhang, 
Mao Li
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Direct Cytosolic Uptake of Cell Penetrating Peptides with Shortened Sidechains</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500391</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500391</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500391</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500415</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500415</guid>
         <title>Selective and pH&#8208;Responsive Macrocyclic Anionophores</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
A versatile macrocycle scaffold containing phenyl units selectively transports anions over OH&#8722;/ H+. The pyridyl analog shows pH responsive anion transport by cotransporting HCl only at low pH.

The ability to selectively control ion transport across membranes is central for identifying synthetic ionophores that can potentially be used as therapeutics for diseases involving dysfunction of natural ion transporters. Herein, a family of C2&#8208;symmetric macrocycles is presented, which is derived from serine or threonine and a disubstituted aromatic moiety. The ion transport behavior of the macrocycles can be precisely tuned by modifying their aromatic core and symmetry. The phenyl&#8208;based macrocycles are highly anion&#8208;selective and do not disturb vesicular pH gradients, a key step toward safe therapeutic use of ionophores with minimal cytotoxic risk. In contrast, the introduction of pH responsive pyridyl units in the macrocycle results in measurable chloride transport only below pH 5, a feature that can be utilized to target the acidic lysosomal compartments. This work highlights a structure&#8208;guided approach to achieving tunable and conditionally active ionophores, with potential implications in biomedical applications.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/1ee95d9f-a965-48a1-929e-66d579ee7023/cbic70027-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Selective and pH-Responsive Macrocyclic Anionophores"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A versatile macrocycle scaffold containing phenyl units selectively transports anions over OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt;/ H&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;. The pyridyl analog shows pH responsive anion transport by cotransporting HCl only at low pH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to selectively control ion transport across membranes is central for identifying synthetic ionophores that can potentially be used as therapeutics for diseases involving dysfunction of natural ion transporters. Herein, a family of &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-symmetric macrocycles is presented, which is derived from serine or threonine and a disubstituted aromatic moiety. The ion transport behavior of the macrocycles can be precisely tuned by modifying their aromatic core and symmetry. The phenyl-based macrocycles are highly anion-selective and do not disturb vesicular pH gradients, a key step toward safe therapeutic use of ionophores with minimal cytotoxic risk. In contrast, the introduction of pH responsive pyridyl units in the macrocycle results in measurable chloride transport only below pH 5, a feature that can be utilized to target the acidic lysosomal compartments. This work highlights a structure-guided approach to achieving tunable and conditionally active ionophores, with potential implications in biomedical applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Biswaranjan Baliarsingh, 
Nandita Madhavan
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Selective and pH&#8208;Responsive Macrocyclic Anionophores</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500415</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500415</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500415</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500428</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500428</guid>
         <title>Resonance Raman Spectroscopic Study of the Unusual [4Fe&#8208;4S]2+ Cluster of IspH, the Last Enzyme of the Methylerythritol Phosphate Pathway for Terpenoid Biosynthesis</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Raman spectroscopy confirms that the apical Fe atom of the [4Fe&#8208;4S]2+ cluster of IspH is linked to H2O molecules and that the (E)&#8208;4&#8208;hydroxy&#8208;3&#8208;methyl&#8208;but&#8208;2&#8208;en&#8208;1&#8208;yl diphosphate substrate and the propargyl diphosphate inhibitor lead to a change of coordination geometry. The loss of octahedral coordination of the apical Fe atom is also very likely when the dimethylallyl diphosphate product is added, while no change is observed with isopentenyl diphosphate.

IspH is the last enzyme of the methylerythritol phosphate pathway. It catalyzes the reductive dehydroxylation of (E)&#8208;4&#8208;hydroxy&#8208;3&#8208;methyl&#8208;but&#8208;2&#8208;en&#8208;1&#8208;yl diphosphate into isopentenyl diphosphate (IPP) and dimethylallyl diphosphate (DMAPP), which are precursors for the biosynthesis of terpenoids, essential molecules for the survival of all living organisms. This pathway is absent in humans, making it a promising target for drug discovery. Escherichia coli IspH harbors an unusual [4Fe&#8208;4S]2+ cluster linked to three conserved cysteines with a unique iron site proposed to be coordinated to three water molecules. Here, the first resonance Raman spectroscopic study of the cluster of IspH in the 2+ oxidation state is reported. Using isotopic labeling with 2H2O and H218O, the bands of the cluster that are sensitive to water coordination or hydrogen bonding are identified. The change of geometry of the cluster upon binding of the substrate, an alkyne diphosphate inhibitor, and the two enzyme products is also analyzed. Distinct binding modes to the cluster may indeed be at the origin of the different distribution of IPP and DMAPP observed during catalysis.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/0c64c77e-8d05-46b4-9841-9bab192b42bb/cbic70036-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Resonance Raman Spectroscopic Study of the Unusual [4Fe-4S]2+ Cluster of IspH, the Last Enzyme of the Methylerythritol Phosphate Pathway for Terpenoid Biosynthesis"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raman spectroscopy confirms that the apical Fe atom of the [4Fe-4S]&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; cluster of IspH is linked to H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O molecules and that the (&lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt;)-4-hydroxy-3-methyl-but-2-en-1-yl diphosphate substrate and the propargyl diphosphate inhibitor lead to a change of coordination geometry. The loss of octahedral coordination of the apical Fe atom is also very likely when the dimethylallyl diphosphate product is added, while no change is observed with isopentenyl diphosphate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IspH is the last enzyme of the methylerythritol phosphate pathway. It catalyzes the reductive dehydroxylation of (&lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt;)-4-hydroxy-3-methyl-but-2-en-1-yl diphosphate into isopentenyl diphosphate (IPP) and dimethylallyl diphosphate (DMAPP), which are precursors for the biosynthesis of terpenoids, essential molecules for the survival of all living organisms. This pathway is absent in humans, making it a promising target for drug discovery. &lt;i&gt;Escherichia&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;coli&lt;/i&gt; IspH harbors an unusual [4Fe-4S]&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; cluster linked to three conserved cysteines with a unique iron site proposed to be coordinated to three water molecules. Here, the first resonance Raman spectroscopic study of the cluster of IspH in the 2+ oxidation state is reported. Using isotopic labeling with &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O, the bands of the cluster that are sensitive to water coordination or hydrogen bonding are identified. The change of geometry of the cluster upon binding of the substrate, an alkyne diphosphate inhibitor, and the two enzyme products is also analyzed. Distinct binding modes to the cluster may indeed be at the origin of the different distribution of IPP and DMAPP observed during catalysis.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Hannah Jobelius, 
Philippe Chaignon, 
Gabriella I. Bianchino, 
Joanna Wandzig, 
Petra Hellwig, 
Myriam Seemann, 
Frederic Melin
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Resonance Raman Spectroscopic Study of the Unusual [4Fe&#8208;4S]2+ Cluster of IspH, the Last Enzyme of the Methylerythritol Phosphate Pathway for Terpenoid Biosynthesis</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500428</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500428</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500428</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500508</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500508</guid>
         <title>Dual&#8208;Targeting of PD&#8208;L1 and Integrin &#945;v&#946;3 for Preclinical PET Imaging of Cancer</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Activation of integrin &#945;v&#946;3 can upregulate the expression of PD&#8208;L1. Here, a dual&#8208;targeting radiotracer capable of simultaneously targeting both PD&#8208;L1 and &#945;v&#946;3 exhibited prolonged tumor accumulation in PET imaging, making it useful for long&#8208;term monitoring of PD&#8208;L1 expression as a guide for preclinical diagnosis and therapy.

The dual&#8208;targeting strategy has demonstrated advantages in enhancing tumor uptake, improving imaging contrast, and ultimately increasing tumor detection rate. PD&#8208;L1 is overexpressed on multiple tumor cells and regulated by &#945;v&#946;3&#8208;integrin. In this study, a dual&#8208;targeting radiotracer, [64Cu]&#8208;PEG&#8208;RGD&#8208;TPP&#8208;1, is developedfor PET/CT imaging of both PD&#8208;L1 and &#945;v&#946;3&#8208;integrin simultaneously, achieving high contrast, enhanced tumor uptake, and prolonged tumor retention time. [64Cu]&#8208;PEG&#8208;RGD&#8208;TPP&#8208;1 comprises the peptide TPP&#8208;1 and cyclic peptide c(RGDyC), linked via a PEG linker. The dual&#8208;targeting molecule had a moderate serum stability (&#8776;60%) in vivo after 1&#8201;hr. This dual&#8208;targeting radiotracer is evaluated and compared with the single&#8208;targeting radiotracers [64Cu]&#8208;PEG&#8208;TPP&#8208;1 and [64Cu]&#8208;TPP&#8208;1. PET imaging and ex vivo biodistribution studies show that [64Cu]&#8208;PEG&#8208;RGD&#8208;TPP&#8208;1 exhibits higher tumor uptake than its single&#8208;targeting counterparts. Moreover, the dual&#8208;targeting radiotracer demonstrated potential for ultrasmall tumor imaging and could be combined with X&#8208;ray irradiation to further enhance PET imaging contrast, thereby improving tumor&#8208;targeting efficiency. These findings suggest that [64Cu]&#8208;PEG&#8208;RGD&#8208;TPP&#8208;1 is a promising noninvasive tracer for detecting tumors expressing PD&#8208;L1 and/or integrin av&#946;3, with the prospect of clinical implementation.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/915a3c0b-412d-4c71-bb35-6369206c12fb/cbic70032-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Dual-Targeting of PD-L1 and Integrin &#945;v&#946;3 for Preclinical PET Imaging of Cancer"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of integrin &#945;v&#946;3 can upregulate the expression of PD-L1. Here, a dual-targeting radiotracer capable of simultaneously targeting both PD-L1 and &#945;&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt;&#946;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; exhibited prolonged tumor accumulation in PET imaging, making it useful for long-term monitoring of PD-L1 expression as a guide for preclinical diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dual-targeting strategy has demonstrated advantages in enhancing tumor uptake, improving imaging contrast, and ultimately increasing tumor detection rate. PD-L1 is overexpressed on multiple tumor cells and regulated by &lt;i&gt;&#945;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-integrin. In this study, a dual-targeting radiotracer, [64Cu]-PEG-RGD-TPP-1, is developedfor PET/CT imaging of both PD-L1 and &lt;i&gt;&#945;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-integrin simultaneously, achieving high contrast, enhanced tumor uptake, and prolonged tumor retention time. [&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt;Cu]-PEG-RGD-TPP-1 comprises the peptide TPP-1 and cyclic peptide c(RGDyC), linked via a PEG linker. The dual-targeting molecule had a moderate serum stability (&#8776;60%) in vivo after 1&#8201;hr. This dual-targeting radiotracer is evaluated and compared with the single-targeting radiotracers [&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt;Cu]-PEG-TPP-1 and [&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt;Cu]-TPP-1. PET imaging and &lt;i&gt;ex vivo&lt;/i&gt; biodistribution studies show that [&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt;Cu]-PEG-RGD-TPP-1 exhibits higher tumor uptake than its single-targeting counterparts. Moreover, the dual-targeting radiotracer demonstrated potential for ultrasmall tumor imaging and could be combined with X-ray irradiation to further enhance PET imaging contrast, thereby improving tumor-targeting efficiency. These findings suggest that [&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt;Cu]-PEG-RGD-TPP-1 is a promising noninvasive tracer for detecting tumors expressing PD-L1 and/or integrin &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, with the prospect of clinical implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Wenhao Liu, 
Xiushuang Yuan, 
Siqi Zhang, 
Xingkai Wang, 
Xin Gao, 
Hao Tian, 
Dun Wang, 
Ming&#8208;Rong Zhang, 
Rui Wang, 
Kuan Hu
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Dual&#8208;Targeting of PD&#8208;L1 and Integrin &#945;v&#946;3 for Preclinical PET Imaging of Cancer</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500508</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500508</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500508</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500266</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500266</guid>
         <title>Selective Lysine Ubiquitination Using Activated Phenol Esters</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Ubiquitination of both peptides and proteins using a novel water&#8208;soluble acylation reagent, based on a 2,4&#8208;dichloro&#8208;6&#8208;sulfonic acid phenol ester, is presented. At alkaline pH, fast lysine ubiquitination is observed on model peptide FLYRANK, and its regioselectivity is confirmed using controls. The same selective lysine ubiquitination is shown on the Fau gene encoded Ubiquitin&#8208;like protein (FUBI) protein, which is confirmed using liquid chromatography tandem mass&#8208;spectrometry analysis/mass spectrometry analysis.

Ubiquitination of target proteins is an essential post&#8208;translational modification influencing a wide variety of cellular processes. Herein, the use of a novel water&#8208;soluble acylation reagent based on the 2,4&#8208;dichloro&#8208;6&#8208;sulfonic acid phenol ester of ubiquitin is described for efficient and selective ubiquitin modification of peptides. Under alkaline conditions, this reagent is swift and regioselective toward lysine acylation, while at neutral pH it shows loss of regioselectivity and is able to acylate both lysine and N&#8208;terminal modification at reduced speeds. As proof of concept, a model peptide is utilized to demonstrate this strategy, proving to be successful. Then the ubiquitination of a synthetic protein called Fau gene encoded Ubiquitin&#8208;like protein (FUBI) is performed under alkaline conditions followed by tandem MS analysis, proving that the selective lysine ubiquitination works to prepare protein&#8211;protein conjugates.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2cd92c57-c79a-42cc-aaea-42d57a4f4bf2/cbic70023-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Selective Lysine Ubiquitination Using Activated Phenol Esters"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitination of both peptides and proteins using a novel water-soluble acylation reagent, based on a 2,4-dichloro-6-sulfonic acid phenol ester, is presented. At alkaline pH, fast lysine ubiquitination is observed on model peptide FLYRANK, and its regioselectivity is confirmed using controls. The same selective lysine ubiquitination is shown on the Fau gene encoded Ubiquitin-like protein (FUBI) protein, which is confirmed using liquid chromatography tandem mass-spectrometry analysis/mass spectrometry analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitination of target proteins is an essential post-translational modification influencing a wide variety of cellular processes. Herein, the use of a novel water-soluble acylation reagent based on the 2,4-dichloro-6-sulfonic acid phenol ester of ubiquitin is described for efficient and selective ubiquitin modification of peptides. Under alkaline conditions, this reagent is swift and regioselective toward lysine acylation, while at neutral pH it shows loss of regioselectivity and is able to acylate both lysine and N-terminal modification at reduced speeds. As proof of concept, a model peptide is utilized to demonstrate this strategy, proving to be successful. Then the ubiquitination of a synthetic protein called Fau gene encoded Ubiquitin-like protein (FUBI) is performed under alkaline conditions followed by tandem MS analysis, proving that the selective lysine ubiquitination works to prepare protein&#8211;protein conjugates.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Halana C. Vlaming, 
Yara Huppelschoten, 
Rayman T. N. Tjokrodirijo, 
Peter A. van Veelen, 
Francesca D&#8217;Amico, 
Kim B. Jensen, 
Jens Buchardt, 
Thomas E. Nielsen, 
Bhavesh Premdjee, 
Gerbrand J. van der Heden van Noort
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Selective Lysine Ubiquitination Using Activated Phenol Esters</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500266</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500266</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500266</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500424</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500424</guid>
         <title>Cationic Fluorophores on Citrate&#8208;Stabilized Gold Nanoparticles for Fluorogenic Detection of Nanomolar Amyloid Beta Monomers</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Cationic fluorophores are prepared from their respective radical species, after release of an electron, and are utilized for amyloid beta detection after being conjugated with citrate&#8208;stabilized gold nanoparticles. The turn&#8208;on fluorescence mechanism is used for detect amyloid beta monomer in nanomolar concentration from 10 to 130 nM.

Gold nanoparticle&#8208;based fluorogenic enhancement for detection of analytes requires a strategy to quench the fluorescence property of the fluorophore effectively before the treatment of analytes. The designing principle of the fluorophore for gold nanoparticle surface coverage is challenging in comparison with chemical modification of a small organic fluorophore for similar quenching. In this report, the ionic interactions between negatively charged gold nanoparticle and cationic fluorophores have been considered . The interaction between two ionic systems is much more effective than the interaction between charged gold nanoparticle and neutral fluorophore for fluorescence quenching. This simple and sensitive strategy for selective nanomolar detection of monomeric amyloid beta (A&#946;) has been demonstrated using the combination of citrate&#8208;stabilized gold nanoparticles (AuNP) and cationic fluorophores (1 and 2). The cationic fluorophores have been generated in aqueous medium from their corresponding radicals by releasing electron. The prompt turn on fluorescence response of 1 has found to be superior to the similar response from 2. The response is suitable for the fluorogenic detection of A&#946; monomer within the concentration range 10&#8211;130&#8201;nM. Further, both the cationic probes have further been utilized successfully to detect monomeric A&#946; level in artificial cerebrospinal fluid and human serum albumin.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/77237d26-a959-4cc3-b4df-ee3d0ecdbdad/cbic70045-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Cationic Fluorophores on Citrate-Stabilized Gold Nanoparticles for Fluorogenic Detection of Nanomolar Amyloid Beta Monomers"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cationic fluorophores are prepared from their respective radical species, after release of an electron, and are utilized for amyloid beta detection after being conjugated with citrate-stabilized gold nanoparticles. The turn-on fluorescence mechanism is used for detect amyloid beta monomer in nanomolar concentration from 10 to 130 nM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold nanoparticle-based fluorogenic enhancement for detection of analytes requires a strategy to quench the fluorescence property of the fluorophore effectively before the treatment of analytes. The designing principle of the fluorophore for gold nanoparticle surface coverage is challenging in comparison with chemical modification of a small organic fluorophore for similar quenching. In this report, the ionic interactions between negatively charged gold nanoparticle and cationic fluorophores have been considered . The interaction between two ionic systems is much more effective than the interaction between charged gold nanoparticle and neutral fluorophore for fluorescence quenching. This simple and sensitive strategy for selective nanomolar detection of monomeric amyloid beta (A&#946;) has been demonstrated using the combination of citrate-stabilized gold nanoparticles (AuNP) and cationic fluorophores (&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;). The cationic fluorophores have been generated in aqueous medium from their corresponding radicals by releasing electron. The prompt turn on fluorescence response of &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; has found to be superior to the similar response from &lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;. The response is suitable for the fluorogenic detection of A&#946; monomer within the concentration range 10&#8211;130&#8201;nM. Further, both the cationic probes have further been utilized successfully to detect monomeric A&#946; level in artificial cerebrospinal fluid and human serum albumin.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Mohit Kulshrestha, 
Soumen Ghosh, 
Kalyan K. Sadhu
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Cationic Fluorophores on Citrate&#8208;Stabilized Gold Nanoparticles for Fluorogenic Detection of Nanomolar Amyloid Beta Monomers</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500424</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500424</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500424</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500437</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500437</guid>
         <title>Characterizing Mixed Single&#8208;Chain Amphiphile&#8208;Based Coacervates as a Robust Protocell System</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Amphiphiles present in the early Earth's prebiotic soup have been shown to readily self&#8208;assemble into compartments. However, their assembly into coacervates remains underexplored. In this study, coacervates resulting from nonanoic acid (NA), nonanol (NOH) and tyramine have been characterized. These remain stable across a wide range of pH, temperature and salt conditions. They also efficiently sequester RNA and support nonenzymatic RNA primer extension, highlighting their potential role as protocells.

Prebiotic soup would have been a dilute pool of chemicals, which would have undergone reactions to form biologically relevant precursors during life's origin. Herein, compartments formed by liquid&#8211;liquid phase separation (LLPS) can concentrated these chemicals, thereby catalyzing their reactions. In this backdrop, LLPS&#8208;based systems are being studied, with a decanoic acid&#8208;based coacervate system recently described as a model protocell. This is in contrast to studies where fatty acids vesicles are predominantly explored as protocells. Further, exogenous delivery and endogenous synthesis of fatty acids suggest greater prevalence of shorter chain lengths of single&#8208;chain amphiphiles on the early Earth. In this backdrop, a mixed amphiphile&#8208;based coacervate system composed of nonanoic acid (NA), nonanol (NOH) and tyramine&#160;is&#160;characterized, which can form coacervates over a broad range of pHs, temperatures, and salt concentrations. This is noteworthy as compositionally heterogenous vesicles have also been shown to have advantages over pure fatty acid vesicles. Additionally, RNA sequestration&#160;is demonstrated in these coacervates, which gets enhanced upon addition of cationic amino acids, emphasizing the importance of cosolute interactions in the prebiotic soup. Nonenzymatic template&#8208;directed primer extension is&#160;also&#160;demonstrated in these coacervates, suggesting a potential functional role for these compartments during life's origin.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/9a7e2591-a871-47ff-91d0-4839d829a656/cbic70034-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Characterizing Mixed Single-Chain Amphiphile-Based Coacervates as a Robust Protocell System"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amphiphiles present in the early Earth's prebiotic soup have been shown to readily self-assemble into compartments. However, their assembly into coacervates remains underexplored. In this study, coacervates resulting from nonanoic acid (NA), nonanol (NOH) and tyramine have been characterized. These remain stable across a wide range of pH, temperature and salt conditions. They also efficiently sequester RNA and support nonenzymatic RNA primer extension, highlighting their potential role as protocells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prebiotic soup would have been a dilute pool of chemicals, which would have undergone reactions to form biologically relevant precursors during life's origin. Herein, compartments formed by liquid&#8211;liquid phase separation (LLPS) can concentrated these chemicals, thereby catalyzing their reactions. In this backdrop, LLPS-based systems are being studied, with a decanoic acid-based coacervate system recently described as a model protocell. This is in contrast to studies where fatty acids vesicles are predominantly explored as protocells. Further, exogenous delivery and endogenous synthesis of fatty acids suggest greater prevalence of shorter chain lengths of single-chain amphiphiles on the early Earth. In this backdrop, a mixed amphiphile-based coacervate system composed of nonanoic acid (NA), nonanol (NOH) and tyramine&#160;is&#160;characterized, which can form coacervates over a broad range of pHs, temperatures, and salt concentrations. This is noteworthy as compositionally heterogenous vesicles have also been shown to have advantages over pure fatty acid vesicles. Additionally, RNA sequestration&#160;is demonstrated in these coacervates, which gets enhanced upon addition of cationic amino acids, emphasizing the importance of cosolute interactions in the prebiotic soup. Nonenzymatic template-directed primer extension is&#160;also&#160;demonstrated in these coacervates, suggesting a potential functional role for these compartments during life's origin.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Gauri M. Patki, 
Vanthanaa Sridhar, 
Sudha Rajamani
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Characterizing Mixed Single&#8208;Chain Amphiphile&#8208;Based Coacervates as a Robust Protocell System</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500437</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500437</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500437</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70050</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.70050</guid>
         <title>Front Cover: Pathological Disulfide Bond Crosslinking: Molecular Insights into Amyloidogenesis and Diseases Progression (ChemBioChem 18/2025)</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
This cover illustrates that disulfide crosslinking between amyloidogenic proteins plays a critical role in stabilizing misfolded protein oligomers and facilitating their aggregation into fibrillar assemblies. These disulfide&#8208;linked species evade proteolytic clearance, disrupt cellular proteostasis, and propagate between cells&#8212;thereby driving proteinopathy characterized by aberrant protein accumulation and aggregation, as observed in various neurodegenerative disorders. More information can be found in the Review Article by Yun Kyung Kim, Sungsu Lim, and co&#8208;workers (DOI: 10.1002/cbic.202500316).
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/bdf77f11-9990-4916-93b0-061e95dc2141/cbic70050-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Front Cover: Pathological Disulfide Bond Crosslinking: Molecular Insights into Amyloidogenesis and Diseases Progression (ChemBioChem 18/2025)"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cover illustrates that disulfide crosslinking between amyloidogenic proteins plays a critical role in stabilizing misfolded protein oligomers and facilitating their aggregation into fibrillar assemblies. These disulfide-linked species evade proteolytic clearance, disrupt cellular proteostasis, and propagate between cells&#8212;thereby driving proteinopathy characterized by aberrant protein accumulation and aggregation, as observed in various neurodegenerative disorders. More information can be found in the Review Article by Yun Kyung Kim, Sungsu Lim, and co-workers (DOI: &lt;a target="_blank"
   title="Link to external resource"
   href="http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/cbic.202500316"&gt;10.1002/cbic.202500316&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Dong Min Kang, 
Nataliia Lukianenko, 
Ja&#8208;Hyun Baik, 
Yun Kyung Kim, 
Sungsu Lim
</dc:creator>
         <category>Cover</category>
         <dc:title>Front Cover: Pathological Disulfide Bond Crosslinking: Molecular Insights into Amyloidogenesis and Diseases Progression (ChemBioChem 18/2025)</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.70050</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.70050</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70050</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Cover</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500143</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500143</guid>
         <title>Applications of Fluidized Bed Reactors in Biocatalysis</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
The fluidized bed reactor combines the properties of a stirred tank reactor and a continuous tubular reactor. Its advantages are its high transfer capacity and its use with liquid and gas phases. This device has been used to degrade contaminants and synthesize cosmetics, food, pharmaceuticals, lubricants, and biodiesel compounds. Its versatility will constitute an attractive alternative for developing biocatalytic systems.

The main objective of this article is to review previous contributions on the applications of fluidized bed reactors (FBR) in biocatalysis. FBR combines the properties of a stirred tank reactor and a continuous tubular reactor, making it an efficient system for carrying out enzymatic reactions with immobilized enzymes. This equipment's advantages include its high transfer capacity and versatility, as it can be used with liquid and gaseous phases. According to the literature, these devices have been primarily used to degrade contaminants, synthesize cosmetic ingredients, produce food and pharmaceutical compounds, and synthesize biolubricants and biodiesel. The enzymes most used in fluidized bed mode are laccases, lipases, and proteases immobilized on methacrylate resins, mesoporous silicas, alginate, and chitosan beads. Enzyme immobilization is essential, as it can promote the suspension of biocatalyst particles, thereby increasing yields and productivity. One of the leading prospects for these systems is to stabilize the fluidized bed using a magnetic field and the concept of &#8220;microfluidization,&#8221; which enables the stabilization of smaller biocatalyst particles with smaller equipment, thereby increasing efficiency and intensifying the biocatalytic process. In the future, the versatility of FBR will constitute an attractive alternative for developing biocatalytic systems.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/9ed39de7-ba25-42bb-bb3a-b3f59b93b6d4/cbic70033-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Applications of Fluidized Bed Reactors in Biocatalysis"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fluidized bed reactor combines the properties of a stirred tank reactor and a continuous tubular reactor. Its advantages are its high transfer capacity and its use with liquid and gas phases. This device has been used to degrade contaminants and synthesize cosmetics, food, pharmaceuticals, lubricants, and biodiesel compounds. Its versatility will constitute an attractive alternative for developing biocatalytic systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main objective of this article is to review previous contributions on the applications of fluidized bed reactors (FBR) in biocatalysis. FBR combines the properties of a stirred tank reactor and a continuous tubular reactor, making it an efficient system for carrying out enzymatic reactions with immobilized enzymes. This equipment's advantages include its high transfer capacity and versatility, as it can be used with liquid and gaseous phases. According to the literature, these devices have been primarily used to degrade contaminants, synthesize cosmetic ingredients, produce food and pharmaceutical compounds, and synthesize biolubricants and biodiesel. The enzymes most used in fluidized bed mode are laccases, lipases, and proteases immobilized on methacrylate resins, mesoporous silicas, alginate, and chitosan beads. Enzyme immobilization is essential, as it can promote the suspension of biocatalyst particles, thereby increasing yields and productivity. One of the leading prospects for these systems is to stabilize the fluidized bed using a magnetic field and the concept of &#8220;microfluidization,&#8221; which enables the stabilization of smaller biocatalyst particles with smaller equipment, thereby increasing efficiency and intensifying the biocatalytic process. In the future, the versatility of FBR will constitute an attractive alternative for developing biocatalytic systems.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Nadia Guajardo, 
Paula Grez, 
Ricardo S. Schrebler, 
Rodrigo A. Schrebler
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Applications of Fluidized Bed Reactors in Biocatalysis</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500143</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500143</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500143</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500478</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500478</guid>
         <title>Hijacking the Electron Train: Menaquinone&#8208;Binding Antimicrobial Peptides</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Menaquinone is an emerging target for antimicrobial peptides. Could it be the new Achilles&#8217; Heel of bacteria?

The rise of antibiotic resistance threatens to undermine modern medicine, making the development of new antibiotics and novel targets an urgent priority. Among emerging strategies, targeting menaquinone (MK), a membrane&#8208;bound electron carrier, has gained traction as a promising yet underexplored approach. MK is only used for electron transport in bacteria, making it an attractive, selective antimicrobial target. Since the discovery of the first MK&#8208;binding antimicrobial peptide (MBAMP), lysocin E, several other examples, natural and synthetic, have been reported. Given the dire need for new antibiotics that are structurally and mechanistically distinct from anything that has come before, MBAMPs potentially offer new hope in the fight against antimicrobial resistance. This review covers recent advances in the discovery, characterization, synthesis and derivatization, and mechanistic understanding of MBAMPs.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/77f769fc-3272-4dd1-8c0f-4ce2e81d5705/cbic70041-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Hijacking the Electron Train: Menaquinone-Binding Antimicrobial Peptides"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Menaquinone is an emerging target for antimicrobial peptides. Could it be the new Achilles&#8217; Heel of bacteria?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of antibiotic resistance threatens to undermine modern medicine, making the development of new antibiotics and novel targets an urgent priority. Among emerging strategies, targeting menaquinone (MK), a membrane-bound electron carrier, has gained traction as a promising yet underexplored approach. MK is only used for electron transport in bacteria, making it an attractive, selective antimicrobial target. Since the discovery of the first MK-binding antimicrobial peptide (MBAMP), lysocin E, several other examples, natural and synthetic, have been reported. Given the dire need for new antibiotics that are structurally and mechanistically distinct from anything that has come before, MBAMPs potentially offer new hope in the fight against antimicrobial resistance. This review covers recent advances in the discovery, characterization, synthesis and derivatization, and mechanistic understanding of MBAMPs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Eilidh J. Matheson, 
Stephen A. Cochrane
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Hijacking the Electron Train: Menaquinone&#8208;Binding Antimicrobial Peptides</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500478</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500478</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500478</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500490</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500490</guid>
         <title>Aspartimide Formation and Its Prevention in Fmoc Chemistry Solid Phase Peptide Synthesis</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
Aspartimide formation remains a persistent challenge in Fmoc solid phase peptide synthesis. This review surveys strategies to prevent aspartimide formation, covering protecting group design, backbone protection, and alternative deprotection approaches. Continued development of scalable, compatible tactics is key to advancing peptide synthesis.

Aspartimide formation remains a persistent challenge during Fmoc chemistry solid phase peptide synthesis. This review outlines various strategies to suppress base&#8208;mediated aspartimide formation, including the use of ester &#946;&#8208;carboxyl protecting groups, non&#8208;ester&#8208;based &#946;&#8208;carboxyl masking groups, and backbone&#8208;protecting groups. In addition, alternatives to the Fmoc group are explored that are cleavable under nonbasic conditions. The work discussed in this review highlights that the continued development of compatible and scalable tactics toward aspartimide prevention is essential for advancing peptide synthesis in both research and industry.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/0cdd5462-034e-4304-9bec-3da565a56a80/cbic70038-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Aspartimide Formation and Its Prevention in Fmoc Chemistry Solid Phase Peptide Synthesis"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aspartimide formation remains a persistent challenge in Fmoc solid phase peptide synthesis. This review surveys strategies to prevent aspartimide formation, covering protecting group design, backbone protection, and alternative deprotection approaches. Continued development of scalable, compatible tactics is key to advancing peptide synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aspartimide formation remains a persistent challenge during Fmoc chemistry solid phase peptide synthesis. This review outlines various strategies to suppress base-mediated aspartimide formation, including the use of ester &#946;-carboxyl protecting groups, non-ester-based &#946;-carboxyl masking groups, and backbone-protecting groups. In addition, alternatives to the Fmoc group are explored that are cleavable under nonbasic conditions. The work discussed in this review highlights that the continued development of compatible and scalable tactics toward aspartimide prevention is essential for advancing peptide synthesis in both research and industry.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Marco J. W. Kong, 
Tim J. H. P. van den Braak, 
Kevin Neumann
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Aspartimide Formation and Its Prevention in Fmoc Chemistry Solid Phase Peptide Synthesis</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500490</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500490</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500490</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500316</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:18:04 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:18:04-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500316</guid>
         <title>Pathological Disulfide Bond Crosslinking: Molecular Insights into Amyloidogenesis and Diseases Progression</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 26, Issue 18, September 18, 2025. </description>
         <dc:description>
This review explores pathological disulfide&#8208;crosslinking as a key driver of amyloidogenic protein misfolding and aggregation. Oxidative and ER stress pathways contributing to disease progression are discussed and emerging therapeutic strategies targeting disulfide&#8208;linked aggregates in neurodegenerative and systemic amyloid diseases are examined.

Amyloidogenesis is a complex process in which normally soluble proteins misfold and assemble into &#946;&#8208;sheet&#8208;rich aggregates known as amyloid fibrils. This pathological process is implicated in a broad range of diseases, including neurodegenerative disorders and systemic amyloidosis. Recent studies indicate that disulfide&#8208;crosslinking plays a central role in promoting protein aggregation by stabilizing misfolded intermediates. This review highlights the cellular pathways leading to abnormal disulfide bond formation and examines their impact on disease progression. Additionally, a discussion is made on how disulfide&#8208;crosslinked oligomeric species resist degradation, overwhelm proteostasis systems, and serve as precursors for amyloid fibrils. By understanding the role of disulfide crosslinks in protein aggregation, insights into amyloid pathogenesis are gained and potential therapeutic targets for intervention are identified.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/4fdd65a5-16d9-417b-8718-01fbd3425a05/cbic202500316-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Pathological Disulfide Bond Crosslinking: Molecular Insights into Amyloidogenesis and Diseases Progression"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review explores pathological disulfide-crosslinking as a key driver of amyloidogenic protein misfolding and aggregation. Oxidative and ER stress pathways contributing to disease progression are discussed and emerging therapeutic strategies targeting disulfide-linked aggregates in neurodegenerative and systemic amyloid diseases are examined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amyloidogenesis is a complex process in which normally soluble proteins misfold and assemble into &#946;-sheet-rich aggregates known as amyloid fibrils. This pathological process is implicated in a broad range of diseases, including neurodegenerative disorders and systemic amyloidosis. Recent studies indicate that disulfide-crosslinking plays a central role in promoting protein aggregation by stabilizing misfolded intermediates. This review highlights the cellular pathways leading to abnormal disulfide bond formation and examines their impact on disease progression. Additionally, a discussion is made on how disulfide-crosslinked oligomeric species resist degradation, overwhelm proteostasis systems, and serve as precursors for amyloid fibrils. By understanding the role of disulfide crosslinks in protein aggregation, insights into amyloid pathogenesis are gained and potential therapeutic targets for intervention are identified.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Dong Min Kang, 
Nataliia Lukianenko, 
Ja&#8208;Hyun Baik, 
Yun Kyung Kim, 
Sungsu Lim
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Pathological Disulfide Bond Crosslinking: Molecular Insights into Amyloidogenesis and Diseases Progression</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500316</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500316</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500316</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>18</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500199</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:11:06-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500199</guid>
         <title>Oleanolic Acid Amide Derivatives as 20s Proteasome Stimulators</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Proteasome stimulation is of high interest for its applications in clearing protein accumulation. This study investigates oleanolic acid, a pentacyclic triterpenoid natural product proteasome stimulator, through a structure&#8211;activity relationship campaign. These findings suggest that para&#8208;substituted benzyl amides and isopropyl amides at C28 increase proteasome stimulation.

Oleanolic acid (OA), a pentacyclic triterpenoid natural product, is previously identified as a proteasome stimulator using purified proteasome. Structure&#8211;activity relationship studies are carried out on OA at the C28 and C3 positions to determine if modifications at these positions can change proteasome stimulation activity. Ten amide derivatives are synthesized and tested in cells. These findings indicate that replacing the carboxylic acid with an amide at position C28 does not diminish the stimulating effect, with certain functional groups making stimulation more potent. Amides with increased steric hinderance stimulate the proteasome the best, particularly amides with ortho substituted benzyl or isopropyl moieties. OA is further derivatized at the C3 position by acylating the hydroxyl group. Changes at this position affect solubility of the derivatives, but do not dramatically diminish proteasome stimulation. These modifications highlight that the structure of OA can be modified to include linkers or covalent cross&#8208;linking moieties to expand upon the available proteasome probes.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e95f342e-00b6-458e-9657-7760c5f33483/cbic70075-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Oleanolic Acid Amide Derivatives as 20s Proteasome Stimulators"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proteasome stimulation is of high interest for its applications in clearing protein accumulation. This study investigates oleanolic acid, a pentacyclic triterpenoid natural product proteasome stimulator, through a structure&#8211;activity relationship campaign. These findings suggest that para-substituted benzyl amides and isopropyl amides at C28 increase proteasome stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleanolic acid (OA), a pentacyclic triterpenoid natural product, is previously identified as a proteasome stimulator using purified proteasome. Structure&#8211;activity relationship studies are carried out on OA at the C&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt; and C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; positions to determine if modifications at these positions can change proteasome stimulation activity. Ten amide derivatives are synthesized and tested in cells. These findings indicate that replacing the carboxylic acid with an amide at position C&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt; does not diminish the stimulating effect, with certain functional groups making stimulation more potent. Amides with increased steric hinderance stimulate the proteasome the best, particularly amides with ortho substituted benzyl or isopropyl moieties. OA is further derivatized at the C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; position by acylating the hydroxyl group. Changes at this position affect solubility of the derivatives, but do not dramatically diminish proteasome stimulation. These modifications highlight that the structure of OA can be modified to include linkers or covalent cross-linking moieties to expand upon the available proteasome probes.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jaida M. Osman, 
Duno S. Dantis, 
Hanna King, 
Darci Jones Trader
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Oleanolic Acid Amide Derivatives as 20s Proteasome Stimulators</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500199</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500199</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500199</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500282</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:09:06 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-19T02:09:06-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500282</guid>
         <title>In Vivo Biosynthesis and Direct Incorporation of Noncanonical Amino Acids into Proteins</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
This review evaluates engineered (semi)autonomous cell systems for the biosynthesis and incorporation of noncanonical amino acids (ncAAs) into proteins. While semi&#8208;autonomous cells convert supplied precursors into ncAAs autonomous cells integrate biosynthetic pathways that produce these building blocks intracellularly. Such integrated approaches significantly reduce process costs, can increase protein yields, and overcome challenges such as the limited membrane permeability of ncAAs.

Autonomous cells are engineered biological systems capable of biosynthesising and directly incorporating noncanonical amino acids (ncAAs) into proteins. These systems have the potential to extend the applicability of the genetic code to enable large&#8208;scale fermentative production of proteins carrying ncAAs. This work evaluates approaches for the generation of autonomous and semi&#8208;autonomous cells. Semi&#8208;autonomous cells rely on the external addition of a precursor, which is enzymatically converted in&#8201;vivo to an ncAA that is directly incorporated. In contrast, autonomous cells have a metabolic system that produces and directly incorporates an ncAA in&#8201;vivo. Through a critical evaluation of the state of the art, the reader is provided with an opinion on the future development of the field.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/84ce0bef-7e2d-4f41-ab14-016cf02a626a/cbic202500282-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="In Vivo Biosynthesis and Direct Incorporation of Noncanonical Amino Acids into Proteins"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review evaluates engineered (semi)autonomous cell systems for the biosynthesis and incorporation of noncanonical amino acids (ncAAs) into proteins. While semi-autonomous cells convert supplied precursors into ncAAs autonomous cells integrate biosynthetic pathways that produce these building blocks intracellularly. Such integrated approaches significantly reduce process costs, can increase protein yields, and overcome challenges such as the limited membrane permeability of ncAAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autonomous cells are engineered biological systems capable of biosynthesising and directly incorporating noncanonical amino acids (ncAAs) into proteins. These systems have the potential to extend the applicability of the genetic code to enable large-scale fermentative production of proteins carrying ncAAs. This work evaluates approaches for the generation of autonomous and semi-autonomous cells. Semi-autonomous cells rely on the external addition of a precursor, which is enzymatically converted in&#8201;vivo to an ncAA that is directly incorporated. In contrast, autonomous cells have a metabolic system that produces and directly incorporates an ncAA in&#8201;vivo. Through a critical evaluation of the state of the art, the reader is provided with an opinion on the future development of the field.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jan Hendrik Illies, 
Tim Moritz Weber, 
Ivana Drienovsk&#225;
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>In Vivo Biosynthesis and Direct Incorporation of Noncanonical Amino Acids into Proteins</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500282</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500282</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500282</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500439</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:08:08 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-17T03:08:08-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500439</guid>
         <title>Hydrogen&#8208;Deuterium Exchange Defines Ligand&#8208;Induced Conformational Changes to the Class III Biotin Protein Ligase from Saccharomyces cerevisiae</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Hydrogen&#8208;deuterium exchange mass spectrometry validated AlphaFold structural prediction of the class III biotin protein ligase (BPL) from Saccharomyces cerevisiae, and revealed a structured domain in the N&#8208;terminal extension characteristic to this class of BPL. Ligand binding to ScBPL induced localized conformational changes in the active site and N&#8208;terminal domain, with reduced conformational sampling and increased stability.

Biotin protein ligase (BPL) catalyzes the covalent attachment of biotin onto biotin&#8208;dependent enzymes, where it functions as an essential cofactor. Eukaryotic BPLs are distinct due to the presence of a large N&#8208;terminal extension to the conserved catalytic domain and C&#8208;terminal cap. No high&#8208;resolution structures of a eukaryotic BPL have been solved; however, previous functional studies revealed the N&#8208;terminal extension interacts with the biotinylation substrate. Mass spectrometry (MS) and complementary techniques were utilized to investigate the structure of the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae BPL (ScBPL). Lower resolution techniques suggested holo&#8208;ScBPL had a more compact structure and sampled fewer conformational states. In addition, solution&#8208;phase and a charge state dependent gas&#8208;phase stabilization was observed. Hydrogen&#8208;deuterium exchange (HDX) MS provided experimental validation of the AlphaFold predicted structure of ScBPL, with a folded domain structurally homologous to a glutamine amidotransferase identified in the N&#8208;terminal extension, and a mostly homologous catalytic domain to that of other species&#8217; BPLs. Further HDX analyses identified localized conformational changes in the ScBPL active site and N&#8208;terminal domain that occur concomitantly with ligand binding. These data provide novel insights into the unique structure of a class III BPL and how ligands influence this structure for catalysis of protein biotinylation.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/4c8ccbad-c27a-49a2-b336-b6dd71b1e5bd/cbic70081-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Hydrogen-Deuterium Exchange Defines Ligand-Induced Conformational Changes to the Class III Biotin Protein Ligase from Saccharomyces cerevisiae"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hydrogen-deuterium exchange mass spectrometry validated AlphaFold structural prediction of the class III biotin protein ligase (BPL) from Saccharomyces cerevisiae, and revealed a structured domain in the N-terminal extension characteristic to this class of BPL. Ligand binding to &lt;i&gt;Sc&lt;/i&gt;BPL induced localized conformational changes in the active site and N-terminal domain, with reduced conformational sampling and increased stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biotin protein ligase (BPL) catalyzes the covalent attachment of biotin onto biotin-dependent enzymes, where it functions as an essential cofactor. Eukaryotic BPLs are distinct due to the presence of a large N-terminal extension to the conserved catalytic domain and C-terminal cap. No high-resolution structures of a eukaryotic BPL have been solved; however, previous functional studies revealed the N-terminal extension interacts with the biotinylation substrate. Mass spectrometry (MS) and complementary techniques were utilized to investigate the structure of the yeast &lt;i&gt;Saccharomyces cerevisiae&lt;/i&gt; BPL (&lt;i&gt;Sc&lt;/i&gt;BPL). Lower resolution techniques suggested holo-&lt;i&gt;Sc&lt;/i&gt;BPL had a more compact structure and sampled fewer conformational states. In addition, solution-phase and a charge state dependent gas-phase stabilization was observed. Hydrogen-deuterium exchange (HDX) MS provided experimental validation of the AlphaFold predicted structure of &lt;i&gt;Sc&lt;/i&gt;BPL, with a folded domain structurally homologous to a glutamine amidotransferase identified in the N-terminal extension, and a mostly homologous catalytic domain to that of other species&#8217; BPLs. Further HDX analyses identified localized conformational changes in the &lt;i&gt;Sc&lt;/i&gt;BPL active site and N-terminal domain that occur concomitantly with ligand binding. These data provide novel insights into the unique structure of a class III BPL and how ligands influence this structure for catalysis of protein biotinylation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Louise M. Sternicki, 
Tara L. Pukala, 
Kamila J. Pacholarz, 
Perdita Barran, 
Grant W. Booker, 
Steven W. Polyak, 
Kate L. Wegener
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Hydrogen&#8208;Deuterium Exchange Defines Ligand&#8208;Induced Conformational Changes to the Class III Biotin Protein Ligase from Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500439</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500439</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500439</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500525</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:49:24 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-17T11:49:24-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500525</guid>
         <title>Effects on LuxR&#8208;Regulated Bioluminescence of Cyclodextrin&#8208;Acyl&#8208;L&#8208;Homoserine Lactone Hybrids</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Cyclodextrin&#8208;N&#8208;acyl&#8208;L&#8208;Homoserine&#8208;Lactone conjugates are synthetized, purified and fully characterized. The study of modulation of LuxR&#8208;regulated bioluminescence production has demonstrated that one of the compounds exhibits not only the capacity to induce bioluminescence with an EC50 value of 64&#8201;&#181;M, but also the ability to reduce bioluminescence with an IC50 value of 10&#8211;20&#8201;&#181;M.

In this work, acyl homoserine lactones (AHLs) are grafted, the most studied signaling molecules in many Gram&#8208;negative bacteria, onto cyclodextrins (CDs) by copper&#8208;catalyzed azide&#8211;alkyne cycloaddition &#8220;click&#8221; coupling between alkynyl&#8208;AHLs and 6&#8208;azido&#8208;CDs derived from &#945;&#8208; and &#946;&#8208;CD, native or methylated. Attaching biomolecules onto a CD scaffold is a known strategy to enhance their properties, but designing CD&#8208;AHL conjugates has never been reported. These molecules were fully characterized by NMR and high&#8208;resolution mass spectrometry, and the study of their solubility and conformation reveals significant conformational changes due to the presence of the AHL appendage on the CD structure. One of the hybrids (per&#8208;AHL&#8208;&#946;&#8208;CD, 9B) exhibits higher solubility in water than AHL and &#946;&#8208;CD alone. The new CD&#8208;AHLs conjugates are found to modulate bioluminescence in a quorum Sensing LuxR&#8208;regulated light&#8208;producing bacterial model, with significant variations depending on the structure. The per&#8208;AHL&#8208;&#946;&#8208;CD, 9B, is found to be the most active compound in the series.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/b5198439-d302-450d-9cac-8d11569654e0/cbic70074-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Effects on LuxR-Regulated Bioluminescence of Cyclodextrin-Acyl-L-Homoserine Lactone Hybrids"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclodextrin-&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-acyl-L-Homoserine-Lactone conjugates are synthetized, purified and fully characterized. The study of modulation of LuxR-regulated bioluminescence production has demonstrated that one of the compounds exhibits not only the capacity to induce bioluminescence with an EC50 value of 64&#8201;&#181;M, but also the ability to reduce bioluminescence with an IC50 value of 10&#8211;20&#8201;&#181;M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, acyl homoserine lactones (AHLs) are grafted, the most studied signaling molecules in many Gram-negative bacteria, onto cyclodextrins (CDs) by copper-catalyzed azide&#8211;alkyne cycloaddition &#8220;click&#8221; coupling between alkynyl-AHLs and 6-azido-CDs derived from &lt;i&gt;&#945;&lt;/i&gt;- and &lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;-CD, native or methylated. Attaching biomolecules onto a CD scaffold is a known strategy to enhance their properties, but designing CD-AHL conjugates has never been reported. These molecules were fully characterized by NMR and high-resolution mass spectrometry, and the study of their solubility and conformation reveals significant conformational changes due to the presence of the AHL appendage on the CD structure. One of the hybrids (per-AHL-&lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;-CD, &lt;b&gt;9&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;B&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/sub&gt;) exhibits higher solubility in water than AHL and &lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;-CD alone. The new CD-AHLs conjugates are found to modulate bioluminescence in a quorum Sensing LuxR-regulated light-producing bacterial model, with significant variations depending on the structure. The per-AHL-&lt;i&gt;&#946;&lt;/i&gt;-CD, &lt;b&gt;9&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;B&lt;/b&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;,&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/sub&gt; is found to be the most active compound in the series.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Nicolas Tinet, 
David Lesur, 
Yves Queneau, 
Laurent Soul&#232;re, 
Florence Djedaini&#8208;Pilard, 
V&#233;ronique Bonnet
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Effects on LuxR&#8208;Regulated Bioluminescence of Cyclodextrin&#8208;Acyl&#8208;L&#8208;Homoserine Lactone Hybrids</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500525</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500525</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500525</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500601</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:44:52 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-17T11:44:52-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500601</guid>
         <title>Enantiocomplementary Bioreduction of Flexible Ring N&#8208;(3&#8208;Oxobutyl)Heterocycles Providing Enantiopure Chiral Fragments for Drug Discovery</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Bioreduction of flexible ring N&#8208;(3&#8208;oxobutyl)&#8208;heterocycles mediated by enantiocomplementary recombinant alcohol dehydrogenases [an (S)&#8208;selective one from Rhodococcus aetherivorans (RaADH), and an (R)&#8208;selective one from Lactobacillus kefir (LkADH)], as whole&#8208;cell biocatalysts results in enantiopure (S)&#8208; and (R)&#8208;alcohols (ee &gt; 99%), which are promising chiral fragments with a high degree of drug&#8208;likeness for drug discovery.

In this study, the bioreduction of prochiral N&#8208;(3&#8208;oxobutyl)heterocycles comprising various (partially) saturated, flexible rings is explored using microbial whole&#8208;cell ketoreductases such as wild&#8208;type yeast strains including baker's yeast (Saccharomyces cerevisiae) and Escherichia coli cells expressing two enantiocomplementary recombinant alcohol dehydrogenases. Initially, four wild&#8208;type yeast strains are screened for ketoreductase activity on a series of nine flexible N&#8208;heterocycles with prochiral carbonyl group in the N&#8208;(3&#8208;oxobutyl) sidechain. The yeast strains resulted in the corresponding (S)&#8208;alcohols with a low to moderate conversions. Using recombinant alcohol dehydrogenase whole&#8208;cell preparations as biocatalysts ((S)&#8208;selective ADH from Rhodococcus aetherivorans (RaADH) and (R)&#8208;selective ADH from Lactobacillus kefir (LkADH)) resulted in higher conversions in most cases, while maintaining the full enantiotopic selectivity. Usually, the preparative&#8208;scale bioreductions showed comparable or even higher conversions than those observed in the small&#8208;scale screening reactions, resulting in virtually enantiopure (S)&#8208; and (R)&#8208;alcohols (ee&#8201;&gt;&#8201;99%), which are promising chiral fragments with a high degree of drug&#8208;likeness. Docking studies confirmed the absolute configuration of the forming (S)&#8208; and (R)&#8208;alcohols.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/70eb6b20-3560-4d6e-b4f2-53a18321aaf3/cbic70073-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Enantiocomplementary Bioreduction of Flexible Ring N-(3-Oxobutyl)Heterocycles Providing Enantiopure Chiral Fragments for Drug Discovery"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bioreduction of flexible ring &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-(3-oxobutyl)-heterocycles mediated by enantiocomplementary recombinant alcohol dehydrogenases [an (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)-selective one from &lt;i&gt;Rhodococcus aetherivorans&lt;/i&gt; (RaADH), and an (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-selective one from &lt;i&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;kefir&lt;/i&gt; (LkADH)], as whole-cell biocatalysts results in enantiopure (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)- and (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-alcohols (ee &amp;gt; 99%), which are promising chiral fragments with a high degree of drug-likeness for drug discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, the bioreduction of prochiral &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-(3-oxobutyl)heterocycles comprising various (partially) saturated, flexible rings is explored using microbial whole-cell ketoreductases such as wild-type yeast strains including baker's yeast (&lt;i&gt;Saccharomyces cerevisiae&lt;/i&gt;) and &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; cells expressing two enantiocomplementary recombinant alcohol dehydrogenases. Initially, four wild-type yeast strains are screened for ketoreductase activity on a series of nine flexible N-heterocycles with prochiral carbonyl group in the &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-(3-oxobutyl) sidechain. The yeast strains resulted in the corresponding (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)-alcohols with a low to moderate conversions. Using recombinant alcohol dehydrogenase whole-cell preparations as biocatalysts ((&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)-selective ADH from &lt;i&gt;Rhodococcus aetherivorans&lt;/i&gt; (RaADH) and (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-selective ADH from &lt;i&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;kefir&lt;/i&gt; (LkADH)) resulted in higher conversions in most cases, while maintaining the full enantiotopic selectivity. Usually, the preparative-scale bioreductions showed comparable or even higher conversions than those observed in the small-scale screening reactions, resulting in virtually enantiopure (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)- and (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-alcohols (ee&#8201;&amp;gt;&#8201;99%), which are promising chiral fragments with a high degree of drug-likeness. Docking studies confirmed the absolute configuration of the forming (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)- and (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-alcohols.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
M&#225;t&#233; Gerg&#337; Honv&#225;ri, 
Levente Andr&#225;s M&#243;cza, 
Bence Attila Kucsinka, 
P&#225;l Csuka, 
Vikt&#243;ria B&#243;dai, 
Diana Maria Scrob, 
L&#225;szl&#243; Poppe, 
G&#225;bor Horny&#225;nszky
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Enantiocomplementary Bioreduction of Flexible Ring N&#8208;(3&#8208;Oxobutyl)Heterocycles Providing Enantiopure Chiral Fragments for Drug Discovery</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500601</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500601</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500601</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500558</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 13:42:27 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-12T01:42:27-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500558</guid>
         <title>A Photocaged N&#8208;Phosphonopiperidinone as a Selective Photo&#8208;Cleavable DPP8/9 Inhibitor</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Photocaged inhibitors are versatile biochemical tools for spatiotemporal control of inhibitor activity, facilitating the elucidation of protein function in a cell type&#8208;dependent fashion. Herein, a green light&#8208;cleavable, BODIPY&#8208;photocaged dipeptidyl peptidase 8 and 9 inhibitor with low phototoxicity, pronounced potency, and selectivity is described, thereby demonstrating the benefits of chemical proteomics for inhibitor characterization.

The strategic introduction of photocages into chemical probes represents a powerful approach to generate spatiotemporally controlled tools with promising applications in chemical biology and drug discovery. This approach is particularly useful for inhibitors of proteins with cell&#8208;type&#8208;dependent functions, as they enable, via light&#8208;triggered selection, the study of their function in selected cells within multicellular organisms. The intracellular dipeptidyl peptidases 8 and 9 (DPP8/9) are serine hydrolases that act in a cell type&#8208;dependent fashion, in diverse biological processes such as inflammation and tumorigenesis. So far, no photocaged inhibitors for DPP8/9 are available, thus hampering their systematic investigations in biomedical research model systems such as mice. Herein, the development of a green light&#8208;cleavable, BODIPY&#8208;photocaged N&#8208;phosphono&#8208;piperidone&#8208;based DPP8/9 inhibitor is presented. This covalent&#8208;acting inhibitor is characterized by its photolysis properties, including a demonstration of its low phototoxicity, as well as potency and selectivity, in biochemical, biological, and, as an extension to these traditional validation approaches, chemical proteomics assays. These studies not only reveal the suitability of the developed photocages for cellular applications, as a prerequisite for their application in multicellular organisms, but also highlight the benefit of chemical proteomics workflows such as activity&#8208;based protein profiling for characterizing proteome&#8208;wide potencies and selectivities of photocaged compounds.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/bd76275b-b0e5-4306-9f99-8e1f3faea5aa/cbic70072-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="A Photocaged N-Phosphonopiperidinone as a Selective Photo-Cleavable DPP8/9 Inhibitor"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photocaged inhibitors are versatile biochemical tools for spatiotemporal control of inhibitor activity, facilitating the elucidation of protein function in a cell type-dependent fashion. Herein, a green light-cleavable, BODIPY-photocaged dipeptidyl peptidase 8 and 9 inhibitor with low phototoxicity, pronounced potency, and selectivity is described, thereby demonstrating the benefits of chemical proteomics for inhibitor characterization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategic introduction of photocages into chemical probes represents a powerful approach to generate spatiotemporally controlled tools with promising applications in chemical biology and drug discovery. This approach is particularly useful for inhibitors of proteins with cell-type-dependent functions, as they enable, via light-triggered selection, the study of their function in selected cells within multicellular organisms. The intracellular dipeptidyl peptidases 8 and 9 (DPP8/9) are serine hydrolases that act in a cell type-dependent fashion, in diverse biological processes such as inflammation and tumorigenesis. So far, no photocaged inhibitors for DPP8/9 are available, thus hampering their systematic investigations in biomedical research model systems such as mice. Herein, the development of a green light-cleavable, BODIPY-photocaged &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-phosphono-piperidone-based DPP8/9 inhibitor is presented. This covalent-acting inhibitor is characterized by its photolysis properties, including a demonstration of its low phototoxicity, as well as potency and selectivity, in biochemical, biological, and, as an extension to these traditional validation approaches, chemical proteomics assays. These studies not only reveal the suitability of the developed photocages for cellular applications, as a prerequisite for their application in multicellular organisms, but also highlight the benefit of chemical proteomics workflows such as activity-based protein profiling for characterizing proteome-wide potencies and selectivities of photocaged compounds.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Leonard Sewald, 
Niko Molke, 
Werner W. A. Tabak, 
Anette Haak, 
Maja Najdzion, 
Ruth Geiss&#8208;Friedlander, 
Doris Hellerschmied, 
Robert Huber, 
Markus Kaiser
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>A Photocaged N&#8208;Phosphonopiperidinone as a Selective Photo&#8208;Cleavable DPP8/9 Inhibitor</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500558</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500558</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500558</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500457</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 13:41:43 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-12T01:41:43-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500457</guid>
         <title>Indomethacin&#8208;Naphthalimide&#8208;Based AIEgen for Illuminating Golgi Apparatus</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
A small molecule library is designed and synthesized for showing aggregation&#8208;induced emission (AIE), among which one small molecule consisting of indomethacin, napthalimide&#8208;N,N&#8242;&#8208;dimethyl aniline, and amide linkage is identified to illuminate Golgi apparatus in cells. Quantum mechanical calculations, electron microscopy, and light scattering confirm the self&#8208;assembly of this novel molecule into nanoscale material.

Golgi apparatus (GA) is a complex organelle controlling subcellular protein modifications, sorting, and transport. Dysregulation in GA leads to cancer development and metastasis. Consequently, development of small molecule fluorophores for illuminating GA in cancer cells remains a major challenge. To address this, herein, a small molecule library of four aggregation&#8208;induced emissive probes (AIEgens) is designed and synthesized, having (a) indomethacin, a nonsteroidal anti&#8208;inflammatory drug (NSAID) for GA homing; (b) 1,8&#8208;naphthalimide&#8208;N,N&#8242;&#8208;disubstituted aniline as AIE inducer; and (c) amide/ester linkage between NSAID and AIE inducer. All the library members exhibited excellent AIE property in THF/water binary solvent systems through self&#8208;assembly in water. Interestingly, one of the library members (compound 13), consisting of napthalimide&#8208;N,N&#8242;&#8208;dimethyl aniline as AIE inducer and amide linkage, efficiently homes into the GA of HCT&#8208;116 colon cancer cells within 30&#8201;min and self&#8208;assembled into 2D nanoscale materials, as shown by scanning electron and atomic force microscopy and confirmed by molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. Moreover, quantum mechanical calculations revealed intramolecular charge transfer (CT) between N,N&#8242;&#8208;dimethyl aniline (donor) and naphthalimide (acceptor) as the underlying mechanism of the photophysical properties of compound 13. This novel AIEgen can serve as a chemical biology tool to visualize GA in cancer cells for next&#8208;generation cancer therapeutics.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2401a5cc-8d8c-4123-bf4c-23fa124e1516/cbic70042-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Indomethacin-Naphthalimide-Based AIEgen for Illuminating Golgi Apparatus"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small molecule library is designed and synthesized for showing aggregation-induced emission (AIE), among which one small molecule consisting of indomethacin, napthalimide-N,N&#8242;-dimethyl aniline, and amide linkage is identified to illuminate Golgi apparatus in cells. Quantum mechanical calculations, electron microscopy, and light scattering confirm the self-assembly of this novel molecule into nanoscale material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golgi apparatus (GA) is a complex organelle controlling subcellular protein modifications, sorting, and transport. Dysregulation in GA leads to cancer development and metastasis. Consequently, development of small molecule fluorophores for illuminating GA in cancer cells remains a major challenge. To address this, herein, a small molecule library of four aggregation-induced emissive probes (AIEgens) is designed and synthesized, having (a) indomethacin, a nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) for GA homing; (b) 1,8-naphthalimide-N,N&#8242;-disubstituted aniline as AIE inducer; and (c) amide/ester linkage between NSAID and AIE inducer. All the library members exhibited excellent AIE property in THF/water binary solvent systems through self-assembly in water. Interestingly, one of the library members (compound 13), consisting of napthalimide-N,N&#8242;-dimethyl aniline as AIE inducer and amide linkage, efficiently homes into the GA of HCT-116 colon cancer cells within 30&#8201;min and self-assembled into 2D nanoscale materials, as shown by scanning electron and atomic force microscopy and confirmed by molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. Moreover, quantum mechanical calculations revealed intramolecular charge transfer (CT) between N,N&#8242;-dimethyl aniline (donor) and naphthalimide (acceptor) as the underlying mechanism of the photophysical properties of compound 13. This novel AIEgen can serve as a chemical biology tool to visualize GA in cancer cells for next-generation cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Phanindra Kumar, 
Tripti Mishra, 
 Sanyam, 
Asima Sahu, 
Anirban Mondal, 
Sudipta Basu
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Indomethacin&#8208;Naphthalimide&#8208;Based AIEgen for Illuminating Golgi Apparatus</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500457</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500457</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500457</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500494</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 13:40:56 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-12T01:40:56-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500494</guid>
         <title>Two&#8208;Color Timestamping of Gene Expression with a Chemigenetic Reporter System</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
A chemigenetic reporter assay is developed that enables monitoring of BiP/GRP78 expression, an important chaperone and key regulator of the unfolded protein response. The system is based on the coexpression of BiP/GRP78 and the self&#8208;labeling protein HaloTag. Using a two&#8208;color labeling strategy for improved readout sensitivity, the assay is applied in high&#8208;content screening for novel activators of BiP/GRP78 expression.

Stress response pathways rely on coordinated gene expression regulation. In the endoplasmic reticulum, the unfolded protein response plays an important role in maintaining the homeostasis of protein folding and processing. A chemigenetic reporter assay is developed that allows monitoring of BiP/GRP78 expression, a key regulator of the unfolded protein response. The system is based on the coexpression of the self&#8208;labeling protein HaloTag via an internal ribosome entry site. HaloTag allows for flexibility in labeling color as well as labeling timepoint. A two&#8208;color timestamping strategy is designed that provides improved readout sensitivity. The reporter system can be used in live&#8208;cell imaging as well as flow cytometry. It is applied in a high&#8208;content screening experiment in which a new promising activator of BiP/GRP78 expression was identified.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/5b0bc1ee-8073-4d23-b5d7-0c5bb93f2732/cbic70065-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Two-Color Timestamping of Gene Expression with a Chemigenetic Reporter System"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chemigenetic reporter assay is developed that enables monitoring of BiP/GRP78 expression, an important chaperone and key regulator of the unfolded protein response. The system is based on the coexpression of BiP/GRP78 and the self-labeling protein HaloTag. Using a two-color labeling strategy for improved readout sensitivity, the assay is applied in high-content screening for novel activators of BiP/GRP78 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress response pathways rely on coordinated gene expression regulation. In the endoplasmic reticulum, the unfolded protein response plays an important role in maintaining the homeostasis of protein folding and processing. A chemigenetic reporter assay is developed that allows monitoring of BiP/GRP78 expression, a key regulator of the unfolded protein response. The system is based on the coexpression of the self-labeling protein HaloTag via an internal ribosome entry site. HaloTag allows for flexibility in labeling color as well as labeling timepoint. A two-color timestamping strategy is designed that provides improved readout sensitivity. The reporter system can be used in live-cell imaging as well as flow cytometry. It is applied in a high-content screening experiment in which a new promising activator of BiP/GRP78 expression was identified.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Henriette L&#228;mmermann, 
Jade Nguyen, 
Juan F. Tamez&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, 
Fabien Kuttler, 
Julien Bortoli Chapalay, 
Marc Chambon, 
Gerardo Turcatti, 
Pablo Rivera&#8208;Fuentes
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Two&#8208;Color Timestamping of Gene Expression with a Chemigenetic Reporter System</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500494</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500494</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500494</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500500</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 01:10:24 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T01:10:24-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500500</guid>
         <title>Screening the Irish Marine Biorepository Identifies a New Bryostatin Analog as Potent Inhibitor of Activated B&#8208;Cells Diffuse Large B&#8208;Cell Lymphoma</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Bryostatin analogs are found to be accumulated in the nudibranch Antiopella cristata collected in Irish waters. These are found to be potent inhibitors of activated B&#8208;cells diffuse large B&#8208;cell lymphoma.

Activated B&#8208;cell diffuse large B&#8208;cell lymphoma (ABC&#8208;DLBCL) is an aggressive cancer with poor response to standard chemotherapy. In search of new therapeutic leads, a library of 435 fractions prepared from the Irish marine biorepository was screened against 2 ABC&#8208;DLBCL cell lines (TMD8 and OCI&#8208;Ly10) and a non&#8208;cancerous control cell line (CB33). Active fractions are prioritized based on potency and selectivity. Among them, fractions from the nudibranch Antiopella cristata and the ascidian Diplosoma listerianum exhibit the most potent and selective cytotoxicity. Bioassay&#8208;guided fractionation of D. listerianum led to the identification of the known loliolide and epiloliolide. On the other hand, A. cristata yielded several bryostatin analogs, including bryostatin 13 and a new natural product, its 18&#8208;demethylated analog. Both compounds demonstrated nanomolar cytotoxicity against ABC&#8208;DLBCL cell lines with minimal activity in CB33. Transcriptomic profiling showed significant gene expression changes, particularly for the 18&#8208;demethylated analog, implicating modulation of key signaling pathways. This study identifies A. cristata as a novel and highly enriched source of bioactive bryostatins and supports the dietary sequestration hypothesis in nudibranchs, highlighting the value of marine invertebrates as reservoirs of selective anticancer agents for drug discovery.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2ee83dd8-cc8b-4717-a245-754465f24e16/cbic70071-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Screening the Irish Marine Biorepository Identifies a New Bryostatin Analog as Potent Inhibitor of Activated B-Cells Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bryostatin analogs are found to be accumulated in the nudibranch &lt;i&gt;Antiopella cristata&lt;/i&gt; collected in Irish waters. These are found to be potent inhibitors of activated B-cells diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activated B-cell diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (ABC-DLBCL) is an aggressive cancer with poor response to standard chemotherapy. In search of new therapeutic leads, a library of 435 fractions prepared from the Irish marine biorepository was screened against 2 ABC-DLBCL cell lines (TMD8 and OCI&lt;b&gt;-&lt;/b&gt;Ly10) and a non-cancerous control cell line (CB33). Active fractions are prioritized based on potency and selectivity. Among them, fractions from the nudibranch &lt;i&gt;Antiopella cristata&lt;/i&gt; and the ascidian &lt;i&gt;Diplosoma listerianum&lt;/i&gt; exhibit the most potent and selective cytotoxicity. Bioassay-guided fractionation of &lt;i&gt;D. listerianum&lt;/i&gt; led to the identification of the known loliolide and epiloliolide. On the other hand, &lt;i&gt;A. cristata&lt;/i&gt; yielded several bryostatin analogs, including bryostatin 13 and a new natural product, its 18-demethylated analog. Both compounds demonstrated nanomolar cytotoxicity against ABC-DLBCL cell lines with minimal activity in CB33. Transcriptomic profiling showed significant gene expression changes, particularly for the 18-demethylated analog, implicating modulation of key signaling pathways. This study identifies &lt;i&gt;A. cristata&lt;/i&gt; as a novel and highly enriched source of bioactive bryostatins and supports the dietary sequestration hypothesis in nudibranchs, highlighting the value of marine invertebrates as reservoirs of selective anticancer agents for drug discovery.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Laurence K. Jennings, 
Filippo Spriano, 
Maggie M. Reddy, 
Luciano Cascione, 
Elisa Civanelli, 
Andrea Rinaldi, 
Francesco Bertoni, 
Olivier P. Thomas
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Screening the Irish Marine Biorepository Identifies a New Bryostatin Analog as Potent Inhibitor of Activated B&#8208;Cells Diffuse Large B&#8208;Cell Lymphoma</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500500</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500500</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500500</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500563</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 01:09:12 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T01:09:12-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500563</guid>
         <title>Characterization of an Extradiol Dioxygenase Using Integrating Cavity Spectrophotometry</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Integrating cavity spectrophotometry enables the direct and efficient characterization of an extradiol dioxygenase using a whole cell&#8208;based assay. This approach obviates the need for protein purification and provides more information about enzyme behavior inside of the cellular environment. Kinetic assays were leveraged for the design of preparative&#8208;scale reactions for biocatalytic synthesis of ring&#8208;cleaved molecules in high yield. 

The development of synthetically&#8208;useful biocatalysts requires characterizing the behavior of an enzyme under conditions amenable to preparative&#8208;scale reactions. Whole cells harboring the catalyst of interest are often used in such reactions, as protein purification is laborious and expensive. However, monitoring reaction rates when using whole cells is challenging, as cellular debris precludes the use of a continuous assay. Herein, we describe an approach to continuous monitoring of whole cell reactions that is enabled by the use of an integrating cavity spectrophotometer. This approach was used to directly profile the kinetic behavior of a previously uncharacterized extradiol dioxygenase DfdB from Rhodococcus sp. YK2. Data obtained from these experiments were compared with traditional in vitro assays. In both whole cell and purified enzyme kinetic assays, similar enzymatic behaviors were observed, including substrate inhibition. Measured KM values and observed trends in catalytic efficiency were comparable for both types of enzyme preparation. Information provided by this analysis was leveraged to optimize preparative&#8208;scale whole cell reactions with DfdB, enabling the synthesis of two DfdB products in high yield. Importantly, this work showcases the potential for ICS&#8208;based methods to rapidly evaluate kinetic trends on analytical scale and thereby enables efficient reaction optimization for preparative&#8208;scale synthesis.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/7732c1fb-d185-4041-be48-de74e94e7492/cbic70070-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Characterization of an Extradiol Dioxygenase Using Integrating Cavity Spectrophotometry"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrating cavity spectrophotometry enables the direct and efficient characterization of an extradiol dioxygenase using a whole cell-based assay. This approach obviates the need for protein purification and provides more information about enzyme behavior inside of the cellular environment. Kinetic assays were leveraged for the design of preparative-scale reactions for biocatalytic synthesis of ring-cleaved molecules in high yield. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of synthetically-useful biocatalysts requires characterizing the behavior of an enzyme under conditions amenable to preparative-scale reactions. Whole cells harboring the catalyst of interest are often used in such reactions, as protein purification is laborious and expensive. However, monitoring reaction rates when using whole cells is challenging, as cellular debris precludes the use of a continuous assay. Herein, we describe an approach to continuous monitoring of whole cell reactions that is enabled by the use of an integrating cavity spectrophotometer. This approach was used to directly profile the kinetic behavior of a previously uncharacterized extradiol dioxygenase DfdB from &lt;i&gt;Rhodococcus&lt;/i&gt; sp. YK2. Data obtained from these experiments were compared with traditional in vitro assays. In both whole cell and purified enzyme kinetic assays, similar enzymatic behaviors were observed, including substrate inhibition. Measured K&lt;sub&gt;M&lt;/sub&gt; values and observed trends in catalytic efficiency were comparable for both types of enzyme preparation. Information provided by this analysis was leveraged to optimize preparative-scale whole cell reactions with DfdB, enabling the synthesis of two DfdB products in high yield. Importantly, this work showcases the potential for ICS-based methods to rapidly evaluate kinetic trends on analytical scale and thereby enables efficient reaction optimization for preparative-scale synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Thomas Benning, 
Hannah R. Zwiefelhofer, 
Cadence F. Cordova, 
Grace C. Rooney, 
Tyler J. Doyon
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Characterization of an Extradiol Dioxygenase Using Integrating Cavity Spectrophotometry</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500563</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500563</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500563</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500405</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:39:27 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:39:27-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500405</guid>
         <title>Design and Characterization of the Fusion Enzyme of Bovine Terminal Deoxynucleotidyl Transferase and DNA Binding Protein Sso7d from Sulfolobus solfataricus</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
The fusion of the DNA&#8208;binding protein Sso7d from Sulfolobus solfataricus with bovine DNA exotransferase results in a threefold increase in DNA&#8208;binding affinity to double&#8208;stranded DNA, enhances expression yield, and improves thermostability, along with altering functional activity. The obtained fusion enzymes serve as promising candidates for novel applications, including gene editing, mutagenesis studies, and aptamer engineering.

The terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase is a unique polymerase that incorporates nucleotides at the 3&#8242;&#8208;terminus of single&#8208;stranded DNA primers in a template&#8208;independent manner. This biological function propels the development of numerous biomedical and bioengineering applications. However, the extensive use of TdT is constrained by its low expression levels in E. coli and low optimal operating temperature. To address these limitations, a fusion enzyme combining TdT and the DNA&#8208;binding protein Sso7d from Sulfolobus solfataricus is designed and isolated. This fusion protein exhibits a threefold increase in DNA&#8208;binding affinity to double&#8208;stranded DNA and demonstrates improved thermostability, denaturing at temperatures up to 48&#8201;&#176;C, along with an enhancement in the expression yield of the target protein. The fusion of Sso7d to the C&#8208;terminus of TdT enhances catalytic activity for nucleotide removal from the coding end, while completely abolishing nucleotide addition activity. Conversely, the presence of Sso7d at the N&#8208;terminus of TdT decreases nucleotide incorporation and enhances nucleotide removal activity, with this effect significantly influenced by substrate length and the presence of metal ions in the reaction mixture. Overall, the obtained fusion enzymes could serve as promising candidates for novel specific applications, such as gene editing, mutagenesis studies, and aptamer engineering.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2990e7e0-ef70-4573-8197-c67f68e950b7/cbic70059-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Design and Characterization of the Fusion Enzyme of Bovine Terminal Deoxynucleotidyl Transferase and DNA Binding Protein Sso7d from Sulfolobus solfataricus"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fusion of the DNA-binding protein Sso7d from &lt;i&gt;Sulfolobus solfataricus&lt;/i&gt; with bovine DNA exotransferase results in a threefold increase in DNA-binding affinity to double-stranded DNA, enhances expression yield, and improves thermostability, along with altering functional activity. The obtained fusion enzymes serve as promising candidates for novel applications, including gene editing, mutagenesis studies, and aptamer engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase is a unique polymerase that incorporates nucleotides at the 3&#8242;-terminus of single-stranded DNA primers in a template-independent manner. This biological function propels the development of numerous biomedical and bioengineering applications. However, the extensive use of TdT is constrained by its low expression levels in &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt; and low optimal operating temperature. To address these limitations, a fusion enzyme combining TdT and the DNA-binding protein Sso7d from &lt;i&gt;Sulfolobus solfataricus&lt;/i&gt; is designed and isolated. This fusion protein exhibits a threefold increase in DNA-binding affinity to double-stranded DNA and demonstrates improved thermostability, denaturing at temperatures up to 48&#8201;&#176;C, along with an enhancement in the expression yield of the target protein. The fusion of Sso7d to the C-terminus of TdT enhances catalytic activity for nucleotide removal from the coding end, while completely abolishing nucleotide addition activity. Conversely, the presence of Sso7d at the N-terminus of TdT decreases nucleotide incorporation and enhances nucleotide removal activity, with this effect significantly influenced by substrate length and the presence of metal ions in the reaction mixture. Overall, the obtained fusion enzymes could serve as promising candidates for novel specific applications, such as gene editing, mutagenesis studies, and aptamer engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Antos B. Sachanka, 
Yaraslau U. Dzichenka, 
Veronika V. Shchur, 
Aliaksei V. Yantsevich
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Design and Characterization of the Fusion Enzyme of Bovine Terminal Deoxynucleotidyl Transferase and DNA Binding Protein Sso7d from Sulfolobus solfataricus</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500405</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500405</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500405</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500585</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:38:19 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:38:19-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500585</guid>
         <title>Recent Advances in P450 Enzyme Engineering for the Production of Natural Products</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
This concept focuses on the advances in natural product synthesis using P450s, covering the applied strategies through cofactor engineering, redox partner engineering, and enzyme engineering, along with recent applications. It also outlines current technical bottlenecks and future development directions.

Natural products exhibit a wide range of biological activities and are the crucial resources for drug development and compound modification. Cytochrome P450 enzymes (P450s, CYP) are a class of multifunctional and stereoselective biocatalysts that utilize heme as a cofactor and can be employed in the biosynthesis of natural products. With the development of biotechnology, P450s have been widely applied in the synthesis of natural products. However, several challenges still exist during the catalytic process, including the difficulties in the soluble expression of P450s, the insufficient supply of cofactor heme, the limited substrate selectivity, and the low efficiency of electron transfer. This concept systematically summarizes recent advances in P450 enzyme engineering for the synthesis of natural products. It covers the engineering strategies to improve heme supply and enhance the catalytic efficiency for various P450 enzymes and their applications in synthesizing steroids, flavonoids, alkaloids, and terpenoids. This concept provides a foundation for overcoming catalytic bottlenecks and promoting the green biomanufacturing of high&#8208;value natural products.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/fa1e3d87-e5bf-439c-be1f-883d03b65008/cbic70067-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Recent Advances in P450 Enzyme Engineering for the Production of Natural Products"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concept focuses on the advances in natural product synthesis using P450s, covering the applied strategies through cofactor engineering, redox partner engineering, and enzyme engineering, along with recent applications. It also outlines current technical bottlenecks and future development directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural products exhibit a wide range of biological activities and are the crucial resources for drug development and compound modification. Cytochrome P450 enzymes (P450s, CYP) are a class of multifunctional and stereoselective biocatalysts that utilize heme as a cofactor and can be employed in the biosynthesis of natural products. With the development of biotechnology, P450s have been widely applied in the synthesis of natural products. However, several challenges still exist during the catalytic process, including the difficulties in the soluble expression of P450s, the insufficient supply of cofactor heme, the limited substrate selectivity, and the low efficiency of electron transfer. This concept systematically summarizes recent advances in P450 enzyme engineering for the synthesis of natural products. It covers the engineering strategies to improve heme supply and enhance the catalytic efficiency for various P450 enzymes and their applications in synthesizing steroids, flavonoids, alkaloids, and terpenoids. This concept provides a foundation for overcoming catalytic bottlenecks and promoting the green biomanufacturing of high-value natural products.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Liping Wang, 
Chixiang Sun, 
Baodong Hu, 
Xinrui Zhao
</dc:creator>
         <category>Concept</category>
         <dc:title>Recent Advances in P450 Enzyme Engineering for the Production of Natural Products</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500585</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500585</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500585</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Concept</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500151</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:30:56 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:30:56-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500151</guid>
         <title>AtGH3.10 and JAR1 Produce 12&#8208;Hydroxyjasmonoyl&#8208;l&#8208;isoleucine from 12&#8208;Hydroxyjasmonic Acid in Arabidopsis thaliana</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
12&#8208;Hydroxy&#8208;7&#8208;iso&#8208;jasmonic acid (12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA) is converted to an active jasmonate 12&#8208;hydroxy&#8208;7&#8208;iso&#8208;jasmonoyl&#8208;l&#8208;isoleucine (12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile) in Arabidopsis. Enzyme assays with recombinant enzymes and mutant analysis reveal that JAR1 and AtGH3.10 conjugate l&#8208;isoleucine to 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA. Higher catalytic efficiency is observed with 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA for AtGH3.10 than for JAR1.

Jasmonates are plant hormones that regulate plant defense and development. 7&#8208;iso&#8208;Jasmonoyl&#8208;l&#8208;isoleucine (JA&#8208;Ile) is a representative active jasmonate which is biosynthesized from 7&#8208;iso&#8208;jasmonic acid (JA) by the jasmonoyl&#8208;amido synthases JASMONATE RESISTANT 1 (JAR1) and AtGH3.10 in Arabidopsis thaliana. 12&#8208;Hydroxy&#8208;7&#8208;iso&#8208;jasmonoyl&#8208;l&#8208;isoleucine (12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile) is another active jasmonate, and 12&#8208;hydroxylation of JA&#8208;Ile is considered the major biosynthetic pathway toward 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile. Previous report elucidated that recombinant JAR1 showed a weak activity against 12&#8208;hydroxy&#8208;7&#8208;iso&#8208;jasmonic acid (12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA). However, the direct conversion from 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA to 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile in planta and the enzyme activity of AtG3.10 against 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA have never been reported. Herein, a feeding experiment with deuterated 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA confirms the direct conversion of 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA to 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile in wild&#8208;type Arabidopsis plants. The conversion from 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA to 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile is not observed in jar1 gh3.10 double mutant, suggesting that 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA is converted to 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA&#8208;Ile by JAR1 and AtGH3.10. Notably, enzyme assays show that the catalytic efficiency with 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA for AtGH3.10 is higher than those with JA for AtGH3.10 and with 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA for JAR1. Comparative analysis of JAR1 and AtGH3.10 structures and site&#8208;directed mutation analysis reveals that Ser120 in AtGH3.10 is the key amino acid residue responsible for its high catalytic efficiency against 12&#8208;OH&#8208;JA.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/30cd066f-41e5-42cd-9f88-231ffcacee8c/cbic70003-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="AtGH3.10 and JAR1 Produce 12-Hydroxyjasmonoyl-l-isoleucine from 12-Hydroxyjasmonic Acid in Arabidopsis thaliana"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12-Hydroxy-7-&lt;i&gt;iso&lt;/i&gt;-jasmonic acid (12-OH-JA) is converted to an active jasmonate 12-hydroxy-7-&lt;i&gt;iso&lt;/i&gt;-jasmonoyl-&lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-isoleucine (12-OH-JA-Ile) in &lt;i&gt;Arabidopsis&lt;/i&gt;. Enzyme assays with recombinant enzymes and mutant analysis reveal that JAR1 and AtGH3.10 conjugate &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-isoleucine to 12-OH-JA. Higher catalytic efficiency is observed with 12-OH-JA for AtGH3.10 than for JAR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jasmonates are plant hormones that regulate plant defense and development. 7-&lt;i&gt;iso&lt;/i&gt;-Jasmonoyl-&lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-isoleucine (JA-Ile) is a representative active jasmonate which is biosynthesized from 7-&lt;i&gt;iso&lt;/i&gt;-jasmonic acid (JA) by the jasmonoyl-amido synthases JASMONATE RESISTANT 1 (JAR1) and AtGH3.10 in &lt;i&gt;Arabidopsis thaliana&lt;/i&gt;. 12-Hydroxy-7-&lt;i&gt;iso&lt;/i&gt;-jasmonoyl-&lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-isoleucine (12-OH-JA-Ile) is another active jasmonate, and 12-hydroxylation of JA-Ile is considered the major biosynthetic pathway toward 12-OH-JA-Ile. Previous report elucidated that recombinant JAR1 showed a weak activity against 12-hydroxy-7-&lt;i&gt;iso&lt;/i&gt;-jasmonic acid (12-OH-JA). However, the direct conversion from 12-OH-JA to 12-OH-JA-Ile in planta and the enzyme activity of AtG3.10 against 12-OH-JA have never been reported. Herein, a feeding experiment with deuterated 12-OH-JA confirms the direct conversion of 12-OH-JA to 12-OH-JA-Ile in wild-type &lt;i&gt;Arabidopsis&lt;/i&gt; plants. The conversion from 12-OH-JA to 12-OH-JA-Ile is not observed in &lt;i&gt;jar1&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;gh3.10&lt;/i&gt; double mutant, suggesting that 12-OH-JA is converted to 12-OH-JA-Ile by JAR1 and AtGH3.10. Notably, enzyme assays show that the catalytic efficiency with 12-OH-JA for AtGH3.10 is higher than those with JA for AtGH3.10 and with 12-OH-JA for JAR1. Comparative analysis of JAR1 and AtGH3.10 structures and site-directed mutation analysis reveals that Ser120 in AtGH3.10 is the key amino acid residue responsible for its high catalytic efficiency against 12-OH-JA.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Katsunari Oki, 
Akane Enoki, 
Yoshitaka Yokota, 
Taiki Kurihara, 
Takafumi Shimizu, 
Wataru Saburi, 
Takayuki Tohge, 
Haruhide Mori, 
Guido Van den Ackerveken, 
Naoki Kitaoka, 
Hideyuki Matsuura
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>AtGH3.10 and JAR1 Produce 12&#8208;Hydroxyjasmonoyl&#8208;l&#8208;isoleucine from 12&#8208;Hydroxyjasmonic Acid in Arabidopsis thaliana</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500151</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500151</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500151</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500416</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:29:08-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500416</guid>
         <title>A Nucleotide&#8208;Derived Fluorophore for Visualizing G&#8208;Quadruplex Assembly and Introduction of Cation&#8208;Regulated Activity into the Thrombin Binding Aptamer</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
An artificial analog of nucleotides, 7,8&#8208;dihydro&#8208;8&#8208;oxo&#8208;1, N6&#8208;ethenoadenine, increases aptamer affinity, introduces cation regulation of affinity, and traces aptamer structure folding.

Nucleic acid aptamers are artificial recognition elements with great potential in biotechnology. For their effective integration into nanodevices, rational strategies for optimizing aptamer affinity and regulating activity are essential. Artificial nucleotide analogs offer versatile tools for both fundamental and applied research in the aptamer field. Herein, the affinity of a thrombin&#8208;binding aptamer is increased tenfold through a single nucleotide modification with 7,8&#8208;dihydro&#8208;8&#8208;oxo&#8208;1, N6&#8208;ethenoadenine (oxo&#8208;&#949;A) introduced at either the 4th or 13th position. Normally, thymines in these positions form a T:T base pair, which is broken during the thrombin binding. A double oxo&#8208;&#949;A modification at both the 4th and 13th positions resulted in Ag+&#8208;dependence of aptamer activity. Ag+ ions formed a noncanonical oxo&#8208;&#949;A:Ag+2:oxo&#8208;&#949;A pair, mimicking the T:T pair found in the unmodified aptamer, which is a crucial part of the thrombin recognition interface. The intrinsic fluorescence of oxo&#8208;&#949;A is used to investigate conformational rearrangements in the loops during G&#8208;quadruplex (GQ) folding. The rapid kinetics of aptamer folding are captured using a stopped&#8208;flow fluorimeter. The dissociation constants are estimated for the aptamer complexes with K+, Na+, and Ag+, revealing the tiny influence of the modifications on GQ&#160;folding.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/4d631317-4499-489f-9783-575ac05abf9f/cbic70058-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="A Nucleotide-Derived Fluorophore for Visualizing G-Quadruplex Assembly and Introduction of Cation-Regulated Activity into the Thrombin Binding Aptamer"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An artificial analog of nucleotides, 7,8-dihydro-8-oxo-1, N6-ethenoadenine, increases aptamer affinity, introduces cation regulation of affinity, and traces aptamer structure folding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nucleic acid aptamers are artificial recognition elements with great potential in biotechnology. For their effective integration into nanodevices, rational strategies for optimizing aptamer affinity and regulating activity are essential. Artificial nucleotide analogs offer versatile tools for both fundamental and applied research in the aptamer field. Herein, the affinity of a thrombin-binding aptamer is increased tenfold through a single nucleotide modification with 7,8-dihydro-8-oxo-1, N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-ethenoadenine (oxo-&#949;A) introduced at either the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; or 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; position. Normally, thymines in these positions form a T:T base pair, which is broken during the thrombin binding. A double oxo-&#949;A modification at both the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; positions resulted in Ag&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependence of aptamer activity. Ag&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; ions formed a noncanonical oxo-&#949;A:Ag&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;:oxo-&#949;A pair, mimicking the T:T pair found in the unmodified aptamer, which is a crucial part of the thrombin recognition interface. The intrinsic fluorescence of oxo-&#949;A is used to investigate conformational rearrangements in the loops during G-quadruplex (GQ) folding. The rapid kinetics of aptamer folding are captured using a stopped-flow fluorimeter. The dissociation constants are estimated for the aptamer complexes with K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, Na&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, and Ag&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, revealing the tiny influence of the modifications on GQ&#160;folding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Rugiya Alieva, 
Svetlana Sokolova, 
Ilya Oleynikov, 
Roman Novikov, 
Timofei Zatsepin, 
Andrey Aralov, 
Elena Zavyalova
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>A Nucleotide&#8208;Derived Fluorophore for Visualizing G&#8208;Quadruplex Assembly and Introduction of Cation&#8208;Regulated Activity into the Thrombin Binding Aptamer</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500416</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500416</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500416</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202400884</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:23:41 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:23:41-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202400884</guid>
         <title>Mechanoglycobiology: The Roles of Cell Surface Glycans in Mechanosensing and Mechanotransduction</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Glycans in the cell glycocalyx play an important role in sensing and transducing biophysical cues, for example, mechanical forces applied to cells, to provoke cellular responses and mediate various physiological and pathological processes, which is the research subject of mechanoglycobiology and may have a wide range of biological and biomedical applications.

Mechanoglycobiology has emerged as a rapidly expanding interdisciplinary field that involves chemistry, biology, and engineering. Despite the great advancements in this field, in&#8208;depth investigation of mechanoglycobiology remains challenging due to the complex nature of glycans and cell glycocalyx, as well as the difficulty to mechanically target these biomolecules. To address the issues, novel methods and models have been established to facilitate the investigation of glycan&#8208;mediated mechanosensing and mechanotransduction. Recently, a new, metabolic glycoengineering&#8208;based approach has been developed to selectively label cell surface glycans. This enables the application of molecularly specific acoustic tweezing cytometry to exert targeted mechanical forces to understand how mechanical actuation of glycans influences cellular activities. This approach is applicable to different glycans and cell types and, therefore, can have a broad impact. The current perspective highlights how recent developments in mechanoglycobiology may improve the knowledge and appreciation of the significance of glycans in&#160;mechanotransduction as well as the potential applications of mechanoglycobiology in medicine.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/a74fdc0e-1596-4fd7-b45c-2e54879c2449/cbic202400884-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Mechanoglycobiology: The Roles of Cell Surface Glycans in Mechanosensing and Mechanotransduction"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glycans in the cell glycocalyx play an important role in sensing and transducing biophysical cues, for example, mechanical forces applied to cells, to provoke cellular responses and mediate various physiological and pathological processes, which is the research subject of mechanoglycobiology and may have a wide range of biological and biomedical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanoglycobiology has emerged as a rapidly expanding interdisciplinary field that involves chemistry, biology, and engineering. Despite the great advancements in this field, in-depth investigation of mechanoglycobiology remains challenging due to the complex nature of glycans and cell glycocalyx, as well as the difficulty to mechanically target these biomolecules. To address the issues, novel methods and models have been established to facilitate the investigation of glycan-mediated mechanosensing and mechanotransduction. Recently, a new, metabolic glycoengineering-based approach has been developed to selectively label cell surface glycans. This enables the application of molecularly specific acoustic tweezing cytometry to exert targeted mechanical forces to understand how mechanical actuation of glycans influences cellular activities. This approach is applicable to different glycans and cell types and, therefore, can have a broad impact. The current perspective highlights how recent developments in mechanoglycobiology may improve the knowledge and appreciation of the significance of glycans in&#160;mechanotransduction as well as the potential applications of mechanoglycobiology in medicine.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jiatong Guo, 
Weiping Li, 
Cheri X. Deng, 
Zhongwu Guo
</dc:creator>
         <category>Perspective</category>
         <dc:title>Mechanoglycobiology: The Roles of Cell Surface Glycans in Mechanosensing and Mechanotransduction</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202400884</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202400884</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202400884</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Perspective</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500551</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:18:19 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:18:19-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500551</guid>
         <title>Mitochondrial ClpX Inhibition Induces Ferroptosis and Blocks Pancreatic Cancer Cell Proliferation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Functional inhibition of ClpXP induces mitochondrial dysfunction, ultimately driving lethal lipid peroxidation and ferroptosis. Through ATPase&#8208;focused screening, we identified MSC1094308 as a hit compound for ClpX inhibition, recapitulating the effects of CLPX&#8208;knockdown by inducing mitochondrial dysfunction and ferroptosis in PDAC cells.

The ATPase caseinolytic protease X (ClpX), forming the ClpXP complex with caseinolytic protease P (ClpP), is essential for mitochondrial protein homeostasis. While ClpP targeting is a recognized anticancer strategy, the role of ClpX in cancer remains underexplored. In pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), elevated CLPX expression correlates with poor prognosis, suggesting its oncogenic function. CLPX knockdown disrupts mitochondrial homeostasis, and reduces oxidative phosphorylation, thus leading to mitochondrial dysfunction and impaired PDAC cell proliferation. The ClpX&#8208;mediated mitochondrial dysfunction induces oxidative stress, unfolded protein response (UPR), and ferroptosis, which is evidenced by increased reactive oxygen species, ferrous iron, lipid peroxidation, and malondialdehyde levels. Screening ATPase inhibitors identifies MSC1094308 as a hit compound for ClpX inhibition, which suppresses ClpXP activity and induces UPR and ferroptosis in PDAC cells. These findings highlight ClpX inhibition as a promising therapeutic strategy for PDAC.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/50983ba1-5096-4806-85c6-b9b617cb2ef6/cbic70064-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Mitochondrial ClpX Inhibition Induces Ferroptosis and Blocks Pancreatic Cancer Cell Proliferation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functional inhibition of ClpXP induces mitochondrial dysfunction, ultimately driving lethal lipid peroxidation and ferroptosis. Through ATPase-focused screening, we identified MSC1094308 as a hit compound for ClpX inhibition, recapitulating the effects of &lt;i&gt;CLPX&lt;/i&gt;-knockdown by inducing mitochondrial dysfunction and ferroptosis in PDAC cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ATPase caseinolytic protease X (ClpX), forming the ClpXP complex with caseinolytic protease P (ClpP), is essential for mitochondrial protein homeostasis. While ClpP targeting is a recognized anticancer strategy, the role of ClpX in cancer remains underexplored. In pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), elevated &lt;i&gt;CLPX&lt;/i&gt; expression correlates with poor prognosis, suggesting its oncogenic function. &lt;i&gt;CLPX&lt;/i&gt; knockdown disrupts mitochondrial homeostasis, and reduces oxidative phosphorylation, thus leading to mitochondrial dysfunction and impaired PDAC cell proliferation. The ClpX-mediated mitochondrial dysfunction induces oxidative stress, unfolded protein response (UPR), and ferroptosis, which is evidenced by increased reactive oxygen species, ferrous iron, lipid peroxidation, and malondialdehyde levels. Screening ATPase inhibitors identifies MSC1094308 as a hit compound for ClpX inhibition, which suppresses ClpXP activity and induces UPR and ferroptosis in PDAC cells. These findings highlight ClpX inhibition as a promising therapeutic strategy for PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Pengyu Wang, 
Ranran Zhang, 
Yihui Pan, 
Wei Wu, 
Tao Zhang, 
Cai&#8208;Guang Yang
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Mitochondrial ClpX Inhibition Induces Ferroptosis and Blocks Pancreatic Cancer Cell Proliferation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500551</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500551</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500551</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500574</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:15:22 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:15:22-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500574</guid>
         <title>Characterization of the N&#8208;Hydroxylating Monooxygenase TheA from Thermocrispum agreste Reveals a Broad Substrate Spectrum</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
TheA is a moderate thermostable flavin&#8208;dependent monooxygenase which accepts, besides l&#8208;ornithine a number of related molecules for the regio&#8208;selective N&#8208;hydroxylation. The combination with a NADP+&#8208;reducing formate dehydrogenase variant (FDH M4) and a H2O2 degrading catalase allows in vitro biocatalytic applications.

The N&#8208;hydroxylating monooxygenase (NMO) TheA from Thermocrispum agreste catalyzes the N&#8208;hydroxylation step of l&#8208;ornithine, which is the first step in the thermochelin siderophore biosynthesis. Characterization of this enzyme revealed a significant thermostability up to 50&#8201;&#176;C and activity with the non&#8208;native substrate d&#8208;ornithine with kinetic parameters (Km&#8201;=&#8201;4.06&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.31&#8201;mM, kcat&#8201;=&#8201;0.057&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.001 s&#8722;1, and kcat/Km&#8201;=&#8201;0.007&#8201;s&#8722;1&#8201;mM&#8722;1) and a coupling rate of 81%. The enzyme is applied in a one&#8208;pot reaction with a formate dehydrogenase variant for NADPH regeneration and catalase for H2O2 detoxification. Optimization of the reaction conditions resulted in activity with various non&#8208;native substrates such as d&#8208;ornithine, l&#8208;lysine, S&#8208;(2&#8208;aminoethyl)&#8208;l&#8208;cysteine, and l&#8208;arginine. Products are confirmed through LC&#8208;MS/MS, and mutagenesis experiments gave insight on the potentially underlying mechanisms. This work identifies a thermotolerant NMO that is suitable for application and as a starting point for enzyme engineering.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/071b9ec6-2317-4ae8-90a9-dfb39c9b42a3/cbic70068-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Characterization of the N-Hydroxylating Monooxygenase TheA from Thermocrispum agreste Reveals a Broad Substrate Spectrum"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TheA is a moderate thermostable flavin-dependent monooxygenase which accepts, besides &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-ornithine a number of related molecules for the regio-selective &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-hydroxylation. The combination with a NADP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-reducing formate dehydrogenase variant (FDH M4) and a H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; degrading catalase allows in vitro biocatalytic applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-hydroxylating monooxygenase (NMO) TheA from &lt;i&gt;Thermocrispum agreste&lt;/i&gt; catalyzes the &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-hydroxylation step of &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-ornithine, which is the first step in the thermochelin siderophore biosynthesis. Characterization of this enzyme revealed a significant thermostability up to 50&#8201;&#176;C and activity with the non-native substrate &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;-ornithine with kinetic parameters (&lt;i&gt;K&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;&#8201;=&#8201;4.06&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.31&#8201;mM, &lt;i&gt;k&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;cat&lt;/sub&gt;&#8201;=&#8201;0.057&#8201;&#177;&#8201;0.001 s&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;k&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;cat&lt;/sub&gt;/&lt;i&gt;K&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;&#8201;=&#8201;0.007&#8201;s&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&#8201;&lt;/sup&gt;mM&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt;) and a coupling rate of 81%. The enzyme is applied in a one-pot reaction with a formate dehydrogenase variant for NADPH regeneration and catalase for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; detoxification. Optimization of the reaction conditions resulted in activity with various non-native substrates such as &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;-ornithine, &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-lysine, S-(2-aminoethyl)-&lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-cysteine, and &lt;span class="smallCaps"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;-arginine. Products are confirmed through LC-MS/MS, and mutagenesis experiments gave insight on the potentially underlying mechanisms. This work identifies a thermotolerant NMO that is suitable for application and as a starting point for enzyme engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Artur Maier, 
Daniel Fast, 
Dmytro Sakalo, 
Lindelo Mguni, 
Dirk Tischler
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Characterization of the N&#8208;Hydroxylating Monooxygenase TheA from Thermocrispum agreste Reveals a Broad Substrate Spectrum</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500574</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500574</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500574</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500618</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:14:56 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:14:56-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500618</guid>
         <title>Cooperative Enhancement of Aldoxime Dehydratase Stability through Whole&#8208;Cell Immobilization and Flow Reactor Integration</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
This work presents a synergistic approach to enhance the stability of the engineered aldoxime dehydratase OxdF1 (L318F/F306Y) by combining whole&#8208;cell immobilization in Ba&#8208;alginate with continuous flow processing. Applied to challenging substrates, like 2,6&#8208;difluorobenzaldoxime, the system enables efficient, stable nitrile synthesis with in&#8208;line product extraction and improved sustainability.

This study investigates the synthesis of aromatic nitriles using an evolved variant of OxdF1 (L318F/F306Y), an aldoxime dehydratase from Pseudomonas putida F1, engineered for improved catalytic efficiency toward benzaldehyde oxime. The double OxdF1 (L318F/F306Y) mutant effectively catalyzes the conversion of various benzaldoxime derivatives to the corresponding nitriles. Due to the enzyme's inherent instability, immobilized whole&#8208;cell systems are employed in a flow reactor to improve its stability and broaden its applicability, with the biotransformation of benzaldehyde oxime and 2,6&#8208;difluorobenzaldehyde oxime serving as case studies. The enzyme's stability is markedly improved, maintaining 87% yield even after 8&#8201;h of processing in the preparation of benzonitrile. Preparation of 2,6&#8208;difluorobenzontirile poses additional challenges due to the low water solubility of both the substrate, and even more so, the product, an important intermediate in various chemical applications. To overcome solubility limitations, a segmented liquid&#8211;liquid flow system (water/cyclohexane) was implemented, significantly improving the enzyme stability. The process was run continuously for 12&#8201;h, with a conversion of &#8776;70% by the end of the operation. Furthermore, 2,6&#8208;difluorobenzonitrile is selectively extracted in&#8208;line using a liquid&#8211;liquid extractor, thus, facilitating its efficient recovery and purification.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/bd1d9d00-5b1e-4f3c-a341-90cb84190767/cbic70066-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Cooperative Enhancement of Aldoxime Dehydratase Stability through Whole-Cell Immobilization and Flow Reactor Integration"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work presents a synergistic approach to enhance the stability of the engineered aldoxime dehydratase OxdF1 (L318F/F306Y) by combining whole-cell immobilization in Ba-alginate with continuous flow processing. Applied to challenging substrates, like 2,6-difluorobenzaldoxime, the system enables efficient, stable nitrile synthesis with in-line product extraction and improved sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study investigates the synthesis of aromatic nitriles using an evolved variant of OxdF1 (L318F/F306Y), an aldoxime dehydratase from &lt;i&gt;Pseudomonas putida&lt;/i&gt; F1, engineered for improved catalytic efficiency toward benzaldehyde oxime. The double OxdF1 (L318F/F306Y) mutant effectively catalyzes the conversion of various benzaldoxime derivatives to the corresponding nitriles. Due to the enzyme's inherent instability, immobilized whole-cell systems are employed in a flow reactor to improve its stability and broaden its applicability, with the biotransformation of benzaldehyde oxime and 2,6-difluorobenzaldehyde oxime serving as case studies. The enzyme's stability is markedly improved, maintaining 87% yield even after 8&#8201;h of processing in the preparation of benzonitrile. Preparation of 2,6-difluorobenzontirile poses additional challenges due to the low water solubility of both the substrate, and even more so, the product, an important intermediate in various chemical applications. To overcome solubility limitations, a segmented liquid&#8211;liquid flow system (water/cyclohexane) was implemented, significantly improving the enzyme stability. The process was run continuously for 12&#8201;h, with a conversion of &#8776;70% by the end of the operation. Furthermore, 2,6-difluorobenzonitrile is selectively extracted in-line using a liquid&#8211;liquid extractor, thus, facilitating its efficient recovery and purification.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Luca Nespoli, 
Silvia Donzella, 
Martina Bigliardi, 
Martina Letizia Contente, 
Ricardo Pinheiro de Souza Oliveira, 
Diego Romano, 
Francesco Molinari
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Cooperative Enhancement of Aldoxime Dehydratase Stability through Whole&#8208;Cell Immobilization and Flow Reactor Integration</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500618</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500618</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500618</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500479</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-11T12:09:00-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500479</guid>
         <title>The Linear Arginoketides Neotetrafibricin A, B, and C have Algicidal and Signal Function in Microbial Interactions</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
This study highlights the effect of the linear arginoketides neotetrafibricins on microorganisms. Structure&#8211;activity relationship analyses revealed that structural elements as the sugar moiety are not essential and presence of a guanidino or an amino group are interchangeable for bioactivity because the neotetrafibricin congeners described exhibited similar algicidal activity and signaling function towards a filamentous fungus.

Soils harbor some of the most diverse microbiomes on Earth. Interactions within these microbial communities are often mediated by natural products, many functioning as chemical signals. Specialized metabolites known as arginoketides, or arginine&#8208;derived polyketides, have been linked to mediate these interactions. However, the effect of linear arginoketides on soil microalgae has not yet been investigated. Here, we report that Streptomyces mashuensis DSM40221 produces the linear arginoketide neotetrafibricin A, and show that it exhibits algicidal activity against the green alga Chlamydomonas reinhardtii and induces production of orsellinic acid and derivatives encoded by the silent ors biosynthetic gene cluster (BGC) in the fungus Aspergillus nidulans. Thus, neotetrafibricin serves as an inter&#8208;kingdom signaling molecule. Genome mining identified the neotetrafibricin BGC in S. mashuensis. Disrupting the first polyketide synthase gene abolished neotetrafibricin production. Further mutational studies identified two neotetrafibricin congeners, including the novel neotetrafibricin C, which contains a terminal guanidino group. Structure&#8211;activity relationship analyses revealed that neither the terminal amino group nor the sugar moiety is essential for its algicidal activity or the induction of the ors BGC in the fungus. These findings expand the understanding of linear arginoketides in microbial ecology and highlight their potential as multifunctional signaling compounds in soil environments.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/3aa9bef1-cfd6-4033-98f7-a232ea8e2d37/cbic70060-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="The Linear Arginoketides Neotetrafibricin A, B, and C have Algicidal and Signal Function in Microbial Interactions"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study highlights the effect of the linear arginoketides neotetrafibricins on microorganisms. Structure&#8211;activity relationship analyses revealed that structural elements as the sugar moiety are not essential and presence of a guanidino or an amino group are interchangeable for bioactivity because the neotetrafibricin congeners described exhibited similar algicidal activity and signaling function towards a filamentous fungus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soils harbor some of the most diverse microbiomes on Earth. Interactions within these microbial communities are often mediated by natural products, many functioning as chemical signals. Specialized metabolites known as arginoketides, or arginine-derived polyketides, have been linked to mediate these interactions. However, the effect of linear arginoketides on soil microalgae has not yet been investigated. Here, we report that &lt;i&gt;Streptomyces mashuensis&lt;/i&gt; DSM40221 produces the linear arginoketide neotetrafibricin A, and show that it exhibits algicidal activity against the green alga &lt;i&gt;Chlamydomonas reinhardtii&lt;/i&gt; and induces production of orsellinic acid and derivatives encoded by the silent &lt;i&gt;ors&lt;/i&gt; biosynthetic gene cluster (BGC) in the fungus &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus nidulans&lt;/i&gt;. Thus, neotetrafibricin serves as an inter-kingdom signaling molecule. Genome mining identified the neotetrafibricin BGC in &lt;i&gt;S. mashuensis&lt;/i&gt;. Disrupting the first polyketide synthase gene abolished neotetrafibricin production. Further mutational studies identified two neotetrafibricin congeners, including the novel neotetrafibricin C, which contains a terminal guanidino group. Structure&#8211;activity relationship analyses revealed that neither the terminal amino group nor the sugar moiety is essential for its algicidal activity or the induction of the &lt;i&gt;ors&lt;/i&gt; BGC in the fungus. These findings expand the understanding of linear arginoketides in microbial ecology and highlight their potential as multifunctional signaling compounds in soil environments.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Mario K. C. Krespach, 
Maira Rosin, 
Kirstin Scherlach, 
Maria C. Stroe, 
Christian Hertweck, 
Axel Brakhage
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>The Linear Arginoketides Neotetrafibricin A, B, and C have Algicidal and Signal Function in Microbial Interactions</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500479</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500479</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500479</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500432</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:59:41 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-02T12:59:41-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500432</guid>
         <title>Artificial Peptides as Autophagy Modulators</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Autophagy is a fundamental cellular process that eliminates molecules and subcellular elements. This process is crucial for maintaining homeostasis and responding to various stressors, playing a key role in physiological development and the genesis of pathological conditions. This review summarizes recent advances in autophagy regulation strategies and the development of artificial peptide&#8208;based tools for monitoring and modulating autophagy.

Autophagy is a highly conserved lysosomal degradation pathway for maintaining cellular homeostasis. Its dysregulation is implicated in various diseases, including cancer, neurodegeneration, and infections, making precise modulation of autophagy a potentially promising therapeutic strategy. Artificial peptide&#8208;based autophagy modulators have emerged as a promising alternative to conventional small molecules, offering several advantages in terms of specificity, biocompatibility, and functional versatility. This review summarizes recent advances in artificial peptide&#8208;based autophagy monitoring tools, autophagy inducers, and autophagy inhibitors.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e006f1f7-be23-4766-9d83-7ac5bee66ea6/cbic70057-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Artificial Peptides as Autophagy Modulators"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a fundamental cellular process that eliminates molecules and subcellular elements. This process is crucial for maintaining homeostasis and responding to various stressors, playing a key role in physiological development and the genesis of pathological conditions. This review summarizes recent advances in autophagy regulation strategies and the development of artificial peptide-based tools for monitoring and modulating autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a highly conserved lysosomal degradation pathway for maintaining cellular homeostasis. Its dysregulation is implicated in various diseases, including cancer, neurodegeneration, and infections, making precise modulation of autophagy a potentially promising therapeutic strategy. Artificial peptide-based autophagy modulators have emerged as a promising alternative to conventional small molecules, offering several advantages in terms of specificity, biocompatibility, and functional versatility. This review summarizes recent advances in artificial peptide-based autophagy monitoring tools, autophagy inducers, and autophagy inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yuhai Cai, 
Ling Qiu, 
Boyu Zhang, 
Guanya Yang, 
Jin Cui
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Artificial Peptides as Autophagy Modulators</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500432</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500432</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500432</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500522</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:53:33 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-09-02T12:53:33-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500522</guid>
         <title>Homogeneous Electrochemical Enzyme&#8208;Linked Immunosorbent Assay Strategy Based On pH&#8208;Mediated Redox Potential Regulation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
A homogeneous electrochemical enzyme&#8208;linked immunosorbent assay platform is developed, which simplifies and accelerates signal acquisition in field settings. Target&#8208;induced pH change is carefully investigated. Highly sensitive, reproducible, and quantitative electrochemical detection is achieved with C&#8208;reactive protein as a model target.

Enzyme&#8208;linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) is widely recognized as the gold standard for protein detection. However, its reliance on expensive and bulky optical instruments limits its use in point&#8208;of&#8208;care and resource&#8208;limited settings. Electrochemical technique emerges as a promising alternative due to its low cost, portability, and simple instrumentation. However, conventional electrochemical methods often require complex surface modifications and suffer from variability between electrodes. To overcome these limitations, a novel homogeneous electrochemical ELISA platform has been developed, that simplifies and accelerates signal acquisition in field settings. This platform leverages pH changes caused by alkaline phosphatase&#8208;catalyzed hydrolysis of ATP, resulting in solution acidification. These pH variations are sensitively detected through shifts in the redox potential of methylene blue (MB), a proton&#8208;sensitive electrochemical probe. By quantitatively correlating the target protein concentration with MB redox potential shift, a sensitive, reproducible, and quantitative electrochemical detection of a model protein, C&#8208;reactive protein, is achieved. This versatile and cost&#8208;effective approach holds significant potential to expand the applicability of ELISA to point&#8208;of&#8208;care diagnostics.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/55f7f30f-4358-4838-87e2-4452828df1cc/cbic70055-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Homogeneous Electrochemical Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay Strategy Based On pH-Mediated Redox Potential Regulation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A homogeneous electrochemical enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay platform is developed, which simplifies and accelerates signal acquisition in field settings. Target-induced pH change is carefully investigated. Highly sensitive, reproducible, and quantitative electrochemical detection is achieved with C-reactive protein as a model target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) is widely recognized as the gold standard for protein detection. However, its reliance on expensive and bulky optical instruments limits its use in point-of-care and resource-limited settings. Electrochemical technique emerges as a promising alternative due to its low cost, portability, and simple instrumentation. However, conventional electrochemical methods often require complex surface modifications and suffer from variability between electrodes. To overcome these limitations, a novel homogeneous electrochemical ELISA platform has been developed, that simplifies and accelerates signal acquisition in field settings. This platform leverages pH changes caused by alkaline phosphatase-catalyzed hydrolysis of ATP, resulting in solution acidification. These pH variations are sensitively detected through shifts in the redox potential of methylene blue (MB), a proton-sensitive electrochemical probe. By quantitatively correlating the target protein concentration with MB redox potential shift, a sensitive, reproducible, and quantitative electrochemical detection of a model protein, C-reactive protein, is achieved. This versatile and cost-effective approach holds significant potential to expand the applicability of ELISA to point-of-care diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jianyang Lu, 
Yiwei Han, 
Xiaomeng Yu, 
Xifeng Chen, 
Jie Yang, 
Peng Miao
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Homogeneous Electrochemical Enzyme&#8208;Linked Immunosorbent Assay Strategy Based On pH&#8208;Mediated Redox Potential Regulation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500522</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500522</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500522</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500557</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 08:31:18 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-29T08:31:18-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500557</guid>
         <title>Quantitative Strategies for Decoding Organelle Ion Dynamics</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
This review highlights cutting&#8208;edge strategies for probing ion dynamics within organelles using fluorescent indicators. It discusses key advances in calibration techniques for absolute ion quantification and their impact on understanding organellar physiology, and concludes with future directions and applications in decoding ion&#8208;regulated processes in health and disease.

Ion dynamics within cellular organelles are fundamental to numerous biochemical processes, maintaining homeostasis and enabling critical cellular functions. Despite continuous ion movement across organelle membranes, stable ionic gradients are preserved, creating optimal microenvironments for organelle&#8208;specific activities such as ATP production in mitochondria, lysosomal degradation, Golgi&#8208;mediated protein modifications, and DNA processing in the nucleus. These gradients are regulated by specialized membrane proteins, including ion channels and transporters, which facilitate selective and controlled ion flux. Dysfunction in these regulatory proteins is linked to various diseases, including neurodegenerative disorders, cardiovascular conditions, immune dysfunctions, and cancers. Understanding ion regulation mechanisms at the molecular level is not only essential for basic cell biology but also crucial for revealing pathological pathways and identifying therapeutic targets. Recent technological advances&#8212;such as fluorescent probes based on green fluorescent protein, small molecules, and DNA nanodevices&#8212;have significantly enhanced our ability to study ion dynamics with high spatial and temporal resolution. These tools enable both qualitative and quantitative analyses, offering insights into ion transport mechanisms and their physiological relevance. A comprehensive overview of the principles underlying functional imaging of ion dynamics is provided, current challenges in quantitative assessment are highlighted, and future directions in organelle&#8208;specific ion regulation are discussed.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/4d37c1bb-c621-45d0-802f-b2e5062a7762/cbic70052-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Quantitative Strategies for Decoding Organelle Ion Dynamics"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review highlights cutting-edge strategies for probing ion dynamics within organelles using fluorescent indicators. It discusses key advances in calibration techniques for absolute ion quantification and their impact on understanding organellar physiology, and concludes with future directions and applications in decoding ion-regulated processes in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ion dynamics within cellular organelles are fundamental to numerous biochemical processes, maintaining homeostasis and enabling critical cellular functions. Despite continuous ion movement across organelle membranes, stable ionic gradients are preserved, creating optimal microenvironments for organelle-specific activities such as ATP production in mitochondria, lysosomal degradation, Golgi-mediated protein modifications, and DNA processing in the nucleus. These gradients are regulated by specialized membrane proteins, including ion channels and transporters, which facilitate selective and controlled ion flux. Dysfunction in these regulatory proteins is linked to various diseases, including neurodegenerative disorders, cardiovascular conditions, immune dysfunctions, and cancers. Understanding ion regulation mechanisms at the molecular level is not only essential for basic cell biology but also crucial for revealing pathological pathways and identifying therapeutic targets. Recent technological advances&#8212;such as fluorescent probes based on green fluorescent protein, small molecules, and DNA nanodevices&#8212;have significantly enhanced our ability to study ion dynamics with high spatial and temporal resolution. These tools enable both qualitative and quantitative analyses, offering insights into ion transport mechanisms and their physiological relevance. A comprehensive overview of the principles underlying functional imaging of ion dynamics is provided, current challenges in quantitative assessment are highlighted, and future directions in organelle-specific ion regulation are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Palapuravan Anees
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Quantitative Strategies for Decoding Organelle Ion Dynamics</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500557</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500557</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500557</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500310</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:35:13 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-26T12:35:13-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500310</guid>
         <title>Photo&#8208;Triggered Hyaluronic Acid Hydrogel for 3D Culture and Cell Recovery</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
GA: Cross&#8208;linking of hyaluronic acid modified by a strained alkyne with a photosensitive crosslinker terminating in azides gives hydrogels with tuneable mechanical properties. By tuning the wavelength of employed light, the hydrogel can either be fully degraded allowing harvesting of cultured cells or softened resulting in notable changes in cell morphology.

Properties of semisynthetic hydrogels can be fine&#8208;tuned, making these attractive for various applications in regenerative medicine. Herein, a hydrogel platform based on hyaluronic acid (HA) modified by (1R, 8S,9S)&#8208;bicycle[6.1.0]non&#8208;4&#8208;yn&#8208;9&#8208;ylmethanol (BCN) and a cross&#8208;linker composed of light&#8208;sensitive o&#8208;nitrobenzyl and polyethylene glycol (PEG) chains terminating in azides is described. The two components can undergo strain&#8208;promoted azide&#8211;alkyne cycloaddition resulting in rapid gel formation. First, adipose&#8208;derived mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) are incorporated in the hydrogel and it is demonstrated that the cells can be easily retrieved by UV light&#8208;mediated degradation, maintaining viability and retaining spindle&#8208;like shape when the cells are replated. Next, a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept of inducing light&#8208;mediated softening of the hydrogel to modulate the morphology of the encapsulated cells is provided. A co&#8208;culture of endothelial cells (cord blood&#8208;derived endothelial colony forming cells and bone marrow&#8208;derived MSCs), which is commonly studied for their ability to form capillary&#8208;like vascular networks, is cultured in the regular and light&#8208;induced softened hydrogels. Nonphotoexposed hydrogels show cells with a prevalently rounded morphology, whereas stretched cells connecting into a primitive capillary network are observed in the light&#8208;softened hydrogels. Photo&#8208;induced softening offers potential to locally control cell shape and self&#8208;organization capacity.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/c242a7b1-1084-49ae-b211-e6b07232d87d/cbic202500310-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Photo-Triggered Hyaluronic Acid Hydrogel for 3D Culture and Cell Recovery"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GA:&lt;/b&gt; Cross-linking of hyaluronic acid modified by a strained alkyne with a photosensitive crosslinker terminating in azides gives hydrogels with tuneable mechanical properties. By tuning the wavelength of employed light, the hydrogel can either be fully degraded allowing harvesting of cultured cells or softened resulting in notable changes in cell morphology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Properties of semisynthetic hydrogels can be fine-tuned, making these attractive for various applications in regenerative medicine. Herein, a hydrogel platform based on hyaluronic acid (HA) modified by (1R, 8S,9S)-bicycle[6.1.0]non-4-yn-9-ylmethanol (BCN) and a cross-linker composed of light-sensitive &lt;i&gt;o&lt;/i&gt;-nitrobenzyl and polyethylene glycol (PEG) chains terminating in azides is described. The two components can undergo strain-promoted azide&#8211;alkyne cycloaddition resulting in rapid gel formation. First, adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) are incorporated in the hydrogel and it is demonstrated that the cells can be easily retrieved by UV light-mediated degradation, maintaining viability and retaining spindle-like shape when the cells are replated. Next, a proof-of-concept of inducing light-mediated softening of the hydrogel to modulate the morphology of the encapsulated cells is provided. A co-culture of endothelial cells (cord blood-derived endothelial colony forming cells and bone marrow-derived MSCs), which is commonly studied for their ability to form capillary-like vascular networks, is cultured in the regular and light-induced softened hydrogels. Nonphotoexposed hydrogels show cells with a prevalently rounded morphology, whereas stretched cells connecting into a primitive capillary network are observed in the light-softened hydrogels. Photo-induced softening offers potential to locally control cell shape and self-organization capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Francesco Palmieri, 
Mari&#232;me Gueye, 
Lucia Vicario del Rio, 
Saskia Bunschuh, 
Pradeep Chopra, 
Silvia Mih&#259;il&#259;, 
Tina Vermonden, 
Riccardo Levato, 
Geert&#8208;Jan Boons
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Photo&#8208;Triggered Hyaluronic Acid Hydrogel for 3D Culture and Cell Recovery</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500310</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500310</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500310</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500412</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:25:27 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-26T12:25:27-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500412</guid>
         <title>Exploring the Substrate Flexibility of GrsB Thioesterase Leads to the Structural Reassignment of a Gramicidin S Variant</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Investigation of the substrate specificity of gramicidin S synthetase B&#8208;thioesterase reveals stereochemical flexibility, enabling the production of gramicidin S (GS) analogs with L&#8208; or D&#8208;Ser(Allyl). Structural reassignment of a GS variant (GS&#8208;SA) obtained from precursor&#8208;directed biosynthesis is achieved using liquid chromatography&#8208;mass spectrometry, 1H nuclear magnetic resonance, and antimicrobial assays.

Gramicidin S (GS) is a cyclic decapeptide derived from two pentapeptides. The C&#8208;terminal thioesterase (TE) domain of gramicidin S synthetase B (GrsB) dimerizes precursor pentapeptides and cyclizes the resulting linear decapeptide. Recently, a GS variant (GS&#8208;SA), in which a single D&#8208;Phe is replaced by L&#8208;Ser(Allyl), is reported via precursor&#8208;directed biosynthesis in a native GS producer. To understand how GrsB&#8208;TE processes such modified precursors, its substrate specificity using synthetic linear peptides is investigated. GrsB&#8208;TE cyclizes a substrate containing L&#8208;Ser(Allyl) at position 6 but not at position 1. However, the enzymatically synthesized GS&#8208;SA shows a different high&#8208;performance liquid chromatography retention time than that of the reported GS variant. Further structural and functional analyses, including 1H nuclear magnetic resonance, antimicrobial assays, and circular dichroism spectroscopy, reveal that the reported GS&#8208;SA contained D&#8208;Ser(Allyl) rather than L&#8208;Ser(Allyl). These findings reveal a previously unrecognized stereochemical flexibility in GrsB&#8208;TE and support the structural revision of the reported GS variant.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/caba6dde-028f-4cdc-b2fd-c040f4dc4e85/cbic202500412-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Exploring the Substrate Flexibility of GrsB Thioesterase Leads to the Structural Reassignment of a Gramicidin S Variant"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigation of the substrate specificity of gramicidin S synthetase B-thioesterase reveals stereochemical flexibility, enabling the production of gramicidin S (GS) analogs with L- or D-Ser(Allyl). Structural reassignment of a GS variant (GS-SA) obtained from precursor-directed biosynthesis is achieved using liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H nuclear magnetic resonance, and antimicrobial assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gramicidin S (GS) is a cyclic decapeptide derived from two pentapeptides. The C-terminal thioesterase (TE) domain of gramicidin S synthetase B (GrsB) dimerizes precursor pentapeptides and cyclizes the resulting linear decapeptide. Recently, a GS variant (GS-SA), in which a single D-Phe is replaced by L-Ser(Allyl), is reported via precursor-directed biosynthesis in a native GS producer. To understand how GrsB-TE processes such modified precursors, its substrate specificity using synthetic linear peptides is investigated. GrsB-TE cyclizes a substrate containing L-Ser(Allyl) at position 6 but not at position 1. However, the enzymatically synthesized GS-SA shows a different high-performance liquid chromatography retention time than that of the reported GS variant. Further structural and functional analyses, including &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H nuclear magnetic resonance, antimicrobial assays, and circular dichroism spectroscopy, reveal that the reported GS-SA contained D-Ser(Allyl) rather than L-Ser(Allyl). These findings reveal a previously unrecognized stereochemical flexibility in GrsB-TE and support the structural revision of the reported GS variant.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Sho Konno, 
Tomoe Mizuguchi, 
Atsuko Suzuki, 
Miyu Tanaka, 
Fumihiro Ishikawa, 
Akihiro Taguchi, 
Atsuhiko Taniguchi, 
Genzoh Tanabe, 
Yoshio Hayashi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Exploring the Substrate Flexibility of GrsB Thioesterase Leads to the Structural Reassignment of a Gramicidin S Variant</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500412</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500412</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500412</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500447</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:20:47 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-26T12:20:47-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500447</guid>
         <title>Gold&#8208;Dithiocarbamato Glycoconjugates as Potential Anticancer Agents: Design, Physico&#8208;Chemical Characterization, and In Vitro Biological Activity</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Metal&#8208;dithiocarbamato glycoconjugates based on gold(III), gold(I)&#8208;phosphino, and gold(I)&#8208;carbene scaffolds are here investigated as potential anticancer agents. Contrary to expectations, they induce cell death by acting at the extracellular level rather than targeting overexpressed glucose transporters.

To develop new metal&#8208;based glycoconjugates as potential anticancer agents, three gold(III)&#8208;dithiocarbamato glycoconjugates of the type [AuIIIBr2(SSC&#8208;Inp&#8208;GlcN)] (Au3&#8208;5), their gold(I)&#8208;phosphine counterparts [AuI(SSC&#8208;Inp&#8208;GlcN)(PPh3)] (AuP3&#8208;5), and gold(I)&#8208;carbene analogs [AuI(SSC&#8208;Inp&#8208;GlcN)(Et2BzImy)] (AuC3&#8208;5) (Inp: isonipecotic moiety; GlcN: amino&#8208;glucose scaffold; Et2BzImy: 1,3&#8208;diethylbenzimidazol&#8208;2&#8208;ylidene moiety), as well as the corresponding non&#8208;glycosylated counterparts (Au1&#8208;2, AuP1&#8208;2, and AuC1&#8208;2) bearing a terminal ester or amide function, are generated and characterized by means of several analytical techniques (FT&#8208;IR, 1H&#8208;/13C&#8208;NMR, UV&#8211;Vis, X&#8208;ray crystallography). Their stability under physiologically relevant conditions (phosphate&#8208;buffered saline solution) has also been evaluated. Contrary to the gold(III)&#8208;glycoconjugates, the glucose&#8208;functionalized gold(I) derivatives show a significant antiproliferative effect against colorectal adenocarcinoma (HT&#8208;29), metastatic breast adenocarcinoma (MDA&#8208;MB&#8208;231), and breast adenocarcinoma (MCF&#8208;7) cells, with IC50 values in the low micromolar range, the gold(I)&#8208;phosphine derivatives turning up to be the best performers. Cell uptake studies show no evident correlation between cell growth inhibition and cellular uptake, and the use of glucose&#8208;free cell culture media and a GLUT1 inhibitor rules out the involvement of glucose transporters in cell internalization, thus suggesting alternative cell death pathways such as acting at extracellular level (especially for the gold(I) derivatives).
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/618cb579-1f95-4141-b029-aadb2ab3a507/cbic202500447-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Gold-Dithiocarbamato Glycoconjugates as Potential Anticancer Agents: Design, Physico-Chemical Characterization, and In Vitro Biological Activity"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal-dithiocarbamato glycoconjugates based on gold(III), gold(I)-phosphino, and gold(I)-carbene scaffolds are here investigated as potential anticancer agents. Contrary to expectations, they induce cell death by acting at the extracellular level rather than targeting overexpressed glucose transporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To develop new metal-based glycoconjugates as potential anticancer agents, three gold(III)-dithiocarbamato glycoconjugates of the type [Au&lt;sup&gt;III&lt;/sup&gt;Br&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(SSC-Inp-GlcN)] (&lt;b&gt;Au3-5&lt;/b&gt;), their gold(I)-phosphine counterparts [Au&lt;sup&gt;I&lt;/sup&gt;(SSC-Inp-GlcN)(PPh&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;)] (&lt;b&gt;AuP3-5&lt;/b&gt;), and gold(I)-carbene analogs [Au&lt;sup&gt;I&lt;/sup&gt;(SSC-Inp-GlcN)(Et&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;BzImy)] (&lt;b&gt;AuC3-5&lt;/b&gt;) (Inp: isonipecotic moiety; GlcN: amino-glucose scaffold; Et&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;BzImy: 1,3-diethylbenzimidazol-2-ylidene moiety), as well as the corresponding non-glycosylated counterparts (&lt;b&gt;Au1-2&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;AuP1-2,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;AuC1-2&lt;/b&gt;) bearing a terminal ester or amide function, are generated and characterized by means of several analytical techniques (FT-IR, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H-/&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C-NMR, UV&#8211;Vis, X-ray crystallography). Their stability under physiologically relevant conditions (phosphate-buffered saline solution) has also been evaluated. Contrary to the gold(III)-glycoconjugates, the glucose-functionalized gold(I) derivatives show a significant antiproliferative effect against colorectal adenocarcinoma (HT-29), metastatic breast adenocarcinoma (MDA-MB-231), and breast adenocarcinoma (MCF-7) cells, with IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; values in the low micromolar range, the gold(I)-phosphine derivatives turning up to be the best performers. Cell uptake studies show no evident correlation between cell growth inhibition and cellular uptake, and the use of glucose-free cell culture media and a GLUT1 inhibitor rules out the involvement of glucose transporters in cell internalization, thus suggesting alternative cell death pathways such as acting at extracellular level (especially for the gold(I) derivatives).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Andrea Pettenuzzo, 
Jessica W&#246;lker, 
Luciano Marchi&#242;, 
Ingo Ott, 
Luca Ronconi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Gold&#8208;Dithiocarbamato Glycoconjugates as Potential Anticancer Agents: Design, Physico&#8208;Chemical Characterization, and In Vitro Biological Activity</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500447</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500447</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500447</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500421</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:20:03 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-26T12:20:03-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500421</guid>
         <title>Docking and Molecular Dynamics Simulation&#8208;Based Analysis of Advanced Small&#8208;Molecule Kinase Inhibitors Identified pre&#8208;let&#8208;7 miRNA Binders</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
An integrated computational approach evaluating the binding between pre&#8208;let&#8208;7 microRNA and small&#8208;molecule kinase inhibitors (SMKIs) revealed varied pre&#8208;let&#8208;7 binding affinities among the advanced SMKIs. The results justified the characterization of potential RNA targets for kinase inhibitors and small molecules with protein targets in general.

RNAs play crucial roles in various cellular actions, and the uncontrolled expression or improper folding of RNAs is a cause of many diseases. Certain oncogenic phenotypes stem from the overexpression of regulatory microRNAs that contain secondary structural elements. Thus, targeting disease&#8208;related microRNAs with small molecules is a potential therapeutic&#160;strategy that has attracted growing interest. To probe the RNA&#8208;binding chemical space held in advanced small&#8208;molecule therapeutics, in this work, we screened the 78 FDA&#8208;approved small&#8208;molecule kinase inhibitors (SMKIs) as representatives of the most advanced kinase inhibitors for their binding affinity with pre&#8208;let&#8208;7 miRNA via a combination of computational methods and biophysical measurement. The best&#8208;ranked SMKIs based on docking scores were subjected to molecular dynamics simulation studies, followed by analysis of different computational parameters. Collectively, it provided reliable information on the binding affinity for the top&#8208;performed SMKI in the formation of SMKI&#8211;miRNA complexes with pre&#8208;let&#8208;7. Furthermore, the identification of the predicted most promising SMKI&#8211;miRNA interactions was validated by microscale thermophoresis, measuring direct binding affinities. This study evaluating the binding landscapes of the 78 FDA&#8208;approved SMKIs with pre&#8208;let&#8208;7 miRNA served as an example highlighting the necessity to characterize the biological targets of SMKIs, many of which are FDA&#8208;approved cancer agents, at the transcriptomic level with RNAs. The study also illustrates the possibility that the interaction with RNA targets may contribute to the observed biological and clinical performance of these approved SMKIs.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/d43b962f-fe59-41cd-9ddd-51d43770fae6/cbic202500421-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Docking and Molecular Dynamics Simulation-Based Analysis of Advanced Small-Molecule Kinase Inhibitors Identified pre-let-7 miRNA Binders"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An integrated computational approach evaluating the binding between pre-&lt;i&gt;let&lt;/i&gt;-&lt;i&gt;7&lt;/i&gt; microRNA and small-molecule kinase inhibitors (SMKIs) revealed varied pre-&lt;i&gt;let&lt;/i&gt;-&lt;i&gt;7&lt;/i&gt; binding affinities among the advanced SMKIs. The results justified the characterization of potential RNA targets for kinase inhibitors and small molecules with protein targets in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNAs play crucial roles in various cellular actions, and the uncontrolled expression or improper folding of RNAs is a cause of many diseases. Certain oncogenic phenotypes stem from the overexpression of regulatory microRNAs that contain secondary structural elements. Thus, targeting disease-related microRNAs with small molecules is a potential therapeutic&#160;strategy that has attracted growing interest. To probe the RNA-binding chemical space held in advanced small-molecule therapeutics, in this work, we screened the 78 FDA-approved small-molecule kinase inhibitors (SMKIs) as representatives of the most advanced kinase inhibitors for their binding affinity with pre-&lt;i&gt;let-7&lt;/i&gt; miRNA via a combination of computational methods and biophysical measurement. The best-ranked SMKIs based on docking scores were subjected to molecular dynamics simulation studies, followed by analysis of different computational parameters. Collectively, it provided reliable information on the binding affinity for the top-performed SMKI in the formation of SMKI&#8211;miRNA complexes with pre-&lt;i&gt;let-7.&lt;/i&gt; Furthermore, the identification of the predicted most promising SMKI&#8211;miRNA interactions was validated by microscale thermophoresis, measuring direct binding affinities. This study evaluating the binding landscapes of the 78 FDA-approved SMKIs with pre-&lt;i&gt;let-7&lt;/i&gt; miRNA served as an example highlighting the necessity to characterize the biological targets of SMKIs, many of which are FDA-approved cancer agents, at the transcriptomic level with RNAs. The study also illustrates the possibility that the interaction with RNA targets may contribute to the observed biological and clinical performance of these approved SMKIs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Soma Roy, 
Yang Liu, 
Peng Wu
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Docking and Molecular Dynamics Simulation&#8208;Based Analysis of Advanced Small&#8208;Molecule Kinase Inhibitors Identified pre&#8208;let&#8208;7 miRNA Binders</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500421</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500421</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500421</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500318</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:45:11 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-14T01:45:11-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500318</guid>
         <title>Internal Ubiquitin Electrophiles for Covalent Trapping and Inhibition of Deubiquitinases</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
GA: Genetically encoded internal electrophiles in ubiquitin (Ub) enable the profiling of multivalent interaction interfaces, addressing a key limitation of current Ub&#8208;based activity&#8208;based probes. In this study, these probes capture a Ub&#8211;deubiquitinase interaction with minimal structural perturbation and serve as selective diUb probes that covalently target the catalytic cysteines of Met1&#8208;specific Dubs. 

The ubiquitin (Ub) system governs vital cellular processes in eukaryotic biology through an intricate network of Ub&#8211;protein interactions. While semisynthetic C&#8208;terminal Ub electrophiles (UbEs) are widely used to study Ub transfer and deubiquitinase (Dub) activity, they are limited to probing the active site while leaving other functionally important sites unexplored. Building on previously identified multivalent interaction interfaces and potential allosteric sites which are key to understanding their dynamic nature, here we report the development of genetically encoded Ub&#8208;based probes to covalently tether Ub&#8208;protein interactions in a proximity&#8208;driven manner at distal locations away from the active site. This study demonstrates that UbEs with internal electrophiles maintain conformational changes observed with their C&#8208;terminal counterparts while circumventing their limitations in capturing distal binding&#8208;site complexes, an emerging feature in Ub&#8208;mediated regulation. Genetically encoding these electrophiles further demonstrate rational variation as activity&#8208;based probes (ABP), leading to a Met1&#8208;diUb ABP showing preference for OTULIN over other Met1 cleaving Dubs. Taken together, our study introduces genetically encoded Ub&#8208;based probes to explore the structural and biochemical significance of Ub&#8208;Dub interactions beyond the canonical S1 site, overcoming some limitations of traditional Ub C&#8208;terminal electrophiles.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/122d24c2-a8e6-486b-b727-26a5fd5a4eb5/cbic202500318-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Internal Ubiquitin Electrophiles for Covalent Trapping and Inhibition of Deubiquitinases"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GA: Genetically encoded internal electrophiles in ubiquitin (Ub) enable the profiling of multivalent interaction interfaces, addressing a key limitation of current Ub-based activity-based probes. In this study, these probes capture a Ub&#8211;deubiquitinase interaction with minimal structural perturbation and serve as selective diUb probes that covalently target the catalytic cysteines of Met1-specific Dubs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ubiquitin (Ub) system governs vital cellular processes in eukaryotic biology through an intricate network of Ub&#8211;protein interactions. While semisynthetic C-terminal Ub electrophiles (UbEs) are widely used to study Ub transfer and deubiquitinase (Dub) activity, they are limited to probing the active site while leaving other functionally important sites unexplored. Building on previously identified multivalent interaction interfaces and potential allosteric sites which are key to understanding their dynamic nature, here we report the development of genetically encoded Ub-based probes to covalently tether Ub-protein interactions in a proximity-driven manner at distal locations away from the active site. This study demonstrates that UbEs with internal electrophiles maintain conformational changes observed with their C-terminal counterparts while circumventing their limitations in capturing distal binding-site complexes, an emerging feature in Ub-mediated regulation. Genetically encoding these electrophiles further demonstrate rational variation as activity-based probes (ABP), leading to a Met1-diUb ABP showing preference for OTULIN over other Met1 cleaving Dubs. Taken together, our study introduces genetically encoded Ub-based probes to explore the structural and biochemical significance of Ub-Dub interactions beyond the canonical S1 site, overcoming some limitations of traditional Ub C-terminal electrophiles.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Nipuni M. Pannala, 
Rishi S. Patel, 
Abhijith Saseendran Anit, 
Debapriya Bhattacharya, 
Kristos Negron Teron, 
Bryon Drown, 
Rudi Fasan, 
Chittaranjan Das
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Internal Ubiquitin Electrophiles for Covalent Trapping and Inhibition of Deubiquitinases</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500318</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500318</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500318</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500237</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:44:37 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-14T01:44:37-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500237</guid>
         <title>Adding A C&#8208;Terminal Amino Acid Prevents the Conformational Interconversion of Plecantide Analogs</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Bicyclic Peptide Conformational Locks: Plecanatide, an FDA&#8208;endorsed therapy for chronic idiopathic constipation and irritable bowel syndrome with constipation, faces stability challenges in acidic environments. The innovative approach involved appending a functional amino acid to the C&#8208;termini, transforming plecanatide into highly stable isomers that retained or enhanced their GC&#8208;C agonistic activity.

The principle of structure dictating properties is illustrated by the direct correlation between cyclic peptide conformation and their biological efficacy. Plecanatide, a synthetic analog of uroguanylin, has received FDA approval for the treatment of chronic idiopathic constipation and irritable bowel syndrome with constipation. Nevertheless, our investigation has revealed that plecanatide undergoes slow conformational interconversion in slightly acidic conditions. In response, propargylglycine is strategically incorporated at the carboxyl terminal of plecanatide, a modification that not only facilitates additional functionalization and derivatizationbut also confers exceptional conformational stability. Remarkably, the resulting isomers not only maintained long&#8208;term conformational stability but also exhibited either preserved or slightly enhanced agonistic activity. This discovery represents a contribution to drug research focused on plecanatide, particularly in elucidating the relationship between its conformational properties and biological activity.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/d87d287a-1711-48c3-8abc-ca58152d2c0d/cbic202500237-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Adding A C-Terminal Amino Acid Prevents the Conformational Interconversion of Plecantide Analogs"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bicyclic Peptide Conformational Locks: Plecanatide, an FDA-endorsed therapy for chronic idiopathic constipation and irritable bowel syndrome with constipation, faces stability challenges in acidic environments. The innovative approach involved appending a functional amino acid to the C-termini, transforming plecanatide into highly stable isomers that retained or enhanced their GC-C agonistic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle of structure dictating properties is illustrated by the direct correlation between cyclic peptide conformation and their biological efficacy. Plecanatide, a synthetic analog of uroguanylin, has received FDA approval for the treatment of chronic idiopathic constipation and irritable bowel syndrome with constipation. Nevertheless, our investigation has revealed that plecanatide undergoes slow conformational interconversion in slightly acidic conditions. In response, propargylglycine is strategically incorporated at the carboxyl terminal of plecanatide, a modification that not only facilitates additional functionalization and derivatizationbut also confers exceptional conformational stability. Remarkably, the resulting isomers not only maintained long-term conformational stability but also exhibited either preserved or slightly enhanced agonistic activity. This discovery represents a contribution to drug research focused on plecanatide, particularly in elucidating the relationship between its conformational properties and biological activity.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yi Zhou, 
Jingyan Jin, 
Pingzheng Zhou, 
Wu Su, 
Guiyang Yao
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Adding A C&#8208;Terminal Amino Acid Prevents the Conformational Interconversion of Plecantide Analogs</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500237</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500237</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500237</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500357</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 12:13:36 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-08-13T12:13:36-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500357</guid>
         <title>Precision Delivery of CRISPR/Cas Systems via DNA Nanostructures for Gene Therapy and Intracellular Detection</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
The emergence of gene editing technology has catalyzed a paradigm shift in life science research, with the CRISPR/Cas system emerging as a cornerstone tool in modern biology due to its transformative capabilities. This review systematically examines current delivery modalities for CRISPR/Cas systems (Cas9, Cas12, Cas13), with particular emphasis on the implementation of DNA&#8208;based functional materials as advanced delivery vehicles.

The CRISPR/Cas system represents a transformative breakthrough in genome editing technology, featuring three principal effector proteins with distinct functionalities: Cas9, which induces site&#8208;specific double&#8208;strand breaks guided by a single guide RNA, enabling precise gene knockout and knock&#8208;in modifications; Cas12, which mediates targeted DNA cleavage through cis&#8208;activity while exhibiting nonspecific trans&#8208;cleavage of single&#8208;stranded DNA, a property exploited for ultrasensitive nucleic acid detection in molecular diagnostics; and Cas13, an RNA&#8208;guided RNase that specifically degrades complementary RNA transcripts, demonstrating significant potential for antiviral therapies and transcriptome regulation. Despite these advances, the clinical translation of CRISPR/Cas systems faces substantial challenges, particularly in achieving efficient and controllable delivery. This reviewsystematically examines current delivery modalities for CRISPR/Cas systems, with particular emphasis on the implementation of DNA&#8208;based functional materials as advanced delivery vehicles. The integration of multifunctional DNA nanostructures with diverse CRISPR/Cas systems may facilitate the development of integrated theranostic platforms, thereby advancing precision medicine through synergistic bioengineering approaches.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/82b0560f-6991-4039-851a-6aed0a2b27b1/cbic202500357-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Precision Delivery of CRISPR/Cas Systems via DNA Nanostructures for Gene Therapy and Intracellular Detection"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of gene editing technology has catalyzed a paradigm shift in life science research, with the CRISPR/Cas system emerging as a cornerstone tool in modern biology due to its transformative capabilities. This review systematically examines current delivery modalities for CRISPR/Cas systems (Cas9, Cas12, Cas13), with particular emphasis on the implementation of DNA-based functional materials as advanced delivery vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRISPR/Cas system represents a transformative breakthrough in genome editing technology, featuring three principal effector proteins with distinct functionalities: Cas9, which induces site-specific double-strand breaks guided by a single guide RNA, enabling precise gene knockout and knock-in modifications; Cas12, which mediates targeted DNA cleavage through cis-activity while exhibiting nonspecific trans-cleavage of single-stranded DNA, a property exploited for ultrasensitive nucleic acid detection in molecular diagnostics; and Cas13, an RNA-guided RNase that specifically degrades complementary RNA transcripts, demonstrating significant potential for antiviral therapies and transcriptome regulation. Despite these advances, the clinical translation of CRISPR/Cas systems faces substantial challenges, particularly in achieving efficient and controllable delivery. This reviewsystematically examines current delivery modalities for CRISPR/Cas systems, with particular emphasis on the implementation of DNA-based functional materials as advanced delivery vehicles. The integration of multifunctional DNA nanostructures with diverse CRISPR/Cas systems may facilitate the development of integrated theranostic platforms, thereby advancing precision medicine through synergistic bioengineering approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Nachuan Song, 
Lijun Wang, 
Le Zhang, 
Gengqi Tian, 
Chi Yao, 
Dayong Yang
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Precision Delivery of CRISPR/Cas Systems via DNA Nanostructures for Gene Therapy and Intracellular Detection</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500357</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500357</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500357</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500323</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 02:47:59 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-29T02:47:59-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500323</guid>
         <title>Regulation of Gene Expression of Mouse D&#8208;Amino Acid Oxidase</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
The front cover illustration shows the transcriptional regulation of the mouse D&#8208;amino acid oxidase (DAO) gene. Key TFs act on the core promoter to stimulate DAO expression, leading to D&#8208;serine metabolism and influencing neurotransmission. This reflects the study's discovery of conserved regulatory elements in DAO gene control.

D&#8208;amino acid oxidase (DAO) catalyzes oxidative deamination of D&#8208;amino acids, producing 2&#8208;oxo acids, hydrogen peroxide, and ammonia. In mammals, DAO is essential for metabolizing both endogenous and exogenous D&#8208;amino acids. Previous studies on human DAO identify two promoter regions (P1 and P2), a negative regulatory element in intron 1, and several transcription factor (TF) binding sites. In this study, the regulatory mechanism of mouse DAO gene expression is investigated to compare with the human system. To determine the promoter activity in the upstream region of the initiation site, plasmids containing mouse DAO gene fragments inserted into the pGL4 [luc2P/Hygro] vector and assessed luciferase activity in LLC&#8208;PK1 cells are constructed. A series of deletion constructs is analyzed, revealing promoter activity in all tested fragments. The highest promoter activity is detected in the &#8722;333/&#8722;87 subregion, with residual activities in the &#8722;87/&#8201;+&#8201;111 region. Bioinformatics analysis identifies TFs, including NEUR, EGRF, ZF07, ZF11, KLFS, SP1F, and ZF02, which bind to both the human and mouse DAO genes at conserved positions, suggesting their critical role in regulating DAO promoter activity.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/18c814cd-b78b-4c3b-92e3-cec9a182f1d7/cbic202500323-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Regulation of Gene Expression of Mouse D-Amino Acid Oxidase"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front cover illustration shows the transcriptional regulation of the mouse D-amino acid oxidase (&lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt;) gene. Key TFs act on the core promoter to stimulate &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; expression, leading to D-serine metabolism and influencing neurotransmission. This reflects the study's discovery of conserved regulatory elements in &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; gene control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D-amino acid oxidase (&lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt;) catalyzes oxidative deamination of D-amino acids, producing 2-oxo acids, hydrogen peroxide, and ammonia. In mammals, &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; is essential for metabolizing both endogenous and exogenous D-amino acids. Previous studies on human &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; identify two promoter regions (P1 and P2), a negative regulatory element in intron 1, and several transcription factor (TF) binding sites. In this study, the regulatory mechanism of mouse &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; gene expression is investigated to compare with the human system. To determine the promoter activity in the upstream region of the initiation site, plasmids containing mouse &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; gene fragments inserted into the pGL4 [luc2P/Hygro] vector and assessed luciferase activity in LLC-PK1 cells are constructed. A series of deletion constructs is analyzed, revealing promoter activity in all tested fragments. The highest promoter activity is detected in the &#8722;333/&#8722;87 subregion, with residual activities in the &#8722;87/&#8201;+&#8201;111 region. Bioinformatics analysis identifies TFs, including NEUR, EGRF, ZF07, ZF11, KLFS, SP1F, and ZF02, which bind to both the human and mouse &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; genes at conserved positions, suggesting their critical role in regulating &lt;i&gt;DAO&lt;/i&gt; promoter activity.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Huong Thi Thanh Trinh, 
Yuji Shishido, 
Nam Hoang Tran, 
Diem Hong Tran, 
Soo Hyeon Kim, 
Hirofumi Sogabe, 
Kiyoshi Fukui
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Regulation of Gene Expression of Mouse D&#8208;Amino Acid Oxidase</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500323</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500323</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500323</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500330</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 02:29:14 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-24T02:29:14-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500330</guid>
         <title>Dominant&#8208;Negative Effects of p53 R337 Variants in Li&#8211;Fraumeni Syndrome: Impact on Tetramer Formation and Transcriptional Activity</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Hetero&#8208;tetramer dysfunction: Li&#8211;Fraumeni syndrome (LFS) is a hereditary cancer predisposition caused by mutations in the TP53 gene encoding the tumor suppressor p53. It is shown that p53 variants R337C and R337H, found in LFS, impair wild&#8208;type (WT) p53 function by forming heterotetramers with reduced transcriptional activity. This dominant&#8208;negative&#8208;like effect may explain tissue&#8208;specific tumor susceptibility in LFS.

Li&#8211;Fraumeni syndrome (LFS) is an inherited cancer predisposition disorder caused by heterozygous TP53 mutations. Among these, missense mutations at Arg337&#8212;such as R337C and R337H&#8212;are common in LFS patients. Although many studies have characterized individual p53 variants in LFS, the impact of tetramerization domain (TD) mutations on wild&#8208;type (WT) p53 function remains unclear. Herein, a novel FRET&#8208;based assay system that enables the simultaneous detection of heterotetramer formation and p53&#8208;dependent transcriptional activity in live cells is developed. These results show that the heteromultimerization of the R337C variant with WT p53 is only slightly reduced compared to WT homotetramers, yet its transcriptional activity is diminished by over 50%. In contrast, the R337H variant forms heterotetramers at near&#8208;normal levels but exhibits markedly compromised transcriptional activity. These findings reveal a previously unrecognized dominant&#8208;negative&#8208;like effect, suggesting reduced p53 function is due not only to decreased tetramer formation but also to diminished heterotetramer stability. Moreover, the LFS&#8208;associated p53TD variants show a greater loss of activity against the low&#8208;affinity, apoptosis&#8208;inducing bax response element than against the high&#8208;affinity, cell cycle arrest&#8208;related CDKN1A response element. Collectively, this study demonstrates that p53TD mutations can exert dominant&#8208;negative effects, advancing the understanding of p53 heteromultimer function in LFS pathogenesis. These mechanistic insights into p53 heterotetramer stability may not only inform genetic screening strategies for LFS but also support future therapeutic approaches aimed at restoring p53 function by stabilizing mutant tetramers.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2ba49b38-430d-4479-b13f-6f1e81552b73/cbic70002-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Dominant-Negative Effects of p53 R337 Variants in Li&#8211;Fraumeni Syndrome: Impact on Tetramer Formation and Transcriptional Activity"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hetero-tetramer dysfunction:&lt;/i&gt; Li&#8211;Fraumeni syndrome (LFS) is a hereditary cancer predisposition caused by mutations in the &lt;i&gt;TP53&lt;/i&gt; gene encoding the tumor suppressor p53. It is shown that p53 variants R337C and R337H, found in LFS, impair wild-type (WT) p53 function by forming heterotetramers with reduced transcriptional activity. This dominant-negative-like effect may explain tissue-specific tumor susceptibility in LFS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li&#8211;Fraumeni syndrome (LFS) is an inherited cancer predisposition disorder caused by heterozygous &lt;i&gt;TP53&lt;/i&gt; mutations. Among these, missense mutations at Arg337&#8212;such as R337C and R337H&#8212;are common in LFS patients. Although many studies have characterized individual p53 variants in LFS, the impact of tetramerization domain (TD) mutations on wild-type (WT) p53 function remains unclear. Herein, a novel FRET-based assay system that enables the simultaneous detection of heterotetramer formation and p53-dependent transcriptional activity in live cells is developed. These results show that the heteromultimerization of the R337C variant with WT p53 is only slightly reduced compared to WT homotetramers, yet its transcriptional activity is diminished by over 50%. In contrast, the R337H variant forms heterotetramers at near-normal levels but exhibits markedly compromised transcriptional activity. These findings reveal a previously unrecognized dominant-negative-like effect, suggesting reduced p53 function is due not only to decreased tetramer formation but also to diminished heterotetramer stability. Moreover, the LFS-associated p53TD variants show a greater loss of activity against the low-affinity, apoptosis-inducing &lt;i&gt;bax&lt;/i&gt; response element than against the high-affinity, cell cycle arrest-related &lt;i&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/i&gt; response element. Collectively, this study demonstrates that p53TD mutations can exert dominant-negative effects, advancing the understanding of p53 heteromultimer function in LFS pathogenesis. These mechanistic insights into p53 heterotetramer stability may not only inform genetic screening strategies for LFS but also support future therapeutic approaches aimed at restoring p53 function by stabilizing mutant tetramers.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Rui Kamada, 
Shuya Sakaguchi, 
Madoka Kanno, 
Takaaki Ozawa, 
Natsumi Nakagawa, 
James G. Omichinski, 
Kazuyasu Sakaguchi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Dominant&#8208;Negative Effects of p53 R337 Variants in Li&#8211;Fraumeni Syndrome: Impact on Tetramer Formation and Transcriptional Activity</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500330</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500330</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500330</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500403</link>
         <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 03:58:48 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-21T03:58:48-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500403</guid>
         <title>Chemically Synthesized LRAD3&#8208;D1 Interacts with N&#8208;Terminal Domain of SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 Spike Protein</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Chemical synthesis, calcium&#8208;templated in&#8208;vitro folding and competitive ELISA assay reveal that only domain 1 of the LRAD3 ectodomain interacts with the severe acute respiratory syndrome&#8208;related corona virus 2 (SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2) spike NTD, while domains 2 and 3 do not, providing valuable insight into ACE2&#8208;independent viral entry pathways that may contribute to the development of new therapeutic approaches targeting SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 strains associated with severe neurological complications.

Growing evidence of post&#8208;COVID neurological complications, such as encephalopathy, neurodegeneration, and cognitive impairment, suggests severe acute respiratory syndrome&#8208;related corona virus 2 (SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2) viral infection into the central nervous system (CNS). Therefore, understanding the mechanisms of viral entry into the CNS, where human angiotensin&#8208;converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) is barely expressed, is critical for addressing the neurological consequences of COVID&#8208;19. Importantly, the low&#8208;density lipoprotein receptor class A domain containing 3 (LRAD3) is overexpressed in brain cells, suggesting a possible ACE2&#8208;independent alternate pathway of viral entry into brain cells. Herein, the interaction of the chemically synthesized LRAD3 domains with SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 spike protein is reported. It is observed that the extracellular domains of LRAD3 depend on calcium for proper folding and maintaining their structural integrity. The results reveal that domain 1 of LRAD3, which is most accessible from the cell surface, engages with the N&#8208;terminal domain of the viral spike protein. These findings open up possibilities to develop new therapeutic strategies targeting ACE2 independent viral entry pathways.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/c6f1d4c8-90ef-4f25-917e-7dfa6c30ca83/cbic202500403-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Chemically Synthesized LRAD3-D1 Interacts with N-Terminal Domain of SARS-CoV-2 Spike Protein"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemical synthesis, calcium-templated in-vitro folding and competitive ELISA assay reveal that only domain 1 of the LRAD3 ectodomain interacts with the severe acute respiratory syndrome-related corona virus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) spike NTD, while domains 2 and 3 do not, providing valuable insight into ACE2-independent viral entry pathways that may contribute to the development of new therapeutic approaches targeting SARS-CoV-2 strains associated with severe neurological complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing evidence of post-COVID neurological complications, such as encephalopathy, neurodegeneration, and cognitive impairment, suggests severe acute respiratory syndrome-related corona virus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) viral infection into the central nervous system (CNS). Therefore, understanding the mechanisms of viral entry into the CNS, where human angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) is barely expressed, is critical for addressing the neurological consequences of COVID-19. Importantly, the low-density lipoprotein receptor class A domain containing 3 (LRAD3) is overexpressed in brain cells, suggesting a possible ACE2-independent alternate pathway of viral entry into brain cells. Herein, the interaction of the chemically synthesized LRAD3 domains with SARS-CoV-2 spike protein is reported. It is observed that the extracellular domains of LRAD3 depend on calcium for proper folding and maintaining their structural integrity. The results reveal that domain 1 of LRAD3, which is most accessible from the cell surface, engages with the N-terminal domain of the viral spike protein. These findings open up possibilities to develop new therapeutic strategies targeting ACE2 independent viral entry pathways.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Mrinmoy Jana, 
Rathina Delipan, 
Arighna Sarkar, 
Sreejith Raran&#8208;Kurussi, 
Rajesh P. Ringe, 
Kalyaneswar Mandal
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Chemically Synthesized LRAD3&#8208;D1 Interacts with N&#8208;Terminal Domain of SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 Spike Protein</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500403</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500403</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500403</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500258</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 05:55:26 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-09T05:55:26-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500258</guid>
         <title>Poly(ethylene Glycol)&#8208;Based Peptidomimetics (Pegtides) of Antimicrobial Peptides</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
Polyethylene glycol (PEG) is commonly used to improve the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of therapeutic candidates by conjugation. Here PEG is exploited for peptidomimetic conversion of antimicrobial peptides (AMPs), as candidate antibacterial agents, by replacing their polyamide backbone. The pegtides obtained thereby can be readily synthesized from inexpensive starting materials and demonstrate properties commensurate of AMP mimetics.

Cationic amphipathic poly(ethylene glycol)&#8208;based polymers are generated with synthetic efficiencies allowing their evaluation as antimicrobial peptide (AMP) mimetics. Accordingly, statistical copolymers with cationic units consistently functionalized with guanyl groups, but different side&#8208;chain lengths, and hydrophobic units displaying long aliphatic, branched, and/or aromatic side chains are produced and tested for their antimicrobial and hemolytic properties. The results obtained indicate that candidates with activities and selectivity commensurate to some AMPs can be obtained and that further development of this novel type of antimicrobial peptidomimetics, pegtides, is warranted for clinical and/or biotechnological applications.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/71eabbc6-aa75-40da-84f5-82359bfd40c1/cbic202500258-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Poly(ethylene Glycol)-Based Peptidomimetics (Pegtides) of Antimicrobial Peptides"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polyethylene glycol (PEG) is commonly used to improve the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of therapeutic candidates by conjugation. Here PEG is exploited for peptidomimetic conversion of antimicrobial peptides (AMPs), as candidate antibacterial agents, by replacing their polyamide backbone. The pegtides obtained thereby can be readily synthesized from inexpensive starting materials and demonstrate properties commensurate of AMP mimetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cationic amphipathic poly(ethylene glycol)-based polymers are generated with synthetic efficiencies allowing their evaluation as antimicrobial peptide (AMP) mimetics. Accordingly, statistical copolymers with cationic units consistently functionalized with guanyl groups, but different side-chain lengths, and hydrophobic units displaying long aliphatic, branched, and/or aromatic side chains are produced and tested for their antimicrobial and hemolytic properties. The results obtained indicate that candidates with activities and selectivity commensurate to some AMPs can be obtained and that further development of this novel type of antimicrobial peptidomimetics, pegtides, is warranted for clinical and/or biotechnological applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Conor Shine, 
John R. F. B. Connolly, 
Robert D. Murphy, 
Hazel Lafferty, 
Abdalmalek Alfnikh, 
Ned P. Buijs, 
Hawraa Shahrour, 
Nathaniel I. Martin, 
Eoghan O'Neill, 
George Amarandei, 
Jimmy Muldoon, 
Marc Maresca, 
Deirdre Fitzgerald&#8208;Hughes, 
Marc Devocelle
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Poly(ethylene Glycol)&#8208;Based Peptidomimetics (Pegtides) of Antimicrobial Peptides</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500258</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500258</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500258</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500353</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-08T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500353</guid>
         <title>Developing FGF2 Mutants with Selectively Reduced Heparan Sulfate Affinity to Explore Their Impact on FGFR1 Signaling</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Fibroblast growth factor 2 (FGF2) regulates signal transduction by forming complexes with its receptors, FGF receptors (FGFRs), and heparan sulfate (HS), playing a crucial role in biological systems. Although HS has been suggested to modulate FGF/FGFR signaling as a co&#8208;receptor, multiple hypotheses exist regarding how HS affects FGF/FGFR signaling, and the mechanism remains unclear. In this study, to highlight the role of FGF2/HS interaction in FGF2/FGFR1 signaling, FGF2 mutants with reduced HS&#8208;binding affinity were rationally designed through&#160;in silico&#160;analysis. These FGF2 mutants exhibited reduced HS affinity by more than two orders of magnitude while maintaining binding affinity to FGFR1. In addition, these mutants retained their thermal stability. Cellular assays using the FGF2 mutant suggested that, contrary to previous reports, the contribution of the FGF2/HS interaction in FGF2/FGFR1 signaling may be limited. The mutant FGFs that specifically alter the interaction with HS, achieved in this study, would contribute to an understanding of the role of FGF/HS interaction in FGF/FGFR signaling.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Fibroblast growth factor 2 (FGF2) regulates signal transduction by forming complexes with its receptors, FGF receptors (FGFRs), and heparan sulfate (HS), playing a crucial role in biological systems. Although HS has been suggested to modulate FGF/FGFR signaling as a co-receptor, multiple hypotheses exist regarding how HS affects FGF/FGFR signaling, and the mechanism remains unclear. In this study, to highlight the role of FGF2/HS interaction in FGF2/FGFR1 signaling, FGF2 mutants with reduced HS-binding affinity were rationally designed through&#160;in silico&#160;analysis. These FGF2 mutants exhibited reduced HS affinity by more than two orders of magnitude while maintaining binding affinity to FGFR1. In addition, these mutants retained their thermal stability. Cellular assays using the FGF2 mutant suggested that, contrary to previous reports, the contribution of the FGF2/HS interaction in FGF2/FGFR1 signaling may be limited. The mutant FGFs that specifically alter the interaction with HS, achieved in this study, would contribute to an understanding of the role of FGF/HS interaction in FGF/FGFR signaling.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yuga Okada, 
Akihiro Eguchi, 
Daisuke Kuroda, 
Kouhei Tsumoto, 
Ryosuke Ueki, 
Shinsuke Sando
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Developing FGF2 Mutants with Selectively Reduced Heparan Sulfate Affinity to Explore Their Impact on FGFR1 Signaling</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500353</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500353</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500353</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500304</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-08T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500304</guid>
         <title>Design and Characterization of Prodrugged Anti&#8208;CTLA&#8208;4 Antibodies</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Therapeutic antibodies are widely used to treat diseases like cancer and inflammatory conditions by binding with high specificity to their molecular targets. Masking is a strategy to mitigate undesirable activity in non&#8208;target tissues, improving safety and pharmacokinetic (PK) profiles by reducing target&#8208;mediated drug disposition (TMDD). In this study, we explored masking an anti&#8208;CTLA&#8208;4 antibody by conjugating a large PEG molecule to specific sites on the antibody. While anti&#8208;CTLA&#8208;4 immunotherapy benefits solid tumor treatment, its adverse events limit its utility. We evaluated multiple conjugation sites within the complementarity&#8208;determining regions (CDRs) and adjacent framework regions to attenuate CTLA&#8208;4 binding. We identified the optimal site for maximizing masking efficiency, allowing for efficient bioconjugation and functional restoration upon exposure to a cleaving enzyme in the tumor microenvironment. The prodrugged antibody exhibited reduced binding to CTLA&#8208;4 and Fc gamma receptors (FcgRs), high stability, and an extended half&#8208;life in a mouse model. This technology has the potential to improve the PK profile and safety attributes of therapeutic antibodies.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Therapeutic antibodies are widely used to treat diseases like cancer and inflammatory conditions by binding with high specificity to their molecular targets. Masking is a strategy to mitigate undesirable activity in non-target tissues, improving safety and pharmacokinetic (PK) profiles by reducing target-mediated drug disposition (TMDD). In this study, we explored masking an anti-CTLA-4 antibody by conjugating a large PEG molecule to specific sites on the antibody. While anti-CTLA-4 immunotherapy benefits solid tumor treatment, its adverse events limit its utility. We evaluated multiple conjugation sites within the complementarity-determining regions (CDRs) and adjacent framework regions to attenuate CTLA-4 binding. We identified the optimal site for maximizing masking efficiency, allowing for efficient bioconjugation and functional restoration upon exposure to a cleaving enzyme in the tumor microenvironment. The prodrugged antibody exhibited reduced binding to CTLA-4 and Fc gamma receptors (FcgRs), high stability, and an extended half-life in a mouse model. This technology has the potential to improve the PK profile and safety attributes of therapeutic antibodies.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Sayumi Yamazoe, 
Mary Huber, 
Srikanth Kotapati, 
Rahima Akter, 
Aarti Jashnani, 
Suprit Deol, 
Christine Bee, 
John Engelhart, 
Yam  B Poudel, 
Stanley Krystek, 
Mohan Srinivasan, 
Arvind Rajpal, 
Yong Zhang, 
Pavel Strop, 
Chetana Rao, 
John Haugner
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Design and Characterization of Prodrugged Anti&#8208;CTLA&#8208;4 Antibodies</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500304</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500304</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500304</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500268</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 05:34:51 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-07-03T05:34:51-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500268</guid>
         <title>Covalent Stabilization of Collagen Mimetic Triple Helices and Assemblies by Dopa Crosslinking</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Creating thermally stable collagen mimetic peptides (CMPs) is a persistent challenge. Nature leverages covalent crosslinkings to stabilize collagen's triple helix&#160;and higher&#8208;order assemblies. Herein, we demonstrate that crosslinkings between levodopa (Dopa) and lysine can covalently stabilize the triple helix in collagen mimetic peptides. Since alkaline conditions catalyze the oxidation of the catechol on Dopa to a benzoquinone, while being in proximity to the nucleophilic lysine, we hypothesized that this reaction could be a facile method to covalently capture the supramolecular structure of CMPs by simply increasing the pH of the aqueous solvent with the addition of sodium hydroxide. This strategy covalently stabilizes CMP homotrimers and a de novo designed ABC&#8208;type heterotrimer demonstrating that the Lysine&#8208;Dopa covalent bond is best templated by a supramolecular, axial cation&#8208;&#960; pairwise interaction. In nature, collagen can hierarchically assemble into fibers. This behavior can be mimicked with the self&#8208;assembly of CMPs, but the resulting nanofibers typically exhibit thermal stability below body temperature. In a final application, we demonstrate that Dopa&#8208;Lysine covalent capture also enhances the thermal stability of CMP nanofibers well above 37 &#176;C. This biomimetic covalent capture strategy can stabilize a wide variety of CMP systems and potentially enable the biomedical application of these materials.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Creating thermally stable collagen mimetic peptides (CMPs) is a persistent challenge. Nature leverages covalent crosslinkings to stabilize collagen's triple helix&#160;and higher-order assemblies. Herein, we demonstrate that crosslinkings between levodopa (Dopa) and lysine can covalently stabilize the triple helix in collagen mimetic peptides. Since alkaline conditions catalyze the oxidation of the catechol on Dopa to a benzoquinone, while being in proximity to the nucleophilic lysine, we hypothesized that this reaction could be a facile method to covalently capture the supramolecular structure of CMPs by simply increasing the pH of the aqueous solvent with the addition of sodium hydroxide. This strategy covalently stabilizes CMP homotrimers and a de novo designed ABC-type heterotrimer demonstrating that the Lysine-Dopa covalent bond is best templated by a supramolecular, axial cation-&#960; pairwise interaction. In nature, collagen can hierarchically assemble into fibers. This behavior can be mimicked with the self-assembly of CMPs, but the resulting nanofibers typically exhibit thermal stability below body temperature. In a final application, we demonstrate that Dopa-Lysine covalent capture also enhances the thermal stability of CMP nanofibers well above 37 &#176;C. This biomimetic covalent capture strategy can stabilize a wide variety of CMP systems and potentially enable the biomedical application of these materials.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Carson Cole, 
Brett  H. Pogostin, 
Vardan  H. Vardanyan, 
Kiana  A. Cahue, 
Thi  H. Bui, 
Adam  C Farsheed, 
Joseph  W.R. Swain, 
Jonathan Makhoul, 
Marija Dubackic, 
Peter Holmqvist, 
Ulf Olsson, 
Anatoly  B. Kolomeisky, 
Kevin  J. McHugh, 
Jeffrey  Dale Hartgerink
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Covalent Stabilization of Collagen Mimetic Triple Helices and Assemblies by Dopa Crosslinking</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500268</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500268</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500268</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500276</link>
         <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 10:14:15 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-06-30T10:14:15-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500276</guid>
         <title>Recent Advances in the Photochemical Biology of Serotonin</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, EarlyView. </description>
         <dc:description>
The neurotransmitter serotonin influences a wide range of behaviors and biological processes through a series of serotonin receptors and transporters. Recent photochemical tools have made it possible to follow this complicated web of interactions with ever improving spatial and temporal resolution.

Serotonin (5&#8208;HT) is an endogenous neurotransmitter that plays a key role in cellular signaling. Its interactions with serotonin receptors (5&#8208;HTRs) and the serotonin transporter (SERT) influence processes as disparate as hunger, happiness, healing, and headaches. Over the last several decades, photochemical tools have been developed to observe, track, and modulate these serotonin&#8211;protein interactions. The tools tend to fit into one of four categories: photoswitches, photocages, photobiosensors, or photocross&#8208;linkers. This review examines the development and application of these photochemical tools for 5&#8208;HT, 5&#8208;HTRs, and SERT over the last &#8776;10&#8201;years, with an emphasis on the chemistry involved.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/f1bb5120-4009-4fe5-a600-b559eb009a47/cbic202500276-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Recent Advances in the Photochemical Biology of Serotonin"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neurotransmitter serotonin influences a wide range of behaviors and biological processes through a series of serotonin receptors and transporters. Recent photochemical tools have made it possible to follow this complicated web of interactions with ever improving spatial and temporal resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serotonin (5-HT) is an endogenous neurotransmitter that plays a key role in cellular signaling. Its interactions with serotonin receptors (5-HTRs) and the serotonin transporter (SERT) influence processes as disparate as hunger, happiness, healing, and headaches. Over the last several decades, photochemical tools have been developed to observe, track, and modulate these serotonin&#8211;protein interactions. The tools tend to fit into one of four categories: photoswitches, photocages, photobiosensors, or photocross-linkers. This review examines the development and application of these photochemical tools for 5-HT, 5-HTRs, and SERT over the last &#8776;10&#8201;years, with an emphasis on the chemistry involved.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Claire E. Nieder, 
Michael A. Kienzler
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Recent Advances in the Photochemical Biology of Serotonin</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500276</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500276</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500276</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202400439</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-06-26T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202400439</guid>
         <title>5&#8208;thiohistidine N&#8208;acetyltransferase from Proteiniphilum saccharofermentans</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Ovothiol A is a 5&#8208;thiohistidine derivative biosynthesized by a broad range of prokaryotic and eukaryotic organisms. Its redox&#8208;active mercaptoimidazole side chain is believed to protect cells from oxidative stress. The three enzymes that produce ovothiol A from histidine, cysteine, and&#160;S&#8208;adenosyl methionine have been identified and characterized. In contrast, no enzymes are known that produce other 5&#8208;thiohistidine derivatives. Here, we describe a small family of acetyl&#8208;coenzyme A&#8208;dependent transferases that produce&#160;N&#8208;acetyl&#8208;5&#8208;thiohistidine. The discovery of these enzymes from&#160;Proteiniphilum saccharofermentans&#160;and related Bacteroidota provides evidence that the 5&#8208;thiohistidine class may be structurally and functionally more diverse than previously thought.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Ovothiol A is a 5-thiohistidine derivative biosynthesized by a broad range of prokaryotic and eukaryotic organisms. Its redox-active mercaptoimidazole side chain is believed to protect cells from oxidative stress. The three enzymes that produce ovothiol A from histidine, cysteine, and&#160;S-adenosyl methionine have been identified and characterized. In contrast, no enzymes are known that produce other 5-thiohistidine derivatives. Here, we describe a small family of acetyl-coenzyme A-dependent transferases that produce&#160;N-acetyl-5-thiohistidine. The discovery of these enzymes from&#160;Proteiniphilum saccharofermentans&#160;and related Bacteroidota provides evidence that the 5-thiohistidine class may be structurally and functionally more diverse than previously thought.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Cangsong Liao, 
David Lim, 
Gladwin Suryatin Alim, 
Florian  P. Seebeck
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>5&#8208;thiohistidine N&#8208;acetyltransferase from Proteiniphilum saccharofermentans</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202400439</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202400439</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202400439</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500384</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-06-18T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500384</guid>
         <title>Bioactivity profiles of progressively ring&#8208;fluorinated cyclohexyl motifs in the WKYMVm peptide as formylpeptide FPR2 agonists and in keto&#8208;piperazines as anti&#8208;trypanosome agents.</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>A series of all&#8208;cis ring fluorinated cyclohexylalanines with progressively increasing levels of vicinal fluorines, as well as 4&#8208;fluorophenylalanine and pentafluoroarylphenylalanine were introduced into the WKYMVm peptide in place of its tyrosine residue, for assays against the G&#8208;protein coupled formylpeptide receptor, FPR2. Selected all&#8208;cis ring cyclohexylalanines of this class were also incorporated into a keto&#8208;piperazine molecular scaffold to generate sp3 rich derivatives for assays against the parasite Trypanosoma. brucei. For these cyclohexylalanine analogues bioactivity trends correlated progressively with the levels of fluorination in each of the case studies. Notably, the all&#8208;cis pentafluorocyclohexylalanine analogue of the W&#8208;peptide was least active perhaps correlating with the well&#8208;known polarity of this &#8216;Janus face&#8217; cyclohexane. Although the trend was also apparent in the anti&#8208;trypanosomal assays of the keto&#8208;piperazine derivatives, it was less so and some compounds were more active than the previously reported phenylalanine derived analogue.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A series of all-cis ring fluorinated cyclohexylalanines with progressively increasing levels of vicinal fluorines, as well as 4-fluorophenylalanine and pentafluoroarylphenylalanine were introduced into the WKYMVm peptide in place of its tyrosine residue, for assays against the G-protein coupled formylpeptide receptor, FPR2. Selected all-cis ring cyclohexylalanines of this class were also incorporated into a keto-piperazine molecular scaffold to generate sp3 rich derivatives for assays against the parasite Trypanosoma. brucei. For these cyclohexylalanine analogues bioactivity trends correlated progressively with the levels of fluorination in each of the case studies. Notably, the all-cis pentafluorocyclohexylalanine analogue of the W-peptide was least active perhaps correlating with the well-known polarity of this &#8216;Janus face&#8217; cyclohexane. Although the trend was also apparent in the anti-trypanosomal assays of the keto-piperazine derivatives, it was less so and some compounds were more active than the previously reported phenylalanine derived analogue.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
David O'Hagan, 
Mengfan He, 
Christina  M Thomson, 
Dawn Thompson, 
Vytautus Kuodis, 
Terence  K. Smith, 
Sergio Dall'Angelo
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Bioactivity profiles of progressively ring&#8208;fluorinated cyclohexyl motifs in the WKYMVm peptide as formylpeptide FPR2 agonists and in keto&#8208;piperazines as anti&#8208;trypanosome agents.</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500384</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500384</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500384</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500270</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 06:54:49 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-06-03T06:54:49-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500270</guid>
         <title>Engineering Glucagon via Molecular and Formulation Strategies: From Natural Hormone to Effective and Stable Therapeutics</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Glucagon, a 29&#8208;amino acid pancreatic hormone, plays a central role in glucose homeostasis through activation of the glucagon receptor (GCGR). While clinically essential for hypoglycemia rescue, its broader therapeutic applications face limitations due to challenging biophysical properties including poor solubility, strong aggregation tendency, and chemical instability, which currently require lyophilized formulations. Recent advances in peptide engineering and formulation science have enabled the development of next&#8208;generation glucagon analogs with enhanced stability and ready&#8208;to&#8208;use profiles. Moving beyond its classical role in glucose elevation, glucagon is now recognized as a multifunctional metabolic regulator influencing lipid metabolism, energy expenditure, and cardiorenal function. This expanded understanding has driven the development of innovative GCGR&#8208;targeting therapies including multi&#8208;receptor agonists such as glucagon&#8208;like peptide&#8208;1 receptor (GLP&#8208;1R)/GCGR co&#8208;agonists for metabolic disorders and advanced dual&#8208;hormone delivery systems. This review examines the evolving pharmacology of glucagon by analyzing: (1) structural optimization and formulation strategies to address physicochemical challenges, (2) innovative delivery technologies, and (3) emerging therapeutic applications in metabolic diseases. Through critical assessment of translational challenges, this work bridges molecular insights with clinical innovation in glucagon&#8208;based therapeutics.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Glucagon, a 29-amino acid pancreatic hormone, plays a central role in glucose homeostasis through activation of the glucagon receptor (GCGR). While clinically essential for hypoglycemia rescue, its broader therapeutic applications face limitations due to challenging biophysical properties including poor solubility, strong aggregation tendency, and chemical instability, which currently require lyophilized formulations. Recent advances in peptide engineering and formulation science have enabled the development of next-generation glucagon analogs with enhanced stability and ready-to-use profiles. Moving beyond its classical role in glucose elevation, glucagon is now recognized as a multifunctional metabolic regulator influencing lipid metabolism, energy expenditure, and cardiorenal function. This expanded understanding has driven the development of innovative GCGR-targeting therapies including multi-receptor agonists such as glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor (GLP-1R)/GCGR co-agonists for metabolic disorders and advanced dual-hormone delivery systems. This review examines the evolving pharmacology of glucagon by analyzing: (1) structural optimization and formulation strategies to address physicochemical challenges, (2) innovative delivery technologies, and (3) emerging therapeutic applications in metabolic diseases. Through critical assessment of translational challenges, this work bridges molecular insights with clinical innovation in glucagon-based therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Xin Li, 
Yani Wang, 
Zican Chen, 
Zhongping Tan
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Engineering Glucagon via Molecular and Formulation Strategies: From Natural Hormone to Effective and Stable Therapeutics</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500270</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500270</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500270</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500212</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 07:15:39 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-05-06T07:15:39-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500212</guid>
         <title>Glycoproteins, Glycolipids, or Both: Why do Glycosyltransferases Recognize Different Acceptors?</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Glycosylation is an important post&#8208;translational modification catalyzed by glycosyltransferases (GTs), which comprise a large group of enzymes with diversified specificity. Most GTs show high specificity toward donor and acceptor molecules, but some can recognize several donor or acceptor molecules and/or create novel glycosidic linkage types. This promiscuity has profound implications for cellular processes, influencing signaling pathways, protein stability and disease progression. GT promiscuity may result from the structural peculiarities of the enzyme and acceptor, modulation by a ligand, oligomerization with other enzymes, or its subcellular localization. In this review, we discuss current insights into GT promiscuity, highlighting its biological significance and potential associations with human diseases. A better understanding of how GTs work will be essential for developing novel therapeutic approaches and obtaining enzymes with improved properties, which are desirable in the emerging field of glycobiotechnology.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Glycosylation is an important post-translational modification catalyzed by glycosyltransferases (GTs), which comprise a large group of enzymes with diversified specificity. Most GTs show high specificity toward donor and acceptor molecules, but some can recognize several donor or acceptor molecules and/or create novel glycosidic linkage types. This promiscuity has profound implications for cellular processes, influencing signaling pathways, protein stability and disease progression. GT promiscuity may result from the structural peculiarities of the enzyme and acceptor, modulation by a ligand, oligomerization with other enzymes, or its subcellular localization. In this review, we discuss current insights into GT promiscuity, highlighting its biological significance and potential associations with human diseases. A better understanding of how GTs work will be essential for developing novel therapeutic approaches and obtaining enzymes with improved properties, which are desirable in the emerging field of glycobiotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Krzysztof Miko&#322;ajczyk, 
Marcin Czerwinski, 
Radoslaw Kaczmarek
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Glycoproteins, Glycolipids, or Both: Why do Glycosyltransferases Recognize Different Acceptors?</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500212</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500212</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500212</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500252</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 08:58:28 -0700</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2025-04-30T08:58:28-07:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate />
         <prism:coverDisplayDate />
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500252</guid>
         <title>Binding of Hg(I) and Hg(II) Ions to Amyloid&#8208;Beta (A&#946;) Peptide Variants Affect Their Structure and Aggregation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Accepted Article. </description>
         <dc:description>Mercury (Hg) exposure is a possible risk factor for Alzheimer&#180;s disease (AD). Some studies reported higher Hg levels in AD patients, but evidence is inconclusive. A mechanism linking Hg exposure to AD neuropathology remains to be found. The hallmark of AD brains is deposits of insoluble amyloid plaques consisting mainly of aggregated amyloid&#8208;&#946; (A&#946;) peptides.
&#160;
Here, we use transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and biophysical spectroscopy techniques to study in vitro interactions between inorganic Hg and pathologically relevant A&#946;(1&#8208;40) and A&#946;(4&#8208;40) variants and the A&#946;(1&#8208;40)(H6A, H13A, H14A) mutant. For the first time, effect on A&#946; aggregation of both Hg(I) and Hg(II) is compared.
&#160;
Hg(II) binds A&#946;(1&#8208;40) with apparent binding affinity of 28&#177;8 &#181;M, at 20 &#176;C in 20 mM MES buffer, pH 7.3. The N&#8208;terminal His6, His13 and His14 residues are involved in binding coordination. Hg(II) binding induces structural alterations (coil&#8208;coil interactions) in A&#946; monomers positioned in membrane&#8208;mimicking SDS micelles. Equimolar amounts of either Hg(I) or Hg(II) inhibit normal A&#946; fibrillation by directing aggregation towards formation of large amorphous aggregates. All these structural rearrangements may be relevant for the harmful A&#946; aggregation processes involved in AD brain pathology. Inducing protein misfolding and aggregation might be a general toxic mechanism of mercury.</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Mercury (Hg) exposure is a possible risk factor for Alzheimer&#180;s disease (AD). Some studies reported higher Hg levels in AD patients, but evidence is inconclusive. A mechanism linking Hg exposure to AD neuropathology remains to be found. The hallmark of AD brains is deposits of insoluble amyloid plaques consisting mainly of aggregated amyloid-&#946; (A&#946;) peptides.
&#160;
Here, we use transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and biophysical spectroscopy techniques to study in vitro interactions between inorganic Hg and pathologically relevant A&#946;(1-40) and A&#946;(4-40) variants and the A&#946;(1-40)(H6A, H13A, H14A) mutant. For the first time, effect on A&#946; aggregation of both Hg(I) and Hg(II) is compared.
&#160;
Hg(II) binds A&#946;(1-40) with apparent binding affinity of 28&#177;8 &#181;M, at 20 &#176;C in 20 mM MES buffer, pH 7.3. The N-terminal His6, His13 and His14 residues are involved in binding coordination. Hg(II) binding induces structural alterations (coil-coil interactions) in A&#946; monomers positioned in membrane-mimicking SDS micelles. Equimolar amounts of either Hg(I) or Hg(II) inhibit normal A&#946; fibrillation by directing aggregation towards formation of large amorphous aggregates. All these structural rearrangements may be relevant for the harmful A&#946; aggregation processes involved in AD brain pathology. Inducing protein misfolding and aggregation might be a general toxic mechanism of mercury.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Elina Berntsson, 
Andra Noorm&#228;gi, 
K&#228;rt Padari, 
J&#252;ri Jarvet, 
Astrid Gr&#228;slund, 
Margus Pooga, 
Peep Palumaa, 
Sebastian  K. T. S. W&#228;rml&#228;nder
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Binding of Hg(I) and Hg(II) Ions to Amyloid&#8208;Beta (A&#946;) Peptide Variants Affect Their Structure and Aggregation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500252</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500252</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500252</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>