<rss xmlns:atom="http://w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/" version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</title>
      <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      <description>Table of Contents for ChemBioChem. List of articles from both the latest and EarlyView issues.</description>
      <language>en-US</language>
      <copyright>&#169; Wiley-VCH GmbH, Weinheim</copyright>
      <managingEditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com (Chemistry Europe)</managingEditor>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 08:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 08:21:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>Atypon&#174; Literatum&#8482;</generator>
      <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <ttl>10080</ttl>
      <dc:title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
      <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</prism:publicationName>
      <atom:link href="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
      <image>
         <title>Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</title>
         <url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/14397633.jpg</url>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      </image>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500492</link>
         <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:20:50 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-26T08:20:50-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500492</guid>
         <title>Amyloid&#8208;Inducing Agents via Metabolite Self&#8208;Assembly Expands the Boundary of Prion Concept beyond Proteins</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 2, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Origin of Prion&#8208;like Amyloid Nucleating Nanostructures via Metabolite Self&#8208;assembly.

The prion concept fundamentally signifies the intrinsic cross&#8208;seeding potential of misfolded protein&#8208;generated amyloid entities to efficiently induce amyloid aggregation in normally folded proteins leading to formation of cytotoxic amyloid structures. A conformational crosstalk between the prion particle and the interacting protein appears critical for the molecular origin of seeded&#8208;aggregation. However, the intricacies of protein specificity, as a prerequisite for the onset of cross&#8208;seeding, hold negligible relevance to the pathobiology of amyloid&#8208;linked diseases because the amyloid&#8208;deposits are heteroprotein assemblies, and there is adequate evidence that substantiates the occurrence of sequence&#8208;independent amyloid&#8208;cross&#8208;seeding/co&#8208;aggregation reactions between diverse protein types. Importantly, extensive research on the self&#8208;assembly of single metabolites into cytotoxic amyloid&#8208;like entities containing cross&#8208;seeding competent conformers has certainly widened the boundary of prion concept much beyond the territory of proteins and peptides. Three important observations: 1) sequence&#8208;independent cross&#8208;seeding and co&#8208;aggregation among proteins; 2) efficient amyloid&#8208;cross&#8208;seeding of proteins triggered by self&#8208;assembled metabolite&#8208;nanostructures, and 3) molecular self&#8208;assembly of metabolites induced by pre&#8208;formed protein amyloid&#8208;seeds, propose a synergetic interplay between the amyloidogenic proteins and self&#8208;assembly&#8208;prone metabolites that can act as a key regulator for the overall amyloidogenesis mechanism. This review on the self&#8208;assembly of biologically relevant metabolites into amyloid&#8208;mimicking nanostructures mainly highlights their cytotoxic properties and cross&#8208;seeding potential, particularly focusing on the significance of the metabolite&#8208;aggregation in the etiology of amyloid hypothesis.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/ba35f1b7-70ac-4e57-90ff-93f848e4bd4b/cbic70099-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Amyloid-Inducing Agents via Metabolite Self-Assembly Expands the Boundary of Prion Concept beyond Proteins"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Origin of Prion-like Amyloid Nucleating Nanostructures via Metabolite Self-assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prion concept fundamentally signifies the intrinsic cross-seeding potential of misfolded protein-generated amyloid entities to efficiently induce amyloid aggregation in normally folded proteins leading to formation of cytotoxic amyloid structures. A conformational crosstalk between the prion particle and the interacting protein appears critical for the molecular origin of seeded-aggregation. However, the intricacies of protein specificity, as a prerequisite for the onset of cross-seeding, hold negligible relevance to the pathobiology of amyloid-linked diseases because the amyloid-deposits are heteroprotein assemblies, and there is adequate evidence that substantiates the occurrence of sequence-independent amyloid-cross-seeding/co-aggregation reactions between diverse protein types. Importantly, extensive research on the self-assembly of single metabolites into cytotoxic amyloid-like entities containing cross-seeding competent conformers has certainly widened the boundary of prion concept much beyond the territory of proteins and peptides. Three important observations: 1) sequence-independent cross-seeding and co-aggregation among proteins; 2) efficient amyloid-cross-seeding of proteins triggered by self-assembled metabolite-nanostructures, and 3) molecular self-assembly of metabolites induced by pre-formed protein amyloid-seeds, propose a synergetic interplay between the amyloidogenic proteins and self-assembly-prone metabolites that can act as a key regulator for the overall amyloidogenesis mechanism. This review on the self-assembly of biologically relevant metabolites into amyloid-mimicking nanostructures mainly highlights their cytotoxic properties and cross-seeding potential, particularly focusing on the significance of the metabolite-aggregation in the etiology of amyloid hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Kailash Prasad Prajapati, 
Shikha Mittal, 
Masihuzzaman Ansari, 
Bibin Gnanadhason Anand, 
Karunakar Kar
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Amyloid&#8208;Inducing Agents via Metabolite Self&#8208;Assembly Expands the Boundary of Prion Concept beyond Proteins</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500492</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500492</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500492</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>2</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500889</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:15:23 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-22T11:15:23-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500889</guid>
         <title>Protein and Peptide&#8208;Based Strategies for Advanced Cryopreservation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 2, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
This review explores protein and peptide&#8208;based cryoprotectants as safe, biomimetic alternatives to toxic dimethyl sulfoxide. It covers natural antifreeze proteins, stress&#8208;tolerant late embryogenesis abundant proteins and other proteins as well as synthetic mimics that inhibit ice growth, stabilize membranes, and reduce oxidative damage. Key challenges like immunogenicity, scalability, and rational design are discussed, highlighting their potential to advance cell therapy and regenerative medicine.

Cryopreservation effectively halts biological metabolism, placing living specimens in a state of &#8216;suspended animation&#8217; for future revival. As a foundational technology for cell&#8208;based biomedicine, cryopreservation relies on cryoprotectants (CPAs) to mitigate freezing&#8208;induced damage, such as ice formation, protein denaturation, and oxidative stress. However, conventional CPAs like dimethyl sulfoxide and glycerol face practical limitations, including cytotoxicity and cumbersome removal processes, driving the need for novel alternatives. In nature, psychrophilic organisms produce stress&#8208;tolerant proteins, such as antifreeze proteins and late embryogenesis abundant proteins, thus enabling themselves to survive in subzero conditions by controlling ice growth, stabilizing membranes, and performing other protective functions. Inspired by these natural systems, this review aims to explore the potential of protein and peptide&#8208;based materials as next&#8208;generation CPAs. We systematically summarize the characteristics, mechanisms, and cryopreservation applications of natural stress&#8208;resistant proteins and their synthetic mimics. Moreover, we discuss key challenges including immunogenicity, scalability, and the rational design of these synthetic mimics, and outline future directions for the development of these biomimetic cryoprotective materials.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/f99e6c44-1c64-40c1-9272-64695903fa9a/cbic70200-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Protein and Peptide-Based Strategies for Advanced Cryopreservation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review explores protein and peptide-based cryoprotectants as safe, biomimetic alternatives to toxic dimethyl sulfoxide. It covers natural antifreeze proteins, stress-tolerant late embryogenesis abundant proteins and other proteins as well as synthetic mimics that inhibit ice growth, stabilize membranes, and reduce oxidative damage. Key challenges like immunogenicity, scalability, and rational design are discussed, highlighting their potential to advance cell therapy and regenerative medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryopreservation effectively halts biological metabolism, placing living specimens in a state of &#8216;suspended animation&#8217; for future revival. As a foundational technology for cell-based biomedicine, cryopreservation relies on cryoprotectants (CPAs) to mitigate freezing-induced damage, such as ice formation, protein denaturation, and oxidative stress. However, conventional CPAs like dimethyl sulfoxide and glycerol face practical limitations, including cytotoxicity and cumbersome removal processes, driving the need for novel alternatives. In nature, psychrophilic organisms produce stress-tolerant proteins, such as antifreeze proteins and late embryogenesis abundant proteins, thus enabling themselves to survive in subzero conditions by controlling ice growth, stabilizing membranes, and performing other protective functions. Inspired by these natural systems, this review aims to explore the potential of protein and peptide-based materials as next-generation CPAs. We systematically summarize the characteristics, mechanisms, and cryopreservation applications of natural stress-resistant proteins and their synthetic mimics. Moreover, we discuss key challenges including immunogenicity, scalability, and the rational design of these synthetic mimics, and outline future directions for the development of these biomimetic cryoprotective materials.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yihang Gao, 
Shenglin Jin, 
Jianjun Wang
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Protein and Peptide&#8208;Based Strategies for Advanced Cryopreservation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500889</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500889</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500889</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>2</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500477</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:03:12 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-22T11:03:12-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500477</guid>
         <title>Amphiphilic Cu(II) Oxacyclen Complexes: From Oxidative Cleavage to Condensation of DNA</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 2, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Monoalkylated Cu(II) oxacyclen complexes show a dual DNA effect: shorter alkyl chains enable ROS&#8208;mediated DNA cleavage, whereas longer chains cause strong DNA condensation/aggregation. Thus, chain length controls activity. Using circular dichroism, UV/visible and fluorescence spectroscopy, atomic force microscopy, dynamic light scattering, and molecular dynamics, we demonstrate that amphiphilic Cu(II) complexes are promising DNA modulators.

Cu(II) complexes with monoalkylated oxacyclen ligands (C12, C16, and C18) have been investigated regarding their interaction with DNA by different methods: circular dichroism, UV/VIS (ultraviolet&#8208;visible) and fluorescence spectroscopy as well as by gel electrophoresis. The results demonstrate that the complexes can cleave DNA through both hydrolytic and oxidative mechanisms, with hydroxyl radicals and hydrogen peroxide identified as the reactive oxygen species involved. The targeted incorporation of alkyl chains significantly enhances the DNA&#8208;binding affinity of the Cu(II) complexes, and the length of the alkyl substituents plays an important role, as they can interact with the major groove of the DNA. Alkylation is the determining structural factor responsible for the enhanced DNA interaction, since such an interaction is not observed with unsubstituted complexes. Moreover, the length of the alkyl chains significantly influences this behavior, as longer substituents induce a concentration&#8208;dependent DNA aggregation, a phenomenon absent in the nonalkylated analog. This aggregation and condensation behavior is examined using atomic force microscopy and dynamic light scattering. Moreover, DNA/small molecule interactions are also investigated using molecular dynamics simulations.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/b0a18b44-9a17-4d85-9101-7c2db5e328be/cbic70140-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Amphiphilic Cu(II) Oxacyclen Complexes: From Oxidative Cleavage to Condensation of DNA"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monoalkylated Cu(II) oxacyclen complexes show a dual DNA effect: shorter alkyl chains enable ROS-mediated DNA cleavage, whereas longer chains cause strong DNA condensation/aggregation. Thus, chain length controls activity. Using circular dichroism, UV/visible and fluorescence spectroscopy, atomic force microscopy, dynamic light scattering, and molecular dynamics, we demonstrate that amphiphilic Cu(II) complexes are promising DNA modulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cu(II) complexes with monoalkylated oxacyclen ligands (C&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;, C&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt;, and C&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt;) have been investigated regarding their interaction with DNA by different methods: circular dichroism, UV/VIS (ultraviolet-visible) and fluorescence spectroscopy as well as by gel electrophoresis. The results demonstrate that the complexes can cleave DNA through both hydrolytic and oxidative mechanisms, with hydroxyl radicals and hydrogen peroxide identified as the reactive oxygen species involved. The targeted incorporation of alkyl chains significantly enhances the DNA-binding affinity of the Cu(II) complexes, and the length of the alkyl substituents plays an important role, as they can interact with the major groove of the DNA. Alkylation is the determining structural factor responsible for the enhanced DNA interaction, since such an interaction is not observed with unsubstituted complexes. Moreover, the length of the alkyl chains significantly influences this behavior, as longer substituents induce a concentration-dependent DNA aggregation, a phenomenon absent in the nonalkylated analog. This aggregation and condensation behavior is examined using atomic force microscopy and dynamic light scattering. Moreover, DNA/small molecule interactions are also investigated using molecular dynamics simulations.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Olga Verbitsky, 
Sebasti&#225;n Hinojosa, 
Amr Mostafa, 
Deepak Ojha, 
Ilko Bald, 
Nora Kulak
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Amphiphilic Cu(II) Oxacyclen Complexes: From Oxidative Cleavage to Condensation of DNA</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500477</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500477</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500477</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>2</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500698</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:22:25 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-17T08:22:25-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500698</guid>
         <title>Stereocontrol of Styrene Monooxygenases: Mechanistic Principles of (R)&#8208; and (S)&#8208;Selective Epoxidations and Their Implications for Biocatalysis</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 2, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Styrene monooxygenases with different enantioselectivities allow olefins to adopt distinct binding orientations within the catalytic cavity, leading the O&#8208;atom of C4a&#8208;hydroperoxyflavin (FADOOH) to attack either the Re&#8208;face or the Si&#8208;face of the substrate. This difference in attack direction ultimately determines the resulting enantioselectivity.

Numerous styrene monooxygenases (SMOs) have been identified and extensively applied in the asymmetric epoxidation of alkenes to prepare enantiopure epoxides, which are important intermediates in pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and fine chemicals. A current challenge is development of engineered SMOs capable of catalyzing a broad range of substrates with complementary enantioselectivity, thereby enabling the production of both (R)&#8208; and (S)&#8208;epoxides. Achieving this requires a deep understanding of the molecular basis underlying enantiocontrolling in SMO&#8208;catalyzed epoxidation. In this concept article, recent progress in elucidating the mechanisms of enantiocontrol by SMOs is summarized, with particular emphasis on the structural and mechanistic features that differentiate (R)&#8208; and (S)&#8208;selective SMOs. These insights not only expand fundamental knowledge of SMO catalysis but also provide a critical foundation for the rational design and protein engineering of highly efficient and versatile SMOs.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/62f4925e-4ba6-4286-a433-c1fbe5d78a6c/cbic70170-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Stereocontrol of Styrene Monooxygenases: Mechanistic Principles of (R)- and (S)-Selective Epoxidations and Their Implications for Biocatalysis"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Styrene monooxygenases with different enantioselectivities allow olefins to adopt distinct binding orientations within the catalytic cavity, leading the O-atom of C4a-hydroperoxyflavin (FAD&lt;sub&gt;OOH&lt;/sub&gt;) to attack either the Re-face or the Si-face of the substrate. This difference in attack direction ultimately determines the resulting enantioselectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous styrene monooxygenases (SMOs) have been identified and extensively applied in the asymmetric epoxidation of alkenes to prepare enantiopure epoxides, which are important intermediates in pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and fine chemicals. A current challenge is development of engineered SMOs capable of catalyzing a broad range of substrates with complementary enantioselectivity, thereby enabling the production of both (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)- and (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)-epoxides. Achieving this requires a deep understanding of the molecular basis underlying enantiocontrolling in SMO-catalyzed epoxidation. In this concept article, recent progress in elucidating the mechanisms of enantiocontrol by SMOs is summarized, with particular emphasis on the structural and mechanistic features that differentiate (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)- and (&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;)-selective SMOs. These insights not only expand fundamental knowledge of SMO catalysis but also provide a critical foundation for the rational design and protein engineering of highly efficient and versatile SMOs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Na Li, 
Yifan Fan, 
Yuansen Hu, 
Zhongliu Wu, 
Hui Lin
</dc:creator>
         <category>Concept</category>
         <dc:title>Stereocontrol of Styrene Monooxygenases: Mechanistic Principles of (R)&#8208; and (S)&#8208;Selective Epoxidations and Their Implications for Biocatalysis</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500698</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500698</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500698</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Concept</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>2</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500795</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:20:55 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-17T08:20:55-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500795</guid>
         <title>Modulation of Liquid&#8208;to&#8208;Solid Phase Transition in Coacervates for Neurodegenerative Disease Treatments</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 2, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
This review summarizes the factors influencing the liquid&#8208;to&#8208;solid phase transition of coacervates, including physical stimuli, molecular modulators, and sequence changes.

Coacervates formed through liquid&#8211;liquid phase separation represent a fundamental model for protocell and serve as a membraneless organelle in living cells, modulating various biological processes. During aging or under stress, protein misfolding and oligomerization trigger aberrant liquid&#8208;to&#8208;solid phase transition (LSPT), a process driven by multivalent interactions. These phase transitions disrupt cellular equilibrium, leading to neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The regulatory strategies is summarize to enhance molecular interactions in coacervate LSPT into three categories, including physical stimulation, molecular modulation, and sequence regulation. This review aims to establish a conceptual framework for modulating coacervate LSPT and further explores potential clinical treatments for neurodegenerative diseases.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/ad8fd57d-e9c7-4c34-8a32-335c09212c13/cbic70178-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Modulation of Liquid-to-Solid Phase Transition in Coacervates for Neurodegenerative Disease Treatments"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review summarizes the factors influencing the liquid-to-solid phase transition of coacervates, including physical stimuli, molecular modulators, and sequence changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coacervates formed through liquid&#8211;liquid phase separation represent a fundamental model for protocell and serve as a membraneless organelle in living cells, modulating various biological processes. During aging or under stress, protein misfolding and oligomerization trigger aberrant liquid-to-solid phase transition (LSPT), a process driven by multivalent interactions. These phase transitions disrupt cellular equilibrium, leading to neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The regulatory strategies is summarize to enhance molecular interactions in coacervate LSPT into three categories, including physical stimulation, molecular modulation, and sequence regulation. This review aims to establish a conceptual framework for modulating coacervate LSPT and further explores potential clinical treatments for neurodegenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Xiaokang Wang, 
Minghao Wei, 
Yan Qiao
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Modulation of Liquid&#8208;to&#8208;Solid Phase Transition in Coacervates for Neurodegenerative Disease Treatments</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500795</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500795</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500795</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>2</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70216</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:20:04 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-17T08:20:04-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.70216</guid>
         <title>Front Cover: Amyloid&#8208;Inducing Agents via Metabolite Self&#8208;Assembly Expands the Boundary of Prion Concept beyond Proteins (ChemBioChem 2/2026)</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 2, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The amazing potential of tiny metabolites to self&#8208;assemble into amyloid&#8208;like structures, which are usually built from the self&#8208;assembly of contiguous polypeptide chains. These metabolite&#8208;nanostructures mimic characteristics of protein amyloids, and they possess striking potential for prion&#8208;like cross&#8208;seeding effect, triggering the amyloid aggregation of diverse proteins, generating protein amyloids, which becomes the foundational event for the onset of devastating amyloid&#8208;linked diseases. Deciphering the mechanism of prion&#8208;like activity of metabolite aggregates would certainly add new insights into the mechanistic understanding of both metabolic disorders and the complex cascade of the amyloid hypothesis. More details can be found in the Review Article by Bibin Gnanadhason Anand, Karunakar Kar, and co&#8208;workers (DOI: 10.1002/cbic.202500492).
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e657636c-2bf7-4476-bbcc-d17e05fdaa14/cbic70216-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Front Cover: Amyloid-Inducing Agents via Metabolite Self-Assembly Expands the Boundary of Prion Concept beyond Proteins (ChemBioChem 2/2026)"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amazing potential of tiny metabolites to self-assemble into amyloid-like structures, which are usually built from the self-assembly of contiguous polypeptide chains. These metabolite-nanostructures mimic characteristics of protein amyloids, and they possess striking potential for prion-like cross-seeding effect, triggering the amyloid aggregation of diverse proteins, generating protein amyloids, which becomes the foundational event for the onset of devastating amyloid-linked diseases. Deciphering the mechanism of prion-like activity of metabolite aggregates would certainly add new insights into the mechanistic understanding of both metabolic disorders and the complex cascade of the amyloid hypothesis. More details can be found in the Review Article by Bibin Gnanadhason Anand, Karunakar Kar, and co-workers (DOI: &lt;a target="_blank"
   title="Link to external resource"
   href="http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/cbic.202500492"&gt;10.1002/cbic.202500492&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Kailash Prasad Prajapati, 
Shikha Mittal, 
Masihuzzaman Ansari, 
Bibin Gnanadhason Anand, 
Karunakar Kar
</dc:creator>
         <category>Cover</category>
         <dc:title>Front Cover: Amyloid&#8208;Inducing Agents via Metabolite Self&#8208;Assembly Expands the Boundary of Prion Concept beyond Proteins (ChemBioChem 2/2026)</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.70216</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.70216</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70216</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Cover</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>2</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500756</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-16T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500756</guid>
         <title>Design, Synthesis, and Bioevaluation of Adamantane&#8208;1&#8208;Carboxamide N&#8208;Acylthioureas for Airway Antiallergic Therapy</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Traffic&#8208;related diesel exhaust particles (DEP) disrupt the airway epithelial barrier and drive allergic asthma via thymic stromal lymphopoietin (TSLP) release. A series of adamantane&#8208;1&#8208;carboxamide N&#8208;acylthiourea derivatives are designed and synthesized. Lead compound AD4 dose&#8208;dependently upregulates PP4, restores epithelial integrity, and strongly suppresses DEP&#8208;induced TSLP in BEAS&#8208;2B cells, emerging as a promising novel therapeutic candidate for allergic airway inflammation.

Airway epithelial cells (AECs) serve as the first line of defense against environmental pollutants, with exposure to traffic&#8208;related particles known to exacerbate allergic asthma. In this study, a series of adamantane&#8208;containing N&#8208;acylthiourea compounds are designed, synthesized, and structurally characterized by 1H NMR, 13C NMR, HR&#8208;ESI&#8208;MS, FT&#8208;IR, and UV&#8211;vis spectroscopy. Among them, compound AD3, is crystallized in the triclinic P&#8208;1 space group. Here, it is found that AD4 upregulated the expression of protein phosphatase 4 (PP4) in BEAS&#8208;2B airway epithelial cells in a concentration&#8208;dependent manner. AD4 treatment also significantly restored epithelial barrier integrity and suppressed the production of thymic stromal lymphopoietin (TSLP) production challenged by diesel exhaust particles (DEP). To the author's knowledge, this represents the first report identifying AD4 as a potential therapeutic agent for allergic asthma, highlighting a novel strategy for antiallergic drugs.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/55b83fdb-505d-42ea-a190-cafe4b9ca0cd/cbic70189-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Design, Synthesis, and Bioevaluation of Adamantane-1-Carboxamide N-Acylthioureas for Airway Antiallergic Therapy"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic-related diesel exhaust particles (DEP) disrupt the airway epithelial barrier and drive allergic asthma via thymic stromal lymphopoietin (TSLP) release. A series of adamantane-1-carboxamide N-acylthiourea derivatives are designed and synthesized. Lead compound &lt;b&gt;AD4&lt;/b&gt; dose-dependently upregulates PP4, restores epithelial integrity, and strongly suppresses DEP-induced TSLP in BEAS-2B cells, emerging as a promising novel therapeutic candidate for allergic airway inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airway epithelial cells (AECs) serve as the first line of defense against environmental pollutants, with exposure to traffic-related particles known to exacerbate allergic asthma. In this study, a series of adamantane-containing N-acylthiourea compounds are designed, synthesized, and structurally characterized by &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H NMR, &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C NMR, HR-ESI-MS, FT-IR, and UV&#8211;vis spectroscopy. Among them, compound &lt;b&gt;AD3&lt;/b&gt;, is crystallized in the triclinic P-1 space group. Here, it is found that &lt;b&gt;AD4&lt;/b&gt; upregulated the expression of protein phosphatase 4 (PP4) in BEAS-2B airway epithelial cells in a concentration-dependent manner. &lt;b&gt;AD4&lt;/b&gt; treatment also significantly restored epithelial barrier integrity and suppressed the production of thymic stromal lymphopoietin (TSLP) production challenged by diesel exhaust particles (DEP). To the author's knowledge, this represents the first report identifying &lt;b&gt;AD4&lt;/b&gt; as a potential therapeutic agent for allergic asthma, highlighting a novel strategy for antiallergic drugs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Rahime Eshaghi Malekshah, 
Amir Karim, 
Chi&#8208;Xin Guo, 
Yu&#8208;Ting Chu, 
Feng&#8208;Ming Yang, 
Sung&#8208;Po Hsu, 
Sodio C. N. Hsu
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Design, Synthesis, and Bioevaluation of Adamantane&#8208;1&#8208;Carboxamide N&#8208;Acylthioureas for Airway Antiallergic Therapy</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500756</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500756</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500756</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500914</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-14T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500914</guid>
         <title>Systematic Characterization of Cancer&#8208;Associated SPOP Mutants Reveals Novel and Reprogrammable Degradative Activities</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Quantitative proteomics reveal distinct activities of speckle&#8208;type POZ protein (SPOP) cancer mutants. SPOP&#8208;F133L, unlike F102C, retains degradation of NUP153 and TPR, and partially down&#8208;regulates p53 through a Cullin&#8208;RING ligase&#8208;dependent mechanism. Both mutants support targeted protein degradation in engineered cells, highlighting opportunities to exploit SPOP variants for ligand&#8208;induced protein degradation in cancers harboring these mutations.

Speckle&#8208;type POZ protein (SPOP) functions as the substrate adaptor of the Cullin3&#8208;RING ligase complex and is recurrently mutated in multiple cancer types. Among these, F102C and F133L are frequent prostate cancer mutations within the substrate&#8208;binding domain, yet their biochemical consequences remain incompletely understood. Using quantitative proteomics, we show that SPOP&#8208;F133L, unlike SPOP&#8208;F102C, retains degradative activity toward the nuclear basket proteins NUP153 and TPR, indicating substrate&#8208;dependent loss&#8208;of&#8208;function. Moreover, SPOP&#8208;F133L induces partial down&#8208;regulation of p53 through a Cullin&#8208;RING ligase&#8208;dependent, post&#8208;translational mechanism, revealing a potential neo&#8208;substrate relationship. Finally, we demonstrate that both SPOP&#8208;F102C and SPOP&#8208;F133L support targeted protein degradation in an engineered cellular system. These findings define the degradative capacities of SPOP mutants and highlight opportunities to repurpose these variants as mutant&#8208;selective E3 ligases for therapeutic applications.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/8562364e-b9c1-46db-b4c9-e47347440b7c/cbic70197-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Systematic Characterization of Cancer-Associated SPOP Mutants Reveals Novel and Reprogrammable Degradative Activities"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantitative proteomics reveal distinct activities of speckle-type POZ protein (SPOP) cancer mutants. SPOP-F133L, unlike F102C, retains degradation of NUP153 and TPR, and partially down-regulates p53 through a Cullin-RING ligase-dependent mechanism. Both mutants support targeted protein degradation in engineered cells, highlighting opportunities to exploit SPOP variants for ligand-induced protein degradation in cancers harboring these mutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speckle-type POZ protein (SPOP) functions as the substrate adaptor of the Cullin3-RING ligase complex and is recurrently mutated in multiple cancer types. Among these, F102C and F133L are frequent prostate cancer mutations within the substrate-binding domain, yet their biochemical consequences remain incompletely understood. Using quantitative proteomics, we show that SPOP-F133L, unlike SPOP-F102C, retains degradative activity toward the nuclear basket proteins NUP153 and TPR, indicating substrate-dependent loss-of-function. Moreover, SPOP-F133L induces partial down-regulation of p53 through a Cullin-RING ligase-dependent, post-translational mechanism, revealing a potential neo-substrate relationship. Finally, we demonstrate that both SPOP-F102C and SPOP-F133L support targeted protein degradation in an engineered cellular system. These findings define the degradative capacities of SPOP mutants and highlight opportunities to repurpose these variants as mutant-selective E3 ligases for therapeutic applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Alana G. Caldwell, 
Harshil Parmar, 
Xiaokang Jin, 
Chen Zhou, 
Xiaoyu Zhang
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Systematic Characterization of Cancer&#8208;Associated SPOP Mutants Reveals Novel and Reprogrammable Degradative Activities</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500914</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500914</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500914</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500616</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-14T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500616</guid>
         <title>Advances and Applications of Spatial Proteomics: From Organellar Maps to Clinical Translation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Spatial proteomics provides high&#8208;resolution maps of protein localization and trafficking by combining advanced mass spectrometry with complementary imaging and computational tools. Emerging low&#8208;input and automated workflows are expanding its applicability to challenging clinical samples, supporting mechanistic disease research and biomarker discovery.

Spatial proteomics has emerged as a powerful approach to systematically map the subcellular localization of thousands of proteins in parallel, providing insights into organelle composition, protein trafficking, and context&#8208;dependent relocalization events. Building on advances in mass spectrometry sensitivity, and acquisition as well as quantification strategies, organelle&#8208;resolved protein maps can now be generated with unprecedented depth and resolution, and recent workflows have expanded the applicability of spatial proteomics to diverse experimental and challenging contexts. Complementary bioinformatic pipelines enable the assignment of proteins to compartments, the detection of distribution shifts, and the integration of spatial data with other omics layers. Beyond fundamental cell biology, the technology holds great potential for clinical research, where limited input material and the complexity of primary samples pose specific challenges. Emerging low&#8208;input preparation methods, antibody&#8208;based organelle enrichment, and microscopy&#8208;guided approaches offer promising solutions, while robust, marker&#8208;independent data analysis will be essential to handle the biological variability of patient&#8208;derived samples. As protocols become more automated, low&#8208;input compatible, and bioinformatically standardized, spatial proteomics is poised to become a valuable tool for mechanistic disease research, biomarker discovery, and therapeutic target identification.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/7440dc3f-4d12-4430-a70e-2a6abb0804c5/cbic70165-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Advances and Applications of Spatial Proteomics: From Organellar Maps to Clinical Translation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial proteomics provides high-resolution maps of protein localization and trafficking by combining advanced mass spectrometry with complementary imaging and computational tools. Emerging low-input and automated workflows are expanding its applicability to challenging clinical samples, supporting mechanistic disease research and biomarker discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial proteomics has emerged as a powerful approach to systematically map the subcellular localization of thousands of proteins in parallel, providing insights into organelle composition, protein trafficking, and context-dependent relocalization events. Building on advances in mass spectrometry sensitivity, and acquisition as well as quantification strategies, organelle-resolved protein maps can now be generated with unprecedented depth and resolution, and recent workflows have expanded the applicability of spatial proteomics to diverse experimental and challenging contexts. Complementary bioinformatic pipelines enable the assignment of proteins to compartments, the detection of distribution shifts, and the integration of spatial data with other omics layers. Beyond fundamental cell biology, the technology holds great potential for clinical research, where limited input material and the complexity of primary samples pose specific challenges. Emerging low-input preparation methods, antibody-based organelle enrichment, and microscopy-guided approaches offer promising solutions, while robust, marker-independent data analysis will be essential to handle the biological variability of patient-derived samples. As protocols become more automated, low-input compatible, and bioinformatically standardized, spatial proteomics is poised to become a valuable tool for mechanistic disease research, biomarker discovery, and therapeutic target identification.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Chiara Bernardini, 
Maike D&#228;ther, 
Franziska R. Traube
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Advances and Applications of Spatial Proteomics: From Organellar Maps to Clinical Translation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500616</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500616</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500616</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500691</link>
         <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-13T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500691</guid>
         <title>Microbial Carrier&#8208;Based Delivery of RHNO1 for Mediating NF&#8208;&#954;B Signaling Inhibition to Regulate Proliferation and Apoptosis in Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Targeting the RHNO1/NF&#8208;&#954;B pathway: Aspergillus melleus extract&#8208;functionalized chitosan nanoparticles (CS&#8208;1@RHNO1) trigger apoptosis and drive tumor regression in nonsmall cell lung cancer.

This study aimed to investigate the role and clinical significance of RHNO1 in nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC). By analyzing clinical samples and cell lines, we assessed RHNO1 expression and its correlation with clinicopathological features and patient prognosis, validating its potential as a diagnostic and prognostic biomarker. Furthermore, in vitro and in vivo experiments revealed the functional role of RHNO1 in NSCLC progression and its molecular interaction with the NF&#8208;&#954;B signaling pathway, defining the regulatory mechanism of the &#8220;RHNO1&#8211;NF&#8208;&#954;B axis.&#8221; In parallel, we developed a chitosan&#8208;based delivery system (CS&#8208;1@RHNO1), which markedly enhanced the loading efficiency and targeting specificity of RHNO1 regulatory agents, enabling precise modulation of the &#8220;RHNO1&#8211;NF&#8208;&#954;B axis.&#8221; Our findings demonstrate that RHNO1 functions not only as a potential diagnostic and prognostic marker but also as a promising therapeutic target, while the CS&#8208;1@RHNO1 system provides a novel strategy for targeted delivery in NSCLC. Collectively, this study offers new theoretical insights and technological advances for understanding NSCLC pathogenesis and developing targeted therapies.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2dae91a4-f185-43b3-b167-3d4b93fd3cfc/cbic70179-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Microbial Carrier-Based Delivery of RHNO1 for Mediating NF-&#954;B Signaling Inhibition to Regulate Proliferation and Apoptosis in Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeting the RHNO1/NF-&#954;B pathway: &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;melleus&lt;/i&gt; extract-functionalized chitosan nanoparticles (CS-1@RHNO1) trigger apoptosis and drive tumor regression in nonsmall cell lung cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to investigate the role and clinical significance of RHNO1 in nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC). By analyzing clinical samples and cell lines, we assessed RHNO1 expression and its correlation with clinicopathological features and patient prognosis, validating its potential as a diagnostic and prognostic biomarker. Furthermore, in vitro and in vivo experiments revealed the functional role of RHNO1 in NSCLC progression and its molecular interaction with the NF-&#954;B signaling pathway, defining the regulatory mechanism of the &#8220;RHNO1&#8211;NF-&#954;B axis.&#8221; In parallel, we developed a chitosan-based delivery system (CS-1@RHNO1), which markedly enhanced the loading efficiency and targeting specificity of RHNO1 regulatory agents, enabling precise modulation of the &#8220;RHNO1&#8211;NF-&#954;B axis.&#8221; Our findings demonstrate that RHNO1 functions not only as a potential diagnostic and prognostic marker but also as a promising therapeutic target, while the CS-1@RHNO1 system provides a novel strategy for targeted delivery in NSCLC. Collectively, this study offers new theoretical insights and technological advances for understanding NSCLC pathogenesis and developing targeted therapies.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Chengshi Zhang, 
Yunfeng Zhao, 
Minghua Xu, 
Qiliang Feng
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Microbial Carrier&#8208;Based Delivery of RHNO1 for Mediating NF&#8208;&#954;B Signaling Inhibition to Regulate Proliferation and Apoptosis in Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500691</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500691</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500691</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500835</link>
         <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-12T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500835</guid>
         <title>Exploring the RNA&#8208;Binding Potential of Three&#8208;Dimensional Cyanines Derived From [2.2]Paracyclophane: A Structure&#8211;Property Relationship</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Turn&#8208;on polymethine dyes with a 3D [2.2]paracyclophane core selectively bind single&#8208;stranded RNA over duplex regions, exhibiting higher specificity than flat benzene analogs.

This study reports the design, synthesis, and structure&#8211;property analysis of an original family of three&#8208;dimensional cyanine dyes based on the [2.2]paracyclophane (pCp) scaffold. By converting planar polymethine chromophores into three&#8208;dimensional architectures, we developed fluorogenic dyes with enhanced selectivity for single&#8208;stranded RNA containing stem&#8208;loop motifs. Comparative studies with planar analogs show that benzothiazole&#8208; and benzoselenazole&#8208;containing pCp derivatives exhibit strong fluorescence turn&#8208;on upon nucleic&#8208;acid binding, with responses varying by nucleic acid type and structure. Circular dichroism analyses suggest that these three&#8208;dimensional dyes interact with RNA via a nonintercalative mode, distinct from classical planar intercalators. Expanding upon preliminary findings, this work explores an extended series of pCp&#8208;derived cyanines, revealing how three&#8208;dimensionality modulates both photophysical behavior and nucleic&#8208;acid recognition. These results provide new directions for the design of selective RNA&#8208;targeting ligands and for future exploration of their interactions with more complex RNA architectures.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/3f1e619e-4c66-4bed-9dcb-bf6ef040dca4/cbic70195-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Exploring the RNA-Binding Potential of Three-Dimensional Cyanines Derived From [2.2]Paracyclophane: A Structure&#8211;Property Relationship"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn-on polymethine dyes with a 3D [2.2]paracyclophane core selectively bind single-stranded RNA over duplex regions, exhibiting higher specificity than flat benzene analogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study reports the design, synthesis, and structure&#8211;property analysis of an original family of three-dimensional cyanine dyes based on the [2.2]paracyclophane (pCp) scaffold. By converting planar polymethine chromophores into three-dimensional architectures, we developed fluorogenic dyes with enhanced selectivity for single-stranded RNA containing stem-loop motifs. Comparative studies with planar analogs show that benzothiazole- and benzoselenazole-containing pCp derivatives exhibit strong fluorescence turn-on upon nucleic-acid binding, with responses varying by nucleic acid type and structure. Circular dichroism analyses suggest that these three-dimensional dyes interact with RNA via a nonintercalative mode, distinct from classical planar intercalators. Expanding upon preliminary findings, this work explores an extended series of pCp-derived cyanines, revealing how three-dimensionality modulates both photophysical behavior and nucleic-acid recognition. These results provide new directions for the design of selective RNA-targeting ligands and for future exploration of their interactions with more complex RNA architectures.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Rongyu Sun, 
Cristian Siretanu, 
Georgina Ilieska, 
Simon Felder, 
Erica Benedetti, 
Laurent Micouin
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Exploring the RNA&#8208;Binding Potential of Three&#8208;Dimensional Cyanines Derived From [2.2]Paracyclophane: A Structure&#8211;Property Relationship</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500835</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500835</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500835</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500688</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-10T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500688</guid>
         <title>Design, Synthesis, Molecular Docking, Structure Activity Relationship, and In Vivo Evaluation of Pyrazole&#8211;Pyrimidines for Discovering New Nonsteroidal Anti&#8208;Inflammatory Drugs</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A new series of pyrazole&#8211;pyrimidines was synthesized. Compounds 4d, 4j, and 4k showed higher binding affinity to COX&#8208;2 in molecular docking studies, corroborated by ADMET predictions, which indicated favorable pharmacokinetic and toxicological properties. Compounds 4d, 4e, 4f, 4j, and 4k were as effective as celecoxib in attenuating the nociceptive behaviors of mice, without causing locomotor alterations.

Nonsteroidal anti&#8208;inflammatory drugs are among the most prescribed worldwide to treat pain, fever, and inflammation. However, they can cause severe adverse effects such as gastric, duodenal, hepatic, and renal injuries. Thus, the search for effective and new drugs is of high priority. Herein, the synthesis of a new series 4&#8208;((5&#8208;substituted&#8208;3&#8208;(trifluoromethyl)&#8208;1H&#8208;pyrazol&#8208;1&#8208;yl)methyl)&#8208;6&#8208;(trifluoromethyl) pyrimidin&#8208;2&#8208;substituted (pyrazole&#8211;pyrimidines) obtained through the cyclocondensation reaction of pyrazole&#8211;enaminones with amidines under mild conditions is reported. The chemical structures are confirmed by 1H and 13C NMR, mass spectrometry, and single&#8208;crystal X&#8208;ray analysis for compounds 4c and 4g. Molecular docking studies are conducted to identify selective cyclooxygenase&#8208;2 (COX&#8208;2) inhibitors, revealing that compounds 4d, 4j, and 4k display higher binding affinity. ADMET predictions (absorption, distribution, metabolism, excretion, and toxicity) corroborate to the docking results, suggesting favorable pharmacokinetic and toxicological properties. The in&#8201;vivo antinociceptive activity is investigated in mice using the capsaicin&#8208;induced nociception model. Oral administration of compounds 4d, 4e, 4f, 4j, and 4k significantly reduces nociceptive responses, achieving effects comparable or superior to celecoxib, without altering locomotor activity. Altogether, the findings demonstrate that pyrazole&#8211;pyrimidine derivatives, especially 4d and 4k, are promising candidates for the development of selective COX&#8208;2 analgesics, combining antinociceptive efficacy with a favorable toxicological profile.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/cc945f98-24da-44ab-b820-8fa180a4bea5/cbic70176-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Design, Synthesis, Molecular Docking, Structure Activity Relationship, and In Vivo Evaluation of Pyrazole&#8211;Pyrimidines for Discovering New Nonsteroidal Anti-Inflammatory Drugs"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new series of pyrazole&#8211;pyrimidines was synthesized. Compounds &lt;b&gt;4d&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4j&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;4k&lt;/b&gt; showed higher binding affinity to COX-2 in molecular docking studies, corroborated by ADMET predictions, which indicated favorable pharmacokinetic and toxicological properties. Compounds &lt;b&gt;4d&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4e&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4f&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4j&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;4k&lt;/b&gt; were as effective as celecoxib in attenuating the nociceptive behaviors of mice, without causing locomotor alterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs are among the most prescribed worldwide to treat pain, fever, and inflammation. However, they can cause severe adverse effects such as gastric, duodenal, hepatic, and renal injuries. Thus, the search for effective and new drugs is of high priority. Herein, the synthesis of a new series 4-((5-substituted-3-(trifluoromethyl)-1&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-pyrazol-1-yl)methyl)-6-(trifluoromethyl) pyrimidin-2-substituted (pyrazole&#8211;pyrimidines) obtained through the cyclocondensation reaction of pyrazole&#8211;enaminones with amidines under mild conditions is reported. The chemical structures are confirmed by &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H and &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C NMR, mass spectrometry, and single-crystal X-ray analysis for compounds &lt;b&gt;4c&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;4g&lt;/b&gt;. Molecular docking studies are conducted to identify selective cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) inhibitors, revealing that compounds &lt;b&gt;4d&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4j&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;4k&lt;/b&gt; display higher binding affinity. ADMET predictions (absorption, distribution, metabolism, excretion, and toxicity) corroborate to the docking results, suggesting favorable pharmacokinetic and toxicological properties. The in&#8201;vivo antinociceptive activity is investigated in mice using the capsaicin-induced nociception model. Oral administration of compounds &lt;b&gt;4d&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4e&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4f&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;4j&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;4k&lt;/b&gt; significantly reduces nociceptive responses, achieving effects comparable or superior to celecoxib, without altering locomotor activity. Altogether, the findings demonstrate that pyrazole&#8211;pyrimidine derivatives, especially &lt;b&gt;4d&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;4k&lt;/b&gt;, are promising candidates for the development of selective COX-2 analgesics, combining antinociceptive efficacy with a favorable toxicological profile.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Paulo A. Moraes, 
Genilson S. Pereira, 
M&#225;rio A. Marangoni, 
Jo&#227;o Pedro V. Lopes, 
Amanda Favarin, 
Adriano F. Camargo, 
Pablo A. Nogara, 
Helio G. Bonacorso, 
Marcos A. P. Martins, 
Sara M. Oliveira, 
Nilo Zanatta
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Design, Synthesis, Molecular Docking, Structure Activity Relationship, and In Vivo Evaluation of Pyrazole&#8211;Pyrimidines for Discovering New Nonsteroidal Anti&#8208;Inflammatory Drugs</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500688</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500688</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500688</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500749</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-10T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500749</guid>
         <title>A Stable Bioisostere of Ester&#8208;Linked Ubiquitin Chains Enables Decoding of Protein Interactors</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
An ester&#8208;to&#8208;amide analog of an ester&#8208;linked ubiquitin dimer is chemically synthesized through a convergent approach involving the sequential chemoselective ligation of three peptide fragments generated through Fmoc&#8208;based solid&#8208;phase peptide synthesis. The hydrolysis&#8208;resistant ubiquitin dimer served as a chemical probe in the identification of potential reader of the ester&#8208;linked ubiquitin chain.

Protein ubiquitination is a pivotal posttranslational modification that regulates diverse biological processes depending on the type of ubiquitin chain linkage. Recently, ester&#8208;linked ubiquitin chains have been identified, yet their inherent hydrolytic instability has posed a significant challenge for biochemical investigations. In this study, a stable and isosteric amide analog of an ester&#8208;linked ubiquitin dimer, is chemically synthesized in which serine (Ser) at position 20 of the proximal ubiquitin is replaced with 2,3&#8208;diaminopropionic acid (Dap). The desired amide analog is synthesized using a convergent approach involving the sequential chemoselective ligation of three peptide fragments generated through Fmoc&#8208;based solid&#8208;phase peptide synthesis. Employing this chemically robust ubiquitin probe, a previously unrecognized interaction is uncovered between Ser20&#8208;linked ubiquitin chains and spliceosome&#8208;associated factors, notably ubiquitin&#8208;specific protease 39. These findings highlight the potential of the ester&#8208;to&#8208;amide bioisosteric strategy to unlock mechanistic insights into atypical ubiquitin modifications. The approach not only circumvents the intrinsic instability of ester&#8208;linked ubiquitin chains but also provides a broadly applicable framework for dissecting their biological roles, paving the way for future discoveries in ubiquitin signaling.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/a37745f4-eb76-413c-8201-bb1caf88fc20/cbic70181-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="A Stable Bioisostere of Ester-Linked Ubiquitin Chains Enables Decoding of Protein Interactors"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ester-to-amide analog of an ester-linked ubiquitin dimer is chemically synthesized through a convergent approach involving the sequential chemoselective ligation of three peptide fragments generated through Fmoc-based solid-phase peptide synthesis. The hydrolysis-resistant ubiquitin dimer served as a chemical probe in the identification of potential reader of the ester-linked ubiquitin chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein ubiquitination is a pivotal posttranslational modification that regulates diverse biological processes depending on the type of ubiquitin chain linkage. Recently, ester-linked ubiquitin chains have been identified, yet their inherent hydrolytic instability has posed a significant challenge for biochemical investigations. In this study, a stable and isosteric amide analog of an ester-linked ubiquitin dimer, is chemically synthesized in which serine (Ser) at position 20 of the proximal ubiquitin is replaced with 2,3-diaminopropionic acid (Dap). The desired amide analog is synthesized using a convergent approach involving the sequential chemoselective ligation of three peptide fragments generated through Fmoc-based solid-phase peptide synthesis. Employing this chemically robust ubiquitin probe, a previously unrecognized interaction is uncovered between Ser20-linked ubiquitin chains and spliceosome-associated factors, notably ubiquitin-specific protease 39. These findings highlight the potential of the ester-to-amide bioisosteric strategy to unlock mechanistic insights into atypical ubiquitin modifications. The approach not only circumvents the intrinsic instability of ester-linked ubiquitin chains but also provides a broadly applicable framework for dissecting their biological roles, paving the way for future discoveries in ubiquitin signaling.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yoshinori Taguchi, 
Takuya Tomita, 
Takuma Nishizawa, 
Dai Nakamura, 
Showmitra Saha, 
Takanori Oyoshi, 
Kohei Sato, 
Nobuyuki Mase, 
Yasushi Saeki, 
Tetsuo Narumi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>A Stable Bioisostere of Ester&#8208;Linked Ubiquitin Chains Enables Decoding of Protein Interactors</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500749</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500749</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500749</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500923</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-10T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500923</guid>
         <title>Crossing Enzymatic Boundaries by Coupling BchNB with the Nitrogenase Cofactor Precursor</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Structural homology between DPOR and nitrogenase enables insertion of the L&#8208;cluster from NifEN into Pchlide&#8208;free BchNB to create a hybrid that reduces N2 and C1 substrates, revealing that BchNB naturally hosts an L&#8208;cluster binding site adjacent to the Pchlide pocket while offering insight into the shared evolution and engineering potential of these homologous enzyme systems.

The dark&#8208;operative protochlorophyllide oxidoreductase (DPOR) catalyzes the light&#8208;independent reduction of protochlorophyllide (Pchlide) to chlorophyllide (Chlide), a key step in photosynthetic pigment biosynthesis. Structurally and mechanistically related to nitrogenase, DPOR consists of a reductase (BchL) and a catalytic component (BchNB) homologous to the reductase (NifH) and catalytic component (NifDK) of Mo&#8208;nitrogenase. Structural alignment of Rhodobacter capsulatus (Rc) BchNB with Azotobacter vinelandii (Av) NifDK and the cofactor maturase NifEN reveals a conserved &#945;2&#946;2 architecture and a shared cofactor&#8208;insertion path linking their respective prosthetic&#8208;like group/cofactors (Pchlide, M&#8208;cluster, L&#8208;cluster), suggesting the possibility of generating chimeric proteins with novel reactivities. Herein, Pchlide&#8208;free RcBchNB (RcBchNBapo) is reconstituted with the L&#8208;cluster extracted from AvNifEN to yield a hybrid protein (RcBchNBL) capable of reducing N2 and C1 substrates (CN&#8722;, CO) to NH3 and hydrocarbons, respectively, in the presence of a strong reductant (EuII&#8208;DTPA). In contrast, reconstituting Pchlide&#8208;bound RcBchNB with the L&#8208;cluster yields minimal activity, indicating that Pchlide and the L&#8208;cluster compete for a common binding site, as supported by Boltz&#8208;2 modeling. These findings support the hypothesis of an intertwined evolution of photosynthetic and nitrogen&#8208;fixing enzymes and outline a framework for engineering chimeric metalloenzymes that couple light capture with nitrogenase&#8208;like catalysis in the future.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/f6dab2b3-3275-4418-ab1f-4476f42db8fe/cbic70184-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Crossing Enzymatic Boundaries by Coupling BchNB with the Nitrogenase Cofactor Precursor"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structural homology between DPOR and nitrogenase enables insertion of the L-cluster from NifEN into Pchlide-free BchNB to create a hybrid that reduces N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; substrates, revealing that BchNB naturally hosts an L-cluster binding site adjacent to the Pchlide pocket while offering insight into the shared evolution and engineering potential of these homologous enzyme systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dark-operative protochlorophyllide oxidoreductase (DPOR) catalyzes the light-independent reduction of protochlorophyllide (Pchlide) to chlorophyllide (Chlide), a key step in photosynthetic pigment biosynthesis. Structurally and mechanistically related to nitrogenase, DPOR consists of a reductase (BchL) and a catalytic component (BchNB) homologous to the reductase (NifH) and catalytic component (NifDK) of Mo-nitrogenase. Structural alignment of &lt;i&gt;Rhodobacter capsulatus&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Rc&lt;/i&gt;) BchNB with &lt;i&gt;Azotobacter vinelandii&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Av&lt;/i&gt;) NifDK and the cofactor maturase NifEN reveals a conserved &#945;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#946;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; architecture and a shared cofactor-insertion path linking their respective prosthetic-like group/cofactors (Pchlide, M-cluster, L-cluster), suggesting the possibility of generating chimeric proteins with novel reactivities. Herein, Pchlide-free &lt;i&gt;Rc&lt;/i&gt;BchNB (&lt;i&gt;Rc&lt;/i&gt;BchNB&lt;sup&gt;apo&lt;/sup&gt;) is reconstituted with the L-cluster extracted from &lt;i&gt;Av&lt;/i&gt;NifEN to yield a hybrid protein (&lt;i&gt;Rc&lt;/i&gt;BchNB&lt;sup&gt;L&lt;/sup&gt;) capable of reducing N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; substrates (CN&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt;, CO) to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; and hydrocarbons, respectively, in the presence of a strong reductant (Eu&lt;sup&gt;II&lt;/sup&gt;-DTPA). In contrast, reconstituting Pchlide-bound &lt;i&gt;Rc&lt;/i&gt;BchNB with the L-cluster yields minimal activity, indicating that Pchlide and the L-cluster compete for a common binding site, as supported by Boltz-2 modeling. These findings support the hypothesis of an intertwined evolution of photosynthetic and nitrogen-fixing enzymes and outline a framework for engineering chimeric metalloenzymes that couple light capture with nitrogenase-like catalysis in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Chi Chung Lee, 
Yimo Yang, 
Kamil G&#243;recki, 
Yilin Hu, 
Markus W. Ribbe
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Crossing Enzymatic Boundaries by Coupling BchNB with the Nitrogenase Cofactor Precursor</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500923</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500923</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500923</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70198</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-10T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.70198</guid>
         <title>
Correction to &#8220;Synthesis of Chemically Diverse siRNA&#8208;Lipid Conjugates Enabled by Reversible Adsorption to Solid Support (RASS)&#8221;</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description />
         <content:encoded />
         <dc:creator />
         <category>Correction</category>
         <dc:title>
Correction to &#8220;Synthesis of Chemically Diverse siRNA&#8208;Lipid Conjugates Enabled by Reversible Adsorption to Solid Support (RASS)&#8221;</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.70198</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.70198</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70198</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Correction</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500945</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-09T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500945</guid>
         <title>(&#8208;)&#8208;Epigallocatechin&#8208;3&#8208;Gallate (EGCG) Regulates the Formation of Zein&#8211;Ovalbumin Heteroprotein Complex Coacervates</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
EGCG plays a significant regulatory role in protein aggregation behavior. EGCG interacts with protein molecules, promoting conformational changes and aggregation, particularly in systems involving zein and ovalbumin. This study highlights the potential application of EGCG in the development of functional foods.

Growing interest in sustainable nutrition has improved the importance of understanding the interactions between (&#8208;)&#8208;Epigallocatechin&#8208;3&#8208;gallate (EGCG), a polyphenol in green tea, and proteins for functional food development. In this study, we investigated the regulatory effects of EGCG on the aggregation behavior of zein, ovalbumin, and their complexes. The addition of EGCG at 100 &#956;g mL&#8722;1 led to significant changes in particle sizes of zein, ovalbumin, and zein&#8208;ovalbumin complexes, increasing them from 215.6, 3485.3, and 2081.0&#8201;nm to 4822.3, 7857.0, and 5895.7&#8201;nm, respectively. The zeta potentials of these samples decreased from 8.4, &#8722;2.6, and 5.0&#8201;mV to &#8722;5.3, &#8722;0.66, and 2.13&#8201;mV, respectively, indicating a reduction in net surface charges and promotion of protein aggregation. UV&#8211;vis absorption spectroscopy revealed hyperchromic effects and blue shifts upon EGCG addition, suggesting conformational changes. Molecular dynamics simulations further revealed that EGCG contributed to the structural stabilization of both individual proteins and their complexes by reinforcing hydrophobic and electrostatic contacts at the molecular interface. These findings provide molecular&#8208;level insights into the regulatory role of EGCG in protein assembly and offer guidance for the rational design of plant&#8208;animal protein complexes with tailored functional properties for food applications.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/1681cf1d-0fa9-4fe9-b200-25655cec0e8a/cbic70185-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="(-)-Epigallocatechin-3-Gallate (EGCG) Regulates the Formation of Zein&#8211;Ovalbumin Heteroprotein Complex Coacervates"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EGCG plays a significant regulatory role in protein aggregation behavior. EGCG interacts with protein molecules, promoting conformational changes and aggregation, particularly in systems involving zein and ovalbumin. This study highlights the potential application of EGCG in the development of functional foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing interest in sustainable nutrition has improved the importance of understanding the interactions between (-)-Epigallocatechin-3-gallate (EGCG), a polyphenol in green tea, and proteins for functional food development. In this study, we investigated the regulatory effects of EGCG on the aggregation behavior of zein, ovalbumin, and their complexes. The addition of EGCG at 100 &#956;g mL&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; led to significant changes in particle sizes of zein, ovalbumin, and zein-ovalbumin complexes, increasing them from 215.6, 3485.3, and 2081.0&#8201;nm to 4822.3, 7857.0, and 5895.7&#8201;nm, respectively. The zeta potentials of these samples decreased from 8.4, &#8722;2.6, and 5.0&#8201;mV to &#8722;5.3, &#8722;0.66, and 2.13&#8201;mV, respectively, indicating a reduction in net surface charges and promotion of protein aggregation. UV&#8211;vis absorption spectroscopy revealed hyperchromic effects and blue shifts upon EGCG addition, suggesting conformational changes. Molecular dynamics simulations further revealed that EGCG contributed to the structural stabilization of both individual proteins and their complexes by reinforcing hydrophobic and electrostatic contacts at the molecular interface. These findings provide molecular-level insights into the regulatory role of EGCG in protein assembly and offer guidance for the rational design of plant-animal protein complexes with tailored functional properties for food applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Min Huang, 
Jiayi Han, 
Hao Li, 
Junhao Lin, 
Qingbo Jiao, 
Zexing Cao, 
Qunfang Lei, 
Wenjun Fang, 
Gerui Ren, 
Zhijun Song, 
Ying Zheng, 
Ruibo Wu, 
Hujun Xie
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>(&#8208;)&#8208;Epigallocatechin&#8208;3&#8208;Gallate (EGCG) Regulates the Formation of Zein&#8211;Ovalbumin Heteroprotein Complex Coacervates</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500945</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500945</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500945</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500733</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-09T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500733</guid>
         <title>Selection and Characterization of SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 Spike Binding Clickmers</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Split&#8208;combine click&#8208;systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment against wild&#8208;type SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 spike glycoprotein yields benzofuran&#8208; and indole&#8208;functionalized DNA aptamers (clickmers). These clickmers retain specific binding to multiple variants with nanomolar affinity, and the 31&#8201;nt indole&#8208;functionalized truncate T2 retains binding to Omicron, highlighting the versatility of the platform for diagnostic aptamers.

Expanding the chemical repertoire of canonical nucleotides is key to unlocking the full functional potential of aptamers for diagnostic use. Herein, click&#8208;systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment (SELEX) is employed to generate chemically modified DNA aptamers, termed clickmers, that target the SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 spike (CoV2&#8208;S) glycoprotein. Two independent split&#8208;combine selection strategies yield distinct clickmer families functionalized with benzofuran or indole moieties. Lead candidates (BF1 and N2) demonstrate nanomolar affinity for wild&#8208;type CoV2&#8208;S and maintain binding to multiple variants, including Alpha, Delta, and Mu, as validated by flow cytometry, surface plasmon resonance, and microscale thermophoresis. Structure&#8211;function analysis reveals essential click&#8208;in positions for both full&#8208;length clickmers and a truncated N2 variant, as short as 31 nucleotides, which displays increased binding to the Omicron variant. These results highlight the versatility of the click&#8208;SELEX platform and exemplify its successful application to a clinically relevant target, advancing previous developments in the field.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/9e1941e1-6171-45ae-bc36-8b5083f631a3/cbic70188-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Selection and Characterization of SARS-CoV-2 Spike Binding Clickmers"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Split-combine click-systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment against wild-type SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein yields benzofuran- and indole-functionalized DNA aptamers (clickmers). These clickmers retain specific binding to multiple variants with nanomolar affinity, and the 31&#8201;nt indole-functionalized truncate T2 retains binding to Omicron, highlighting the versatility of the platform for diagnostic aptamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expanding the chemical repertoire of canonical nucleotides is key to unlocking the full functional potential of aptamers for diagnostic use. Herein, click-systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment (SELEX) is employed to generate chemically modified DNA aptamers, termed clickmers, that target the SARS-CoV-2 spike (CoV2-S) glycoprotein. Two independent split-combine selection strategies yield distinct clickmer families functionalized with benzofuran or indole moieties. Lead candidates (BF1 and N2) demonstrate nanomolar affinity for wild-type CoV2-S and maintain binding to multiple variants, including Alpha, Delta, and Mu, as validated by flow cytometry, surface plasmon resonance, and microscale thermophoresis. Structure&#8211;function analysis reveals essential click-in positions for both full-length clickmers and a truncated N2 variant, as short as 31 nucleotides, which displays increased binding to the Omicron variant. These results highlight the versatility of the click-SELEX platform and exemplify its successful application to a clinically relevant target, advancing previous developments in the field.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Nima Moradzadeh, 
Anna Jonczyk, 
Anton Schmitz, 
Volkmar Fieberg, 
Laia Civit, 
Juli&#225;n Valero, 
Michael Famulok, 
G&#252;nter Mayer
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Selection and Characterization of SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 Spike Binding Clickmers</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500733</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500733</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500733</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500775</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-09T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500775</guid>
         <title>3D Cryogel Composites of Modified Purine Derivative as Osteoinductive Agents for Bone Pathologies</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The process of osteogenic differentiation of mouse myoblast C2C12 cells and pre&#8208;osteoblast MC3T3E1 cells following in vitro treatment with a purine derivative has been studied. As evidenced by elevated alkaline phosphatase activity and calcium deposition, this process results in the production of bone&#8208;forming cells. This highlights the potential of the compound in promoting bone cell differentiation and mineralization.

Purines and their receptors play a role in the regulation of stem cell survival, proliferation, and differentiation. They are responsible for the osteogenic differentiation of stem cells by activating many signaling pathways and enhancing the expression of different osteogenic factors, including bone morphogenetic proteins, runt&#8208;related transcription factor 3, alkaline phosphatase (ALP), etc. Here, a 2,6,9&#8208;trisubstituted adenine derivative is reported, with negligible cytotoxicity and potent osteogenic potential as demonstrated with mouse myoblast (C2C12 cells) and murine preosteoblasts (MC3T3E1 cells). Osteogenic activity of the derivative (Compound 1) is supported by increased expression of ALP and enhanced calcium deposition observed with alizarin staining within cells. Thus, the reported adenine derivatives can serve as potential therapeutics for bone fractures as an injectable therapeutic opening avenue for cell&#8208;free therapy.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/f12f1f5d-fa7d-4282-8949-b6fdc97b4f45/cbic70190-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="3D Cryogel Composites of Modified Purine Derivative as Osteoinductive Agents for Bone Pathologies"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of osteogenic differentiation of mouse myoblast C2C12 cells and pre-osteoblast MC3T3E1 cells following &lt;i&gt;in vitro&lt;/i&gt; treatment with a purine derivative has been studied. As evidenced by elevated alkaline phosphatase activity and calcium deposition, this process results in the production of bone-forming cells. This highlights the potential of the compound in promoting bone cell differentiation and mineralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purines and their receptors play a role in the regulation of stem cell survival, proliferation, and differentiation. They are responsible for the osteogenic differentiation of stem cells by activating many signaling pathways and enhancing the expression of different osteogenic factors, including bone morphogenetic proteins, runt-related transcription factor 3, alkaline phosphatase (ALP), etc. Here, a 2,6,9-trisubstituted adenine derivative is reported, with negligible cytotoxicity and potent osteogenic potential as demonstrated with mouse myoblast (C2C12 cells) and murine preosteoblasts (MC3T3E1 cells). Osteogenic activity of the derivative (Compound &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;) is supported by increased expression of ALP and enhanced calcium deposition observed with alizarin staining within cells. Thus, the reported adenine derivatives can serve as potential therapeutics for bone fractures as an injectable therapeutic opening avenue for cell-free therapy.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Rakhi Bormon, 
Ekta Srivastava, 
Deepshikha Tewari, 
Ashok Kumar, 
Sandeep Verma
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>3D Cryogel Composites of Modified Purine Derivative as Osteoinductive Agents for Bone Pathologies</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500775</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500775</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500775</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500804</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-09T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500804</guid>
         <title>Library&#8208;on&#8208;Library Intercellular Labeling for Selection of Biotin Ligase and Acceptor Peptides</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The library&#8208;on&#8208;library selection platform first identifies novel target peptides via intercellular trans&#8208;biotinylation, followed by the selection of matched enzyme variants through SpyTag&#8211;SpyCatcher&#8208;mediated cis&#8208;biotinylation. Using Escherichia coli biotin ligase and its acceptor peptide as a model system for site&#8208;specific conjugation, this method provides a proof of principle for the coevolution of enzyme&#8211;peptide pairs with tunable activity.

Library&#8208;on&#8208;library (LOL) selection screens combinatorial libraries to generate new protein pairs. Previously, LOL selection has only been applied to stable protein&#8211;protein interactions. To extend LOL to transient enzyme&#8211;substrate pairs, a generalizable sequential LOL trans&#8208; and cis&#8208;labeling platform is developed, and a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept selection is performed on Escherichia coli biotin ligase (BirA) and its acceptor peptide (AP). Using yeast surface display, AP mutant libraries are selected against BirA mutant libraries to identify AP variants trans&#8208;biotinylated by BirA mutants. Matched BirA mutants are subsequently enriched via the SpyTag&#8211;SpyCatcher&#8208;mediated cis&#8208;labeling platform. This represents the first demonstration of enzyme&#8211;peptide substrate LOL selection and offers a versatile framework for engineering new enzyme&#8211;peptide substrate pairs with varied activities.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/bbcbf38b-0ce8-4b4b-a53d-3aac1a411c0a/cbic70187-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Library-on-Library Intercellular Labeling for Selection of Biotin Ligase and Acceptor Peptides"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library-on-library selection platform first identifies novel target peptides via intercellular &lt;i&gt;trans&lt;/i&gt;-biotinylation, followed by the selection of matched enzyme variants through SpyTag&#8211;SpyCatcher-mediated &lt;i&gt;cis&lt;/i&gt;-biotinylation. Using &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; biotin ligase and its acceptor peptide as a model system for site-specific conjugation, this method provides a proof of principle for the coevolution of enzyme&#8211;peptide pairs with tunable activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Library-on-library (LOL) selection screens combinatorial libraries to generate new protein pairs. Previously, LOL selection has only been applied to stable protein&#8211;protein interactions. To extend LOL to transient enzyme&#8211;substrate pairs, a generalizable sequential LOL &lt;i&gt;trans&lt;/i&gt;- and &lt;i&gt;cis&lt;/i&gt;-labeling platform is developed, and a proof-of-concept selection is performed on &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; biotin ligase (BirA) and its acceptor peptide (AP). Using yeast surface display, AP mutant libraries are selected against BirA mutant libraries to identify AP variants &lt;i&gt;trans&lt;/i&gt;-biotinylated by BirA mutants. Matched BirA mutants are subsequently enriched via the SpyTag&#8211;SpyCatcher-mediated &lt;i&gt;cis&lt;/i&gt;-labeling platform. This represents the first demonstration of enzyme&#8211;peptide substrate LOL selection and offers a versatile framework for engineering new enzyme&#8211;peptide substrate pairs with varied activities.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Benya Lakkanasirorat, 
Phatipon Kongkamnead, 
Rawiporn Amornloetwattana, 
Pansa Leejareon, 
Chayasith Uttamapinant, 
Wenjing Wang
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Library&#8208;on&#8208;Library Intercellular Labeling for Selection of Biotin Ligase and Acceptor Peptides</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500804</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500804</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500804</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500833</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500833</guid>
         <title>Three Recent para&#8208;Nitrobenzyl&#8208;Based Hypoxia Probes: Promising Directions for Sensitivity, Reversibility, or Near&#8208;IR Emission</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Recent progresses on nitroaromatics&#8208;based hypoxia probes address the challenges with respect to sensitivity, reversibility, and in&#8201;vivo capability.

Hypoxia bioimaging attracts tremendous attention due to its profound implications in diagnosis of a range of pathological conditions. Nitroaromatics&#8208;based fluorescent probes are the most popular approach to tackle this problem. Despite intensive efforts of the field over the past 15&#8201;years and the development of a range of such probes, three challenges are still not addressed, i.e., highly sensitive probes necessitating a one&#8208;electron reduction, real&#8208;time monitoring probes with reversible sensing capability, and near&#8208;infrared probes with in&#8201;vivo imaging potentials. Three groups have recently reported notable progresses regarding these challenges, which may spur another wave of development along this line of research and meet the need of real&#8208;world applications from researchers and doctors.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/b2baf6ec-c3ad-4197-a982-ad408b769864/cbic70182-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Three Recent para-Nitrobenzyl-Based Hypoxia Probes: Promising Directions for Sensitivity, Reversibility, or Near-IR Emission"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent progresses on nitroaromatics-based hypoxia probes address the challenges with respect to sensitivity, reversibility, and in&#8201;vivo capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypoxia bioimaging attracts tremendous attention due to its profound implications in diagnosis of a range of pathological conditions. Nitroaromatics-based fluorescent probes are the most popular approach to tackle this problem. Despite intensive efforts of the field over the past 15&#8201;years and the development of a range of such probes, three challenges are still not addressed, i.e., highly sensitive probes necessitating a one-electron reduction, real-time monitoring probes with reversible sensing capability, and near-infrared probes with in&#8201;vivo imaging potentials. Three groups have recently reported notable progresses regarding these challenges, which may spur another wave of development along this line of research and meet the need of real-world applications from researchers and doctors.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yuyang Zhang, 
Leilei Li, 
Youjun Yang, 
Ziqian Zhang
</dc:creator>
         <category>Highlight</category>
         <dc:title>Three Recent para&#8208;Nitrobenzyl&#8208;Based Hypoxia Probes: Promising Directions for Sensitivity, Reversibility, or Near&#8208;IR Emission</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500833</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500833</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500833</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Highlight</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500262</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500262</guid>
         <title>Synthesis of Lipid&#8208;Conjugated Heparan Sulfate Mimetics and Their Effect on Complement Inhibition</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Three function&#8208;spacer&#8208;lipid constructs containing sulfated maltose in monomeric or clustered (dimeric or trimeric) form are synthesized as complement inhibitors. The conjugation of maltose clusters with spacer&#8208;armed lipid is carried out with the use of CuAAC click reaction.

Heavily sulfated clusters of maltose are designed as mimetics of heparan sulfate (HS), exhibiting diverse biological activity properties of HS. Herein, the synthesis of three function&#8208;spacer&#8208;lipid (FSL) constructs containing mono, di, and tri sulfated maltoses is reported. FSLs are a class of synthetic glycolipids, the key features of which are simplicity of synthesis and capacity to integrate into cell membranes with sustained retention. A copper&#8208;catalyzed azide&#8211;alkyne cycloaddition click reaction is employed for the conjugation of the sulfated maltose entities with the respective spacer&#8208;lipid block because acylation with activated esters failed to provide the desired products. One FSL construct, featuring a single sulfated maltose unit conjugated to the lipid, demonstrated dose&#8208;dependent inhibition of complement activation in a cellular system, with maximal efficacy observed at 15 &#181;g mL&#8722;1. These findings highlight the potential of FSL&#8208;based HS mimetics for modulating immune responses.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/94b245ea-cf40-4be1-ba40-d93c5427c64d/cbic70168-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Synthesis of Lipid-Conjugated Heparan Sulfate Mimetics and Their Effect on Complement Inhibition"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three function-spacer-lipid constructs containing sulfated maltose in monomeric or clustered (dimeric or trimeric) form are synthesized as complement inhibitors. The conjugation of maltose clusters with spacer-armed lipid is carried out with the use of CuAAC click reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heavily sulfated clusters of maltose are designed as mimetics of heparan sulfate (HS), exhibiting diverse biological activity properties of HS. Herein, the synthesis of three function-spacer-lipid (FSL) constructs containing mono, di, and tri sulfated maltoses is reported. FSLs are a class of synthetic glycolipids, the key features of which are simplicity of synthesis and capacity to integrate into cell membranes with sustained retention. A copper-catalyzed azide&#8211;alkyne cycloaddition click reaction is employed for the conjugation of the sulfated maltose entities with the respective spacer-lipid block because acylation with activated esters failed to provide the desired products. One FSL construct, featuring a single sulfated maltose unit conjugated to the lipid, demonstrated dose-dependent inhibition of complement activation in a cellular system, with maximal efficacy observed at 15 &#181;g mL&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt;. These findings highlight the potential of FSL-based HS mimetics for modulating immune responses.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Ivan M. Ryzhov, 
Alexander B. Tuzikov, 
Inna S. Popova, 
Ye Li, 
Neda Salimi&#8208;Afjani, 
Sam Spijkers&#8208;Shaw, 
Phillip M. Rendle, 
Robert Rieben, 
Nicolai V. Bovin, 
Olga V. Zubkova
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Synthesis of Lipid&#8208;Conjugated Heparan Sulfate Mimetics and Their Effect on Complement Inhibition</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500262</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500262</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500262</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500312</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500312</guid>
         <title>Comparative Binding Studies of the Chelators Methylolanthanin and Rhodopetrobactin B to Lanthanides and Ferric Iron</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The synthesis and the investigation of the lanthanide (Ln) and Fe&#8208;binding properties of the putative lanthanophore methylolanthanin (MLL) and the siderophore rhodopetrobactin B (RPB B) are reported. While both chelators bind Lns, they unexpectedly precipitate with Lns under biologically relevant conditions and thereby challenge the proposed classic siderophore&#8208;like Ln uptake.

The question of lanthanide (Ln) uptake in Ln&#8208;using bacteria has gained a lot of attention in recent years, and the existence of specific Ln&#8208;binding metallophores, termed lanthanophores, has been postulated. Here, the recently isolated metallophore methylolanthanin (MLL), which is shown to be involved in Ln metabolism of Methylobacterium extorquens AM1 along the structurally related siderophore rhodopetrobactin B (RPB B), is investigated. The total synthesis of both chelators as well as Ln&#8208;binding investigations employing a multitude of spectroscopic methods is reported. Compared to MLL, RPB B has a higher binding affinity for Fe3+. Unexpectedly, both metallophores seem to precipitate Lns under biologically relevant conditions (pH and concentration range). Therefore, a solubility product of &#8722;12.07 &#177; 0.24 mol2&#8201;L&#8722;2 for the precipitated Eu3+&#8208;MLL complex is reported. Furthermore, a combination of single&#8208;cell inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry and Liquid Chromatography&#8208;Mass Spectrometry (LC&#8208;MS) analysis of bacterial supernatant to investigate the Nd accumulation as well as MLL secretion under Fe limitation in M. extorquens AM1 is used. Finally, ion mobility spectrometry&#8208;mass spectrometry and quantum chemical calculations are used to investigate the RPB B and MLL complexation in the gas phase with Fe3+ and all rare earth elements (except Pm). The results challenge the classical siderophore&#8208;like Ln uptake (via simple solubilization) through MLL and underline again a potential complex interplay between Fe3+ and Ln3+ in microbial Ln uptake.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/eb14bb42-d31b-402f-883b-8d6dc704d4b3/cbic70141-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Comparative Binding Studies of the Chelators Methylolanthanin and Rhodopetrobactin B to Lanthanides and Ferric Iron"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The synthesis and the investigation of the lanthanide (Ln) and Fe-binding properties of the putative lanthanophore methylolanthanin (MLL) and the siderophore rhodopetrobactin B (RPB B) are reported. While both chelators bind Lns, they unexpectedly precipitate with Lns under biologically relevant conditions and thereby challenge the proposed classic siderophore-like Ln uptake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of lanthanide (Ln) uptake in Ln-using bacteria has gained a lot of attention in recent years, and the existence of specific Ln-binding metallophores, termed lanthanophores, has been postulated. Here, the recently isolated metallophore methylolanthanin (MLL), which is shown to be involved in Ln metabolism of &lt;i&gt;Methylobacterium extorquens&lt;/i&gt; AM1 along the structurally related siderophore rhodopetrobactin B (RPB B), is investigated. The total synthesis of both chelators as well as Ln-binding investigations employing a multitude of spectroscopic methods is reported. Compared to MLL, RPB B has a higher binding affinity for Fe&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt;. Unexpectedly, both metallophores seem to precipitate Lns under biologically relevant conditions (pH and concentration range). Therefore, a solubility product of &#8722;12.07 &#177; 0.24 mol&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt; for the precipitated Eu&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt;-MLL complex is reported. Furthermore, a combination of single-cell inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry and Liquid Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry (LC-MS) analysis of bacterial supernatant to investigate the Nd accumulation as well as MLL secretion under Fe limitation in &lt;i&gt;M. extorquens&lt;/i&gt; AM1 is used. Finally, ion mobility spectrometry-mass spectrometry and quantum chemical calculations are used to investigate the RPB B and MLL complexation in the gas phase with Fe&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; and all rare earth elements (except Pm). The results challenge the classical siderophore-like Ln uptake (via simple solubilization) through MLL and underline again a potential complex interplay between Fe&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; and Ln&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; in microbial Ln uptake.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Sophie M. Gutenthaler&#8208;Tietze, 
Michael Mertens, 
Manh Tri Phi, 
Patrick Weis, 
Bj&#246;rn Drobot, 
Alexander K&#246;hrer, 
Robin Steudtner, 
Uwe Karst, 
N. Cecilia Martinez&#8208;Gomez, 
Lena J. Daumann
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Comparative Binding Studies of the Chelators Methylolanthanin and Rhodopetrobactin B to Lanthanides and Ferric Iron</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500312</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500312</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500312</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500459</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500459</guid>
         <title>&#945;&#8208;O&#8208;Glycosylation at Tyrosine 10 Promotes the Astrocyte Clearance of Amyloid&#8208;&#946; Peptide 1&#8211;42</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Tyr10 O&#8208;glycosylation stabilizes A&#946;42 oligomers, promotes the endocytosis by astrocytes via TLR4 and SR&#8208;A, improves intracellular degradation and IDE secretion, and ultimately rescues spatial cognitive deficits in AD&#8208;like mice, uncovering novel role of Tyr10 O&#8208;glycan in regulating A&#946; clearance in the brain.

Therapies targeting amyloid &#946; (A&#946;), especially promoting A&#946; clearance, have attracted increasing attention in treating Alzheimer's disease (AD). However, the regulatory factors in A&#946; metabolism remain poorly understood. Herein, three homogeneously glycosylated A&#946;42 peptides are utilized to explore the impacts of Tyr10 O&#8208;glycosylation on A&#946; clearance in astrocytes. Based on various biochemical and cellular assays, it is shown that the introduced &#945;&#8208;O&#8208;glycan stabilizes the A&#946; oligomers and enhances A&#946;42 endocytosis and autophagy in astrocytes, which ultimately promotes the intracellular degradation of A&#946;42 and the secretion of A&#946;&#8208;degrading enzymes. Particularly, a disaccharide, Gal&#946;1&#8208;3GalNAc, exhibits the most substantial clearance&#8208;enhancing effect. Moreover, experiments with AD&#8208;like model mice show protective effects from the disaccharide modification in alleviating A&#946;42&#8208;induced impairment of spatial cognitive performance. Thus, beyond showing the influences induced by particular O&#8208;glycosylation on A&#946;42 degradation, the study provides implications of a possible role of Tyr10 O&#8208;glycan in regulating A&#946; clearance in the brain.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/9d5f2f87-0705-4505-b00b-d8658e81726d/cbic70156-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="&#945;-O-Glycosylation at Tyrosine 10 Promotes the Astrocyte Clearance of Amyloid-&#946; Peptide 1&#8211;42"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tyr10 &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-glycosylation stabilizes A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;42&lt;/sub&gt; oligomers, promotes the endocytosis by astrocytes via TLR4 and SR-A, improves intracellular degradation and IDE secretion, and ultimately rescues spatial cognitive deficits in AD-like mice, uncovering novel role of Tyr10 &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-glycan in regulating A&#946; clearance in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapies targeting amyloid &#946; (A&#946;), especially promoting A&#946; clearance, have attracted increasing attention in treating Alzheimer's disease (AD). However, the regulatory factors in A&#946; metabolism remain poorly understood. Herein, three homogeneously glycosylated A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;42&lt;/sub&gt; peptides are utilized to explore the impacts of Tyr10 &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-glycosylation on A&#946; clearance in astrocytes. Based on various biochemical and cellular assays, it is shown that the introduced &#945;-&lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-glycan stabilizes the A&#946; oligomers and enhances A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;42&lt;/sub&gt; endocytosis and autophagy in astrocytes, which ultimately promotes the intracellular degradation of A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;42&lt;/sub&gt; and the secretion of A&#946;-degrading enzymes. Particularly, a disaccharide, Gal&#946;1-3GalNAc, exhibits the most substantial clearance-enhancing effect. Moreover, experiments with AD-like model mice show protective effects from the disaccharide modification in alleviating A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;42&lt;/sub&gt;-induced impairment of spatial cognitive performance. Thus, beyond showing the influences induced by particular &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-glycosylation on A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;42&lt;/sub&gt; degradation, the study provides implications of a possible role of Tyr10 &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-glycan in regulating A&#946; clearance in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Lu Huang, 
Dangliang Liu, 
Qijia Wei, 
Changdong He, 
Jun Zhang, 
Suwei Dong
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>&#945;&#8208;O&#8208;Glycosylation at Tyrosine 10 Promotes the Astrocyte Clearance of Amyloid&#8208;&#946; Peptide 1&#8211;42</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500459</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500459</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500459</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500484</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500484</guid>
         <title>Expanding the Therapeutic Potential of NUIG4: A Multifunctional Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for Dual Anticancer and Antibacterial Drug Delivery</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A multifunctional MOF, NUIG4, enables the codelivery of anticancer drugs (DOX and 5&#8208;FU) and antibiotics (TET, INH, PYZ), achieving high loading efficiency and pH&#8208;triggered release while preserving drug bioactivity.

Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as highly tunable materials for targeted and controlled drug delivery. In this study, NUIG4 is presented as a multifunctional MOF&#8208;based carrier capable of encapsulating both anticancer and antimicrobial therapeutics. NUIG4 exhibits high&#8208;surface area, water stability, and suitable porosity, supporting the efficient loading of a range of drug molecules. Its dual anticancer drug delivery performance is assessed using doxorubicin (DOX) and 5&#8208;fluorouracil (5&#8208;FU). Co&#8208;loading studies demonstrate successful encapsulation of both drugs and synergistic cytotoxicity in MDA&#8208;MB&#8208;231 breast cancer cells, indicating that the MOF preserves and potentially enhances the therapeutic efficacy of both drugs. Furthermore, NUIG4 is assessed as a carrier for antibiotics, including tetracycline (TET), isoniazid (INH), and pyrazinamide (PYZ), demonstrating sustained, pH&#8208;responsive release. TET@NUIG4 retain potent antimicrobial activity against S. aureus and E. coli, with minimum inhibition concentration values matching those of the free drug, while INH and PYZ highlight NUIG4's potential for tuberculosis&#8208;directed delivery. Spectroscopic analyses and kinetic modeling support a chemisorption&#8208;based mechanism and efficient, sustained release. These findings establish NUIG4 as one of the few MOFs reported, capable of both dual anticancer drug codelivery and antibiotic encapsulation and release, suitable for targeting both cancer and infectious diseases.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/c329d821-80f8-4265-b97a-aa50e9cce725/cbic70186-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Expanding the Therapeutic Potential of NUIG4: A Multifunctional Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for Dual Anticancer and Antibacterial Drug Delivery"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multifunctional MOF, NUIG4, enables the codelivery of anticancer drugs (DOX and 5-FU) and antibiotics (TET, INH, PYZ), achieving high loading efficiency and pH-triggered release while preserving drug bioactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as highly tunable materials for targeted and controlled drug delivery. In this study, NUIG4 is presented as a multifunctional MOF-based carrier capable of encapsulating both anticancer and antimicrobial therapeutics. NUIG4 exhibits high-surface area, water stability, and suitable porosity, supporting the efficient loading of a range of drug molecules. Its dual anticancer drug delivery performance is assessed using doxorubicin (DOX) and 5-fluorouracil (5-FU). Co-loading studies demonstrate successful encapsulation of both drugs and synergistic cytotoxicity in MDA-MB-231 breast cancer cells, indicating that the MOF preserves and potentially enhances the therapeutic efficacy of both drugs. Furthermore, NUIG4 is assessed as a carrier for antibiotics, including tetracycline (TET), isoniazid (INH), and pyrazinamide (PYZ), demonstrating sustained, pH-responsive release. TET@NUIG4 retain potent antimicrobial activity against &lt;i&gt;S. aureus and E. coli&lt;/i&gt;, with minimum inhibition concentration values matching those of the free drug, while INH and PYZ highlight NUIG4's potential for tuberculosis-directed delivery. Spectroscopic analyses and kinetic modeling support a chemisorption-based mechanism and efficient, sustained release. These findings establish NUIG4 as one of the few MOFs reported, capable of both dual anticancer drug codelivery and antibiotic encapsulation and release, suitable for targeting both cancer and infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Manal Alrashidi, 
Katie McHugh, 
Liam Jordan, 
Darragh McHugh, 
Sha Li, 
Constantinos G. Efthymiou, 
Dayle Leonard, 
Wenming Tong, 
Pau Farras, 
R&#243;is&#237;n Dwyer, 
Aoife Boyd, 
Constantina Papatriantafyllopoulou
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Expanding the Therapeutic Potential of NUIG4: A Multifunctional Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for Dual Anticancer and Antibacterial Drug Delivery</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500484</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500484</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500484</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500547</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500547</guid>
         <title>Simultaneous Visualization of Distinct Posttranslational Modification States of &#946;&#8208;Catenin Using Genetic Code Expansion and Click Chemistry</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A method to visualize, within the same cell, three distinct posttranslational forms of &#946;&#8208;catenin: wild&#8208;type, phosphomimetic (T41E), and synthetic T41C&#8208;GlcNAc, using genetic code expansion and fluorescence microscopy is developed. This strategy reveals how modifications at T41 alter &#946;&#8208;catenin localization and stability.

A novel strategy based on genetic code expansion combined with click chemistry for the simultaneous visualization of distinct posttranslational modification (PTM) states of a single protein within living cells. As a model, it is focused on threonine 41 (T41) of &#946;&#8208;catenin, a regulatory hotspot implicated in epithelial cancers and known to be phosphorylated, O&#8208;GlcNAcylated, or left unmodified. Using site&#8208;specific incorporation of the unnatural phenylselenocysteine, a &#946;&#8208;catenin&#8208;EGFP fusion protein is engineered allowing selective installation of a S&#8208;GlcNAc moiety via oxidative elimination and thiol&#8208;Michael ligation. Additional &#946;&#8208;catenin variants, phosphomimetic T41E&#8208;mCherry and wild&#8208;type&#8208;blue fluorescent protein fusions, are produced to represent other PTM states. All constructs are successfully introduced into Hep3B and HeLa cells by lipofection or TAT&#8208;mediated transduction. Fluorescence microscopy revealed distinct subcellular localization profiles for each PTM form. Notably, the S&#8208;GlcNAcylated &#946;&#8208;catenin exhibited enhanced resistance to proteasomal degradation, consistent with known roles of O&#8208;GlcNAcylation in protein stability. This approach provides a versatile platform to functionally probe PTMs in a comparative, cell&#8208;based context.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/65cc20b0-8087-44cc-8420-5cee3a18339a/cbic70157-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Simultaneous Visualization of Distinct Posttranslational Modification States of &#946;-Catenin Using Genetic Code Expansion and Click Chemistry"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A method to visualize, within the same cell, three distinct posttranslational forms of &#946;-catenin: wild-type, phosphomimetic (T41E), and synthetic T41C-GlcNAc, using genetic code expansion and fluorescence microscopy is developed. This strategy reveals how modifications at T41 alter &#946;-catenin localization and stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel strategy based on genetic code expansion combined with click chemistry for the simultaneous visualization of distinct posttranslational modification (PTM) states of a single protein within living cells. As a model, it is focused on threonine 41 (T41) of &#946;-catenin, a regulatory hotspot implicated in epithelial cancers and known to be phosphorylated, &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-GlcNAcylated, or left unmodified. Using site-specific incorporation of the unnatural phenylselenocysteine, a &#946;-catenin-EGFP fusion protein is engineered allowing selective installation of a &lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;-GlcNAc moiety via oxidative elimination and thiol-Michael ligation. Additional &#946;-catenin variants, phosphomimetic T41E-mCherry and wild-type-blue fluorescent protein fusions, are produced to represent other PTM states. All constructs are successfully introduced into Hep3B and HeLa cells by lipofection or TAT-mediated transduction. Fluorescence microscopy revealed distinct subcellular localization profiles for each PTM form. Notably, the &lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;-GlcNAcylated &#946;-catenin exhibited enhanced resistance to proteasomal degradation, consistent with known roles of &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-GlcNAcylation in protein stability. This approach provides a versatile platform to functionally probe PTMs in a comparative, cell-based context.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Christer Abou Anny, 
S&#233;bastien Nouaille, 
Isabelle Huvent, 
Corentin Spriet, 
C&#233;line Schulz, 
Fabrice Bray, 
R&#233;gis Faur&#233;, 
Tony Lefebvre, 
Christophe Biot
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Simultaneous Visualization of Distinct Posttranslational Modification States of &#946;&#8208;Catenin Using Genetic Code Expansion and Click Chemistry</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500547</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500547</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500547</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500614</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500614</guid>
         <title>
Computational Analysis Uncovering Contrasts in G&#8208;Quadruplex Propensity and Aptamer Enrichment in SELEX&#8208;Derived Libraries</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Aptamer selection&#8208;derived RNA libraries targeting a DNA G&#8208;quadruplex are profiled by both sequence abundance and three G&#8208;quadruplex&#160;(G4)&#8208;prediction tools. High G4 scores failed to match enrichment or binding, revealing that current G4 predictors alone cannot reliably prioritize functional aptamers and must be combined with abundance&#8208;based and experimental validation workflows.

G&#8208;quadruplexes (G4s) are noncanonical nucleic acid structures with biological and therapeutic significance, and they are found in many aptamer sequences. Using c&#8208;kit 1 G4 DNA as a target, systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment (SELEX) has been carried out using an RNA library, resulting in G4&#8208;rich aptamers. Herein, this article investigates the relationship between predicted G4&#8208;forming potential and aptamer enrichment by analyzing high&#8208;throughput SELEX libraries using three G4 prediction tools: G4NN, G4Hunter, and QGRS Mapper. While the tools demonstrate strong internal consistency and overlap in identifying G4&#8208;prone sequences, their predictions show limited concordance with experimental abundance and enrichment trends across SELEX rounds. Only a small fraction of sequences display both high G4 scores and consistent enrichment. Experimental validation using electrophoretic mobility shift assays confirmed that strong predicted G4&#8208;forming sequences often lack strong binding activity, whereas highly enriched aptamers with strong binding activities may show weaker G4 signatures computationally. These findings suggest that current G4&#8208;prediction tools alone are insufficient for aptamer candidate selection and highlight the need for integrative evaluation strategies that combine structural prediction with empirical performance data.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/8e5ab5bd-5e4b-422e-8ad7-25de63483bbe/cbic70177-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="&amp;#xA;Computational Analysis Uncovering Contrasts in G-Quadruplex Propensity and Aptamer Enrichment in SELEX-Derived Libraries"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aptamer selection-derived RNA libraries targeting a DNA G-quadruplex are profiled by both sequence abundance and three G-quadruplex&#160;(G4)-prediction tools. High G4 scores failed to match enrichment or binding, revealing that current G4 predictors alone cannot reliably prioritize functional aptamers and must be combined with abundance-based and experimental validation workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G-quadruplexes (G4s) are noncanonical nucleic acid structures with biological and therapeutic significance, and they are found in many aptamer sequences. Using &lt;i&gt;c-kit 1&lt;/i&gt; G4 DNA as a target, systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment (SELEX) has been carried out using an RNA library, resulting in G4-rich aptamers. Herein, this article investigates the relationship between predicted G4-forming potential and aptamer enrichment by analyzing high-throughput SELEX libraries using three G4 prediction tools: G4NN, G4Hunter, and QGRS Mapper. While the tools demonstrate strong internal consistency and overlap in identifying G4-prone sequences, their predictions show limited concordance with experimental abundance and enrichment trends across SELEX rounds. Only a small fraction of sequences display both high G4 scores and consistent enrichment. Experimental validation using electrophoretic mobility shift assays confirmed that strong predicted G4-forming sequences often lack strong binding activity, whereas highly enriched aptamers with strong binding activities may show weaker G4 signatures computationally. These findings suggest that current G4-prediction tools alone are insufficient for aptamer candidate selection and highlight the need for integrative evaluation strategies that combine structural prediction with empirical performance data.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Gefei Liu, 
Tian&#8208;Ying Wu, 
Chun Kit Kwok, 
Juewen Liu
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>
Computational Analysis Uncovering Contrasts in G&#8208;Quadruplex Propensity and Aptamer Enrichment in SELEX&#8208;Derived Libraries</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500614</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500614</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500614</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500626</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500626</guid>
         <title>Photo&#8208;Induced Ultra&#8208;Fast Duplex Invasion Targeting Long&#8208;Range Double&#8208;Stranded DNA Using Artificial Nucleotide</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Photo&#8208;induced ultra&#8208;fast duplex invasion via ultra&#8208;fast photo&#8208;crosslinker, 3&#8208;cyanovinylcarbazole nucleoside (CNVK), aiming for fast high&#8208;efficiency invasion.

Genomic DNA stores genetic information and regulates functions of various biological processes. Genetic diseases can be caused by abnormal gene expression. Genetic manipulation requires sequence&#8208;selective recognition of double&#8208;stranded DNAs, various chemical approaches for double&#8208;duplex invasion have been developed. In the previous research, a photo&#8208;induced double&#8208;duplex invasion (pDDI) is introduced that uses artificial nucleotides, 3&#8208;cyanovinylcarbazole nucleoside (CNVK) as photo&#8208;crosslinker and 5&#8208;cyanouridine (CU) as inter&#8208;probe photo&#8208;crosslinking inhibitor. In this study, while investigating the invasion mechanism of the pDDI, the invasion independence of pDDI probes is discovered and proposed a photo&#8208;induced duplex invasion (pDI) that achieves fast invasion using only CNVK while still maintaining a high invasion efficiency. This rapid pDI approach provides a powerful new tool for site&#8208;specific manipulation of genomic DNA.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/564d70b6-8355-4dd6-a366-a656810b3f6d/cbic70128-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Photo-Induced Ultra-Fast Duplex Invasion Targeting Long-Range Double-Stranded DNA Using Artificial Nucleotide"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo-induced ultra-fast duplex invasion via ultra-fast photo-crosslinker, 3-cyanovinylcarbazole nucleoside (&lt;sup&gt;CNV&lt;/sup&gt;K), aiming for fast high-efficiency invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genomic DNA stores genetic information and regulates functions of various biological processes. Genetic diseases can be caused by abnormal gene expression. Genetic manipulation requires sequence-selective recognition of double-stranded DNAs, various chemical approaches for double-duplex invasion have been developed. In the previous research, a photo-induced double-duplex invasion (pDDI) is introduced that uses artificial nucleotides, 3-cyanovinylcarbazole nucleoside (&lt;sup&gt;CNV&lt;/sup&gt;K) as photo-crosslinker and 5-cyanouridine (&lt;sup&gt;C&lt;/sup&gt;U) as inter-probe photo-crosslinking inhibitor. In this study, while investigating the invasion mechanism of the pDDI, the invasion independence of pDDI probes is discovered and proposed a photo-induced duplex invasion (pDI) that achieves fast invasion using only &lt;sup&gt;CNV&lt;/sup&gt;K while still maintaining a high invasion efficiency. This rapid pDI approach provides a powerful new tool for site-specific manipulation of genomic DNA.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Zumila Hailili, 
Yasuha Watanabe, 
Siddhant Sethi, 
Kenzo Fujimoto
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Photo&#8208;Induced Ultra&#8208;Fast Duplex Invasion Targeting Long&#8208;Range Double&#8208;Stranded DNA Using Artificial Nucleotide</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500626</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500626</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500626</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500636</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500636</guid>
         <title>Human Protein Z as the Second Known Heme&#8208;Binding Protein from the Endogenous Blood Coagulation Inhibitor System</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Protein Z is a vitamin K&#8208;dependent anticoagulant with elusive molecular functions. Herein, it is shown that heme binds to protein Z and induces conformational changes. One histidine&#8208;based heme&#8208;binding motif is identified. High heme&#8208;binding affinity and functional effects are demonstrated on protein level. These findings shed new light on the structural and functional roles of protein Z in hemolysis&#8208;driven coagulation disorders.

Protein Z (PZ) is a vitamin&#8208;K&#8208;dependent glycoprotein that serves as an anticoagulant cofactor in blood. Although it is homologous to the serine proteases of blood coagulation, PZ has no enzymatic activity. It binds to the PZ&#8208;dependent protease inhibitor and supports inactivation of factor Xa. In addition, an inhibitory effect on thrombin is described. Clinically, changed PZ levels increase the risk for thrombosis. The related activated protein C (APC) is described as the first anticoagulant protein that binds heme under hemolytic conditions leading to its inhibition. However, the network of inhibitors of blood coagulation is still underexplored with respect to their role in heme&#8208;triggered effects and the regulation thereof. PZ seems to be an interesting candidate in this context due to its homology to APC. Using PZ&#8208;derived peptides as models for potential heme&#8208;binding sites in PZ together with in silico studies, one specific heme&#8208;binding site in PZ is identified. Binding studies on protein level demonstrate binding characteristics similar to APC. Finally, the inhibitory effect of PZ toward thrombin is increased in the presence of heme, providing also insights into a potential functional consequence of the PZ&#8211;heme interaction. In addition, the anticoagulant function of PZ is dampened in the presence of heme in an aPTT&#8208;based clotting assay, suggesting a tendency toward heme&#8208;induced prothrombotic actions. In future, this will support mapping the diverse effects of heme within blood coagulation.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/5d27749c-6af2-4d38-a6d8-eed8d16e9efa/cbic70163-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Human Protein Z as the Second Known Heme-Binding Protein from the Endogenous Blood Coagulation Inhibitor System"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein Z is a vitamin K-dependent anticoagulant with elusive molecular functions. Herein, it is shown that heme binds to protein Z and induces conformational changes. One histidine-based heme-binding motif is identified. High heme-binding affinity and functional effects are demonstrated on protein level. These findings shed new light on the structural and functional roles of protein Z in hemolysis-driven coagulation disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein Z (PZ) is a vitamin-K-dependent glycoprotein that serves as an anticoagulant cofactor in blood. Although it is homologous to the serine proteases of blood coagulation, PZ has no enzymatic activity. It binds to the PZ-dependent protease inhibitor and supports inactivation of factor Xa. In addition, an inhibitory effect on thrombin is described. Clinically, changed PZ levels increase the risk for thrombosis. The related activated protein C (APC) is described as the first anticoagulant protein that binds heme under hemolytic conditions leading to its inhibition. However, the network of inhibitors of blood coagulation is still underexplored with respect to their role in heme-triggered effects and the regulation thereof. PZ seems to be an interesting candidate in this context due to its homology to APC. Using PZ-derived peptides as models for potential heme-binding sites in PZ together with in silico studies, one specific heme-binding site in PZ is identified. Binding studies on protein level demonstrate binding characteristics similar to APC. Finally, the inhibitory effect of PZ toward thrombin is increased in the presence of heme, providing also insights into a potential functional consequence of the PZ&#8211;heme interaction. In addition, the anticoagulant function of PZ is dampened in the presence of heme in an aPTT-based clotting assay, suggesting a tendency toward heme-induced prothrombotic actions. In future, this will support mapping the diverse effects of heme within blood coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Paula Lindemann, 
Marie&#8208;T. Hopp
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Human Protein Z as the Second Known Heme&#8208;Binding Protein from the Endogenous Blood Coagulation Inhibitor System</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500636</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500636</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500636</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500667</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500667</guid>
         <title>Multifaceted Effects of a Multiple Nitric Oxide Photoreleaser and its Photoproducts on Amyloid&#8208;&#946; Aggregation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A blue light&#8208;activatable NO photodonor sequentially releases two NO molecules accompanied by two stable photoproducts, showing differentiated effects on the &#946;&#8208;amyloid aggregation.

Aberrant aggregation of &#946;&#8208;amyloid (A&#946;) peptides into insoluble fibrils is recognized as one of the hallmarks of Alzheimer's disease (AD). Among the post&#8208;translational modifications influencing A&#946; behavior, nitration and nitrosation by nitric oxide (NO) derivatives play a key role, though their impact on aggregation and toxicity remains unclear. This contribution explores the effects on A&#946; aggregation induced by an NO photodonor (NOPD) releasing two NO molecules via a stepwise mechanism under the control of visible blue light. Significant reduction of protein aggregation is observed when a considerable amount NO (&#8776;120&#8201;&#181;M) is photoreleased during the early stages of the protein aggregation. In contrast, long&#8208;term release of a similar NO concentration is ineffective. On the other hand, proaggregative effect is induced by the NOPD kept in the dark. The stable photoproducts formed after the release of the first and the second molecule of NO also show a protein aggregation inhibitory effect both individually and in combination. Dynamic simulation studies are also reported to shed light on the binding of NOPD and its photoproducts with key A&#946;1&#8211;40 residues.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e7d3a17b-1f22-40bf-abb4-73e5bb9c7145/cbic70162-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Multifaceted Effects of a Multiple Nitric Oxide Photoreleaser and its Photoproducts on Amyloid-&#946; Aggregation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blue light-activatable NO photodonor sequentially releases two NO molecules accompanied by two stable photoproducts, showing differentiated effects on the &#946;-amyloid aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant aggregation of &#946;-amyloid (A&#946;) peptides into insoluble fibrils is recognized as one of the hallmarks of Alzheimer's disease (AD). Among the post-translational modifications influencing A&#946; behavior, nitration and nitrosation by nitric oxide (NO) derivatives play a key role, though their impact on aggregation and toxicity remains unclear. This contribution explores the effects on A&#946; aggregation induced by an NO photodonor (NOPD) releasing two NO molecules via a stepwise mechanism under the control of visible blue light. Significant reduction of protein aggregation is observed when a considerable amount NO (&#8776;120&#8201;&#181;M) is photoreleased during the early stages of the protein aggregation. In contrast, long-term release of a similar NO concentration is ineffective. On the other hand, proaggregative effect is induced by the NOPD kept in the dark. The stable photoproducts formed after the release of the first and the second molecule of NO also show a protein aggregation inhibitory effect both individually and in combination. Dynamic simulation studies are also reported to shed light on the binding of NOPD and its photoproducts with key A&#946;&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;40&lt;/sub&gt; residues.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Francesca Laneri, 
Cristina Parisi, 
Salvatore Sortino
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Multifaceted Effects of a Multiple Nitric Oxide Photoreleaser and its Photoproducts on Amyloid&#8208;&#946; Aggregation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500667</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500667</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500667</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500669</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500669</guid>
         <title>A Robust Bioprocess for the Global Incorporation of Noncanonical Amino Acids in Auxotrophic Hosts Produces Labeled Proteins at the Gram Scale</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A robust bioprocess enables global incorporation of noncanonical amino acids in both shake flask and bioreactor cultures, producing gram&#8208;per&#8208;liter titers of efficiently labeled proteins. A versatile Escherichia coli BL21(DE3) auxotroph platform supports broad compatibility with various noncanonical amino acids and target proteins, facilitating flexible and scalable designer protein production.

This study presents a robust bioprocess for the global incorporation of noncanonical amino acids (ncAAs) into proteins, enabling gram&#8208;scale production in auxotrophic Escherichia coli strains. The two&#8208;phase approach adapts from shake flask to bioreactor cultures and relies on cost&#8208;effective synthetic minimal media with glucose as the sole carbon source and yeast extract as an amino acid supply. It supports both external ncAA supplementation and in situ biosynthesis. A versatile E. coli BL21(DE3) auxotroph platform ensures broad ncAA and protein compatibility. Model proteins, such as a thermophilic lipase (TTL) and an oxidoreductase are labeled with biosynthesized norleucine (Nle), synthetic fluoroprolines, and fluorophenylalanine. Under optimal conditions, we achieved titers of up to 2&#8201;g&#8201;L&#8722;1 with near&#8208;quantitative incorporation. To demonstrate the utility of the bioprocess for applications that require substantial amounts of proteins, the crystal structure of Nle&#8208;labeled TTL is solved. Future work should optimize media composition and feeding strategies to improve ncAA bioavailability and integrate biosynthesis pathways into the host genome to reduce metabolic burden and eliminate antibiotic use. These advances will make the process a cost&#8208;effective industrial platform for designer protein production.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/fe666869-ec09-4ea6-8ee9-5313b77e4235/cbic70173-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="A Robust Bioprocess for the Global Incorporation of Noncanonical Amino Acids in Auxotrophic Hosts Produces Labeled Proteins at the Gram Scale"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A robust bioprocess enables global incorporation of noncanonical amino acids in both shake flask and bioreactor cultures, producing gram-per-liter titers of efficiently labeled proteins. A versatile &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; BL21(DE3) auxotroph platform supports broad compatibility with various noncanonical amino acids and target proteins, facilitating flexible and scalable designer protein production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study presents a robust bioprocess for the global incorporation of noncanonical amino acids (ncAAs) into proteins, enabling gram-scale production in auxotrophic &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; strains. The two-phase approach adapts from shake flask to bioreactor cultures and relies on cost-effective synthetic minimal media with glucose as the sole carbon source and yeast extract as an amino acid supply. It supports both external ncAA supplementation and in situ biosynthesis. A versatile &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt; BL21(DE3) auxotroph platform ensures broad ncAA and protein compatibility. Model proteins, such as a thermophilic lipase (TTL) and an oxidoreductase are labeled with biosynthesized norleucine (Nle), synthetic fluoroprolines, and fluorophenylalanine. Under optimal conditions, we achieved titers of up to 2&#8201;g&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; with near-quantitative incorporation. To demonstrate the utility of the bioprocess for applications that require substantial amounts of proteins, the crystal structure of Nle-labeled TTL is solved. Future work should optimize media composition and feeding strategies to improve ncAA bioavailability and integrate biosynthesis pathways into the host genome to reduce metabolic burden and eliminate antibiotic use. These advances will make the process a cost-effective industrial platform for designer protein production.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Patrik Fladischer, 
Niklaus Anderhuber, 
Octavian Murgu, 
Altijana Hromi&#263;&#8208;Jahjefendi&#263;, 
Tea Pavkov&#8208;Keller, 
Karl Gruber, 
Juergen Mairhofer, 
Gerald Striedner, 
Birgit Wiltschi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>A Robust Bioprocess for the Global Incorporation of Noncanonical Amino Acids in Auxotrophic Hosts Produces Labeled Proteins at the Gram Scale</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500669</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500669</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500669</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500677</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500677</guid>
         <title>Differentiating the Substrate Profiles of Inflammatory Caspases Using Extended F&#246;rster Resonance Energy Transfer&#8208;Based Peptide Substrates</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Inflammatory caspases are key players in the innate immune response. Their specificity profiles are investigated using F&#246;rster resonance energy transfer peptide&#8208;based assays, allowing for incorporation of amino acids on both sides of the cleaved aspartic acid residue. Structural analyses led to the conclusion that having an amino acid on the prime side allows the substrate to adopt a different conformation than without it there.

Human inflammatory caspases (caspase&#8208;1, &#8208;4, and &#8208;5) are key players in the innate immune response. These enzymes have been shown to cleave proinflammatory substrates, implicating them in many inflammatory disease states. Their activity is frequently assessed using in&#8201;vitro fluorogenic assays, with all three human inflammatory caspases preferring the same WEHD tetrapeptide. The study examines the specificity of these enzymes C&#8208;terminal to the cleaved aspartate residue with F&#246;rster resonance energy transfer peptide&#8208;based assays using 7&#8208;methoxycoumaryl alanine [A(MCA)] as the donor and lysine&#8208;conjugated dabsyl [K(Dab)] as the quencher. The P4&#8211;P1 peptide sequences A(MCA)EHD, A(MCA)VAD, and A(MCA)QPD are varied on the C&#8208;terminal (prime) side of the peptide. Historically, caspase&#8208;4 and caspase&#8208;5 have been grouped together in their reactivity. Herein, caspase&#8208;5 only appreciably cleaves the A(MCA)EHDGK(Dab) peptide, whereas caspase&#8208;4 displays broader reactivity. All base sequences react more considerably with caspase&#8208;4 when a glycine is included C&#8208;terminal to Asp. The specificity of caspase&#8208;1 at this position varies based on the P3&#8211;P1 sequence of the peptide. These results highlight the interconnectedness of the prime and nonprime side amino acid sequences and the different behavior of each enzyme, which can be useful in understanding these potential drug targets.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/51f2b288-30ff-4723-9874-e666c41bd7bd/cbic70169-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Differentiating the Substrate Profiles of Inflammatory Caspases Using Extended F&#246;rster Resonance Energy Transfer-Based Peptide Substrates"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory caspases are key players in the innate immune response. Their specificity profiles are investigated using F&#246;rster resonance energy transfer peptide-based assays, allowing for incorporation of amino acids on both sides of the cleaved aspartic acid residue. Structural analyses led to the conclusion that having an amino acid on the prime side allows the substrate to adopt a different conformation than without it there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human inflammatory caspases (caspase-1, -4, and -5) are key players in the innate immune response. These enzymes have been shown to cleave proinflammatory substrates, implicating them in many inflammatory disease states. Their activity is frequently assessed using in&#8201;vitro fluorogenic assays, with all three human inflammatory caspases preferring the same WEHD tetrapeptide. The study examines the specificity of these enzymes C-terminal to the cleaved aspartate residue with F&#246;rster resonance energy transfer peptide-based assays using 7-methoxycoumaryl alanine [A(MCA)] as the donor and lysine-conjugated dabsyl [K(Dab)] as the quencher. The P&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;P&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; peptide sequences A(MCA)EHD, A(MCA)VAD, and A(MCA)QPD are varied on the C-terminal (prime) side of the peptide. Historically, caspase-4 and caspase-5 have been grouped together in their reactivity. Herein, caspase-5 only appreciably cleaves the A(MCA)EHDGK(Dab) peptide, whereas caspase-4 displays broader reactivity. All base sequences react more considerably with caspase-4 when a glycine is included C-terminal to Asp. The specificity of caspase-1 at this position varies based on the P&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;P&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; sequence of the peptide. These results highlight the interconnectedness of the prime and nonprime side amino acid sequences and the different behavior of each enzyme, which can be useful in understanding these potential drug targets.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Tess C. Boyd, 
Sophie F. Young, 
Tessa L. Lusis, 
Mya A. Fegaras, 
Rifqa Alani, 
Kaitlyn Shelley, 
Cathrine A. Southern, 
Caitlin E. Karver
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Differentiating the Substrate Profiles of Inflammatory Caspases Using Extended F&#246;rster Resonance Energy Transfer&#8208;Based Peptide Substrates</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500677</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500677</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500677</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500706</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500706</guid>
         <title>Dual COX&#8208;2/5&#8208;LOX Inhibition by Novel Thymol Derivatives: From Molecular Modeling to In Vitro Validation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
In&#8201;silico studies on a series of novel thymol derivatives reveal improved binding affinities, enhanced stability, and persistent interactions within the active pockets of COX&#8208;2 and 5&#8208;LOX enzymes, with respect to thymol and its halogenated derivatives. Cell&#8208;free assays highlight T3 as the most potent COX&#8208;2 inhibitor, while T1 and T3 exhibit similar activity on 5&#8208;LOX.

Dual cyclooxygenase&#8208;2/5&#8208;lipoxygenase (COX&#8208;2/5&#8208;LOX) inhibitors constitute safer alternatives to classical nonsteroidal anti&#8208;inflammatory drugs, widely used to effectively manage inflammation. In this article, molecular docking and molecular dynamics simulations guide the synthesis of novel thymol derivatives that interact with both COX&#8208;2 and 5&#8208;LOX active sites. Ligands are designed with the aim of improving thymol bioactivity, selectivity, stability, as well as pharmacokinetic properties. Therefore, &#8211;Br, &#8211;F, and &#8211;CF3 inclusion on thymol is here evaluated, screening COX&#8208;2 and 5&#8208;LOX interactions with thymol (T), 4&#8208;fluorothymol (FT), 4&#8208;bromothymol (BT), isopropyl thymyl succinate (T1), 1,1,1,3,3,3&#8208;hexafluoroisopropyl thymyl succinate (T2), and 1&#8242;,1&#8242;,1&#8242;,3&#8242;,3&#8242;,3&#8242;&#8208;hexafluoroisopropyl 4&#8208;(4&#8242;&#8217;&#8208;thymyl)&#8208;4&#8208;oxobutanoate (T3). Molecular modeling reveals that the estimated ligands can establish favorable interactions with both COX&#8208;2 and 5&#8208;LOX active pockets, highlighting T1&#8211;T3 as the most promising compounds. In&#8201;vitro assays identify T3 as the most active COX&#8208;2 inhibitor, while T2 results as the most effective ligand for 5&#8208;LOX. Interestingly, cavity analysis of the COX&#8208;2 entry site reveals that T3 insertion is favored over T1 and T2 due to its greater polarity, conferred by the presence of a free phenolic group (OH) able to establish H&#8208;bonds with surrounding residues.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/47714bd2-9518-45a7-a0a2-8d25c3a3a693/cbic70180-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Dual COX-2/5-LOX Inhibition by Novel Thymol Derivatives: From Molecular Modeling to In Vitro Validation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In&#8201;silico studies on a series of novel thymol derivatives reveal improved binding affinities, enhanced stability, and persistent interactions within the active pockets of COX-2 and 5-LOX enzymes, with respect to thymol and its halogenated derivatives. Cell-free assays highlight T3 as the most potent COX-2 inhibitor, while T1 and T3 exhibit similar activity on 5-LOX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dual cyclooxygenase-2/5-lipoxygenase (COX-2/5-LOX) inhibitors constitute safer alternatives to classical nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, widely used to effectively manage inflammation. In this article, molecular docking and molecular dynamics simulations guide the synthesis of novel thymol derivatives that interact with both COX-2 and 5-LOX active sites. Ligands are designed with the aim of improving thymol bioactivity, selectivity, stability, as well as pharmacokinetic properties. Therefore, &#8211;Br, &#8211;F, and &#8211;CF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; inclusion on thymol is here evaluated, screening COX-2 and 5-LOX interactions with thymol (&lt;b&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;), 4-fluorothymol (&lt;b&gt;FT&lt;/b&gt;), 4-bromothymol (&lt;b&gt;BT&lt;/b&gt;), isopropyl thymyl succinate (&lt;b&gt;T1&lt;/b&gt;), 1,1,1,3,3,3-hexafluoroisopropyl thymyl succinate (&lt;b&gt;T2&lt;/b&gt;), and 1&#8242;,1&#8242;,1&#8242;,3&#8242;,3&#8242;,3&#8242;-hexafluoroisopropyl 4-(4&#8242;&#8217;-thymyl)-4-oxobutanoate (&lt;b&gt;T3&lt;/b&gt;). Molecular modeling reveals that the estimated ligands can establish favorable interactions with both COX-2 and 5-LOX active pockets, highlighting &lt;b&gt;T1&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&#8211;T3&lt;/b&gt; as the most promising compounds. In&#8201;vitro assays identify &lt;b&gt;T3&lt;/b&gt; as the most active COX-2 inhibitor, while &lt;b&gt;T2&lt;/b&gt; results as the most effective ligand for 5-LOX. Interestingly, cavity analysis of the COX-2 entry site reveals that &lt;b&gt;T3&lt;/b&gt; insertion is favored over &lt;b&gt;T1&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;T2&lt;/b&gt; due to its greater polarity, conferred by the presence of a free phenolic group (OH) able to establish H-bonds with surrounding residues.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Alice Romeo, 
Silvia Pezzola, 
Francesca Valentini, 
Federico Iacovelli, 
Mattia Falconi, 
Federica Sabuzi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Dual COX&#8208;2/5&#8208;LOX Inhibition by Novel Thymol Derivatives: From Molecular Modeling to In Vitro Validation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500706</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500706</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500706</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500710</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500710</guid>
         <title>Alteration of CD40 Protein Expression by Tyrosine Phosphorylation of the NF&#8208;&#954;B p50 Subunit</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Strategy for incorporation of phosphorylated tyrosine into the p50 subunit of human NF&#8208;&#954;B.

Protein phosphorylation is critical to selective gene expression; the proteins that regulate transcription are often phosphorylated at multiple sites. Serine and threonine phosphorylation in transcription factors such as NF&#8208;&#954;B has been studied, and specific serines are involved in transcriptional activation. Tyrosine phosphorylation of NF&#8208;&#954;B p50 subunit can also facilitate the NF&#8208;&#954;B&#8208;mediated expression of CD40 protein. This study seeks to determine whether tyrosine phosphorylations at positions not normally phosphorylated in vivo could nonetheless affect protein expression mediated by NF&#8208;&#954;B. The alterations studied included p50 analogs having pTyr at positions 59 and 61, which do not contain Tyr naturally, and an analog containing a metabolically stable tyrosine methylene phosphonate at position 60. Additionally, to explore the structural basis for enhanced NF&#8208;&#954;B binding to CD40 promoter DNA by tyrosine phosphorylation, an analog of NF&#8208;&#954;B p50 containing pTyr at both positions 60 and 82 is prepared. The results reflected changes in the ability of the modified NF&#8208;&#954;Bs containing an altered p50 subunit to bind to CD40 promoter DNA in vitro, and to direct the synthesis of CD40 in cellulo.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/c5ae2d3b-5451-45de-a774-69785efe5f9b/cbic70161-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Alteration of CD40 Protein Expression by Tyrosine Phosphorylation of the NF-&#954;B p50 Subunit"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategy for incorporation of phosphorylated tyrosine into the p50 subunit of human NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein phosphorylation is critical to selective gene expression; the proteins that regulate transcription are often phosphorylated at multiple sites. Serine and threonine phosphorylation in transcription factors such as NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B has been studied, and specific serines are involved in transcriptional activation. Tyrosine phosphorylation of NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B p50 subunit can also facilitate the NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B-mediated expression of CD40 protein. This study seeks to determine whether tyrosine phosphorylations at positions not normally phosphorylated in vivo could nonetheless affect protein expression mediated by NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B. The alterations studied included p50 analogs having pTyr at positions 59 and 61, which do not contain Tyr naturally, and an analog containing a metabolically stable tyrosine methylene phosphonate at position 60. Additionally, to explore the structural basis for enhanced NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B binding to CD40 promoter DNA by tyrosine phosphorylation, an analog of NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;B p50 containing pTyr at both positions 60 and 82 is prepared. The results reflected changes in the ability of the modified NF-&lt;i&gt;&#954;&lt;/i&gt;Bs containing an altered p50 subunit to bind to CD40 promoter DNA in vitro, and to direct the synthesis of CD40 in cellulo.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Shengxi Chen, 
Gal Reddy Potuganti, 
Xun Ji, 
Sidney M. Hecht
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Alteration of CD40 Protein Expression by Tyrosine Phosphorylation of the NF&#8208;&#954;B p50 Subunit</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500710</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500710</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500710</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500764</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500764</guid>
         <title>A Thermostable Class III Phosphoribosyl Pyrophosphate Synthetase from Pyrolobus fumarii 1A: Characterization and Application Potential for Phosphoribosyl Pyrophosphate Biosynthesis</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A class III phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate synthetase (PfPRS) from the hyper thermophilic archaeon Pyrolobus fumarii 1A was identified and characterized. PfPRS exhibited exceptional thermal and pH stability, retaining high activity even at 100&#8201;&#176;C. Its robust catalytic features, along with exploratory co&#8208;immobilization for nucleotide regeneration, highlight its promise for biocatalytic applications.

Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate (PRPP) functions as a central metabolic intermediate, supplying ribose&#8208;5&#8208;phosphate moieties for the biosynthesis of nucleotides, certain amino acids, and a range of essential cofactors. In this study, a thermostable phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate synthetase (PfPRS) was identified from the hyper thermophilic archaeon Pyrolobus fumarii 1A, a hyper thermophilic archaeon that grows optimally at 90&#8211;113&#8201;&#176;C. The prs gene was heterologously expressed in Escherichia coli, and the recombinant enzyme was purified and characterized. Peak catalytic activity of PfPRS was observed at approximately pH 7.5 and 55&#8201;&#176;C and retained over 85% of its activity after 2&#8201;h of incubation across pH 4.0&#8211;10.5. PfPRS exhibited high thermal stability. The enzyme exhibited half&#8208;lives of 12&#8201;h at 90&#8201;&#176;C, 5&#8201;h at 95&#8201;&#176;C, and 3&#8201;h at 100&#8201;&#176;C. Among the nucleotides tested as diphosphate donors, PfPRS showed a strong preference for ATP, whereas ADP served as an effective inhibitor. Kinetic analysis revealed Km values of 35&#8201;&#181;M for R5P and 46&#8201;&#181;M for ATP, with turnover rates (kcat) of 71&#8201;s&#8722;1 and 56&#8201;s&#8722;1. PfPRS was co&#8208;immobilized with polyphosphate kinase 2 (DrPPK2) from Deinococcus radiodurans using a cross&#8208;linked enzyme aggregate (CLEA) system to enable ATP regeneration and to explore the feasibility of using PfPRS for PRPP biosynthesis.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/022d9a0e-cd6f-4650-bf78-8b373e7213b6/cbic70175-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="A Thermostable Class III Phosphoribosyl Pyrophosphate Synthetase from Pyrolobus fumarii 1A: Characterization and Application Potential for Phosphoribosyl Pyrophosphate Biosynthesis"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A class III phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate synthetase (&lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS) from the hyper thermophilic archaeon &lt;i&gt;Pyrolobus fumarii&lt;/i&gt; 1A was identified and characterized. &lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS exhibited exceptional thermal and pH stability, retaining high activity even at 100&#8201;&#176;C. Its robust catalytic features, along with exploratory co-immobilization for nucleotide regeneration, highlight its promise for biocatalytic applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate (PRPP) functions as a central metabolic intermediate, supplying ribose-5-phosphate moieties for the biosynthesis of nucleotides, certain amino acids, and a range of essential cofactors. In this study, a thermostable phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate synthetase (&lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS) was identified from the hyper thermophilic archaeon &lt;i&gt;Pyrolobus fumarii&lt;/i&gt; 1A, a hyper thermophilic archaeon that grows optimally at 90&#8211;113&#8201;&#176;C. The &lt;i&gt;prs&lt;/i&gt; gene was heterologously expressed in &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt;, and the recombinant enzyme was purified and characterized. Peak catalytic activity of &lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS was observed at approximately pH 7.5 and 55&#8201;&#176;C and retained over 85% of its activity after 2&#8201;h of incubation across pH 4.0&#8211;10.5. &lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS exhibited high thermal stability. The enzyme exhibited half-lives of 12&#8201;h at 90&#8201;&#176;C, 5&#8201;h at 95&#8201;&#176;C, and 3&#8201;h at 100&#8201;&#176;C. Among the nucleotides tested as diphosphate donors, &lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS showed a strong preference for ATP, whereas ADP served as an effective inhibitor. Kinetic analysis revealed &lt;i&gt;K&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;
   &lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/sub&gt; values of 35&#8201;&#181;M for R5P and 46&#8201;&#181;M for ATP, with turnover rates (&lt;i&gt;k&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;cat&lt;/sub&gt;) of 71&#8201;s&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; and 56&#8201;s&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS was co-immobilized with polyphosphate kinase 2 (&lt;i&gt;Dr&lt;/i&gt;PPK2) from &lt;i&gt;Deinococcus radiodurans&lt;/i&gt; using a cross-linked enzyme aggregate (CLEA) system to enable ATP regeneration and to explore the feasibility of using &lt;i&gt;Pf&lt;/i&gt;PRS for PRPP biosynthesis.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jingfei Wu, 
Takanori Akiyama, 
Yasuhisa Asano
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>A Thermostable Class III Phosphoribosyl Pyrophosphate Synthetase from Pyrolobus fumarii 1A: Characterization and Application Potential for Phosphoribosyl Pyrophosphate Biosynthesis</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500764</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500764</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500764</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500782</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500782</guid>
         <title>Nanomolar Affinity Host&#8208;Dye Reporter Pairs from Fluorescently Labeled Oligoarginine Peptides and p&#8208;Sulfonatocalix[4]arene</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The dependence of the binding affinity of oligoarginine peptides to p&#8208;sulfonatocalix[4]arene (CX4) on peptide length, C&#8208;terminal functionality, and fluorescent labeling is reported. The fluorescent peptides can be excited in the visible range with common lasers and show nanomolar affinity and efficient quenching upon CX4 binding, which enables their use as modular host&#8208;dye reporter pairs for peptide sensing.

Oligoarginine peptides are of interest as cell&#8208;penetrating peptides (CPPs) and play important roles in gene regulation and immune response. Complexation of oligoarginine peptides by the supramolecular host p&#8208;sulfonatocalix[4]arene (CX4) is well&#8208;established and has led to the use of CX4 derivatives as effective counterion activators for arginine&#8208;rich CPPs and to the application of CX4 in peptide sensing. Herein, a systematic binding study between oligoarginine peptides with CX4 is reported. The results show that the binding affinity increases with increasing peptide length from &#8776;104&#8201;M&#8211;1 for the peptide H&#8208;Arg&#8208;Arg&#8208;OH to nanomolar affinities for peptides with more than four arginine residues. Within the series, C&#8208;terminal carboxamides show higher affinities than the respective carboxylates. In addition, the influence of fluorescent dye labeling is investigated with sulforhodamine B (SRB) and fluorescein (FL) dye labels. Efficient fluorescent quenching is observed after complexation of the labeled peptides by CX4, which prompted the exploration of the complexes as reporter pairs for chemosensing applications. The results suggest that the combination of fluorescently labeled oligoarginine peptides with CX4 affords a modular platform of host&#8208;dye reporter pairs for the detection of polycationic peptides with tailorable excitation and emission wavelengths and tailorable binding affinity down to the nanomolar affinity range.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/f3895202-cfb3-4910-b2b5-9143f11baa84/cbic70164-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Nanomolar Affinity Host-Dye Reporter Pairs from Fluorescently Labeled Oligoarginine Peptides and p-Sulfonatocalix[4]arene"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dependence of the binding affinity of oligoarginine peptides to &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-sulfonatocalix[4]arene (CX4) on peptide length, C-terminal functionality, and fluorescent labeling is reported. The fluorescent peptides can be excited in the visible range with common lasers and show nanomolar affinity and efficient quenching upon CX4 binding, which enables their use as modular host-dye reporter pairs for peptide sensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oligoarginine peptides are of interest as cell-penetrating peptides (CPPs) and play important roles in gene regulation and immune response. Complexation of oligoarginine peptides by the supramolecular host &lt;i&gt;p-&lt;/i&gt;sulfonatocalix[4]arene (CX4) is well-established and has led to the use of CX4 derivatives as effective counterion activators for arginine-rich CPPs and to the application of CX4 in peptide sensing. Herein, a systematic binding study between oligoarginine peptides with CX4 is reported. The results show that the binding affinity increases with increasing peptide length from &#8776;10&lt;sup&gt;4&#8201;&lt;/sup&gt;M&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;1&lt;/sup&gt; for the peptide H-Arg-Arg-OH to nanomolar affinities for peptides with more than four arginine residues. Within the series, C-terminal carboxamides show higher affinities than the respective carboxylates. In addition, the influence of fluorescent dye labeling is investigated with sulforhodamine B (SRB) and fluorescein (FL) dye labels. Efficient fluorescent quenching is observed after complexation of the labeled peptides by CX4, which prompted the exploration of the complexes as reporter pairs for chemosensing applications. The results suggest that the combination of fluorescently labeled oligoarginine peptides with CX4 affords a modular platform of host-dye reporter pairs for the detection of polycationic peptides with tailorable excitation and emission wavelengths and tailorable binding affinity down to the nanomolar affinity range.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Aparna Pramanik, 
Mohammad A. Alnajjar, 
Tristan Wegner, 
Andreas Hennig
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Nanomolar Affinity Host&#8208;Dye Reporter Pairs from Fluorescently Labeled Oligoarginine Peptides and p&#8208;Sulfonatocalix[4]arene</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500782</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500782</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500782</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500794</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500794</guid>
         <title>Exploring the Substitution of the C21&#8208;OAc Moiety in [11]Cytochalasans: Synthesis and Evaluation of Fluorophore Conjugates</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Via in&#8201;silico docking of pyrichalasin H on G&#8208; and F&#8208;actin, the C21&#8208;OAc moiety is identified as a modifiable site tolerated for actin binding. Fluorescent [11]cytochalasan probes from pyrichalasin H and epoxycytochalasin C are obtained by selective C21&#8208;OAc hydrolysis and acylation. The conjugates retain actin binding and bioactivity, establishing C21&#8208;OAc as a versatile handle for functionalization.

The actin cytoskeleton plays a central role in cellular organization and dynamics, yet the tools available for targeting actin function remain limited. Cytochalasans represent a large class of actin&#8208;targeting natural products that are readily cell permeable with varying cytotoxicity and actin&#8208;targeting capabilities in mammalian cells. Their pharmacologic exploitation not only requires an understanding of their mode of action but also exact knowledge of how they can be derivatized without affecting their bioactivity. Herein, the design, synthesis, and evaluation of five fluorescently labeled [11]cytochalasan derivatives generated from pyrichalasin H (PyriH) and 19,20&#8208;epoxycytochalasin C (EpoxyCytoC) are reported. Guided by molecular docking, the C21&#8208;OAc moiety is identified as a promising site for tag attachment without disrupting actin binding. Semisynthetic modifications enable the conjugation of different dyes to PyriH and EpoxyCytoC scaffolds. Moreover, the effect of linkers separating cytochalasans and dyes is analyzed. Biological evaluation supplemented by in&#8201;vitro assays to additionally interrogates their activities on the assembly of pure actin filaments revealing distinct activity profiles. Together, this study compares permeability, cytotoxicity, and actin binding of five novel [11]cytochalasan probes bearing substitutions of the C21&#8208;OAc moiety. These findings establish the C21&#8208;OAc position as a versatile functionalization site and provide a framework for developing next generation cytochalasan&#8208;based actin&#8208;targeting probes.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/9b42b030-45a6-4528-a1e1-200af0e99563/cbic70167-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Exploring the Substitution of the C21-OAc Moiety in [11]Cytochalasans: Synthesis and Evaluation of Fluorophore Conjugates"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via in&#8201;silico docking of pyrichalasin H on G- and F-actin, the &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;21-OAc moiety is identified as a modifiable site tolerated for actin binding. Fluorescent [11]cytochalasan probes from pyrichalasin H and epoxycytochalasin C are obtained by selective &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;21-OAc hydrolysis and acylation. The conjugates retain actin binding and bioactivity, establishing &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;21-OAc as a versatile handle for functionalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actin cytoskeleton plays a central role in cellular organization and dynamics, yet the tools available for targeting actin function remain limited. Cytochalasans represent a large class of actin-targeting natural products that are readily cell permeable with varying cytotoxicity and actin-targeting capabilities in mammalian cells. Their pharmacologic exploitation not only requires an understanding of their mode of action but also exact knowledge of how they can be derivatized without affecting their bioactivity. Herein, the design, synthesis, and evaluation of five fluorescently labeled [11]cytochalasan derivatives generated from pyrichalasin H (&lt;b&gt;PyriH&lt;/b&gt;) and 19,20-epoxycytochalasin C (&lt;b&gt;EpoxyCytoC&lt;/b&gt;) are reported. Guided by molecular docking, the &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;21-OAc moiety is identified as a promising site for tag attachment without disrupting actin binding. Semisynthetic modifications enable the conjugation of different dyes to &lt;b&gt;PyriH&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;EpoxyCytoC&lt;/b&gt; scaffolds. Moreover, the effect of linkers separating cytochalasans and dyes is analyzed. Biological evaluation supplemented by in&#8201;vitro assays to additionally interrogates their activities on the assembly of pure actin filaments revealing distinct activity profiles. Together, this study compares permeability, cytotoxicity, and actin binding of five novel [11]cytochalasan probes bearing substitutions of the &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;21-OAc moiety. These findings establish the &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;21-OAc position as a versatile functionalization site and provide a framework for developing next generation cytochalasan-based actin-targeting probes.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Mervic D. Kagho, 
Katharina Schmidt, 
Aishi Chakrabarti, 
Marius Karger, 
Christopher Lambert, 
Maurice Hauser, 
Russell J. Cox, 
Klemens Rottner, 
Marc Stadler, 
Theresia E. Stradal, 
Philipp Klahn
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Exploring the Substitution of the C21&#8208;OAc Moiety in [11]Cytochalasans: Synthesis and Evaluation of Fluorophore Conjugates</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500794</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500794</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500794</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500816</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500816</guid>
         <title>Staphylococcal SplA and SplB Serine Protease Allelic Variants Exhibit Different Substrate Specificities</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A biochemical characterization of Staphylococcus aureus serine proteases SplA and SplB allelic variants (recombinantly produced in E. coli and purified) reveals that allelic variation adds an extra layer of complexity to the functioning of virulence factors in S. aureus colonization and infection. This highlights the importance of considering allelic variation in the study of host&#8208;pathogen interactions.

Staphylococcus aureus is an opportunistic pathogen that is persistently colonizing nearly 30% of the human population and can cause life&#8208;threatening infections. S. aureus secretes a variety of virulence factors, such as a set of extracellular serine protease&#8208;like proteins (Spls). Spls are expressed by most clinical isolates of S. aureus, but their pathophysiological substrates and role during infection are largely unknown. Pathogens use allelic variation of virulence factors to allow an adaption to different host cells and their defense mechanisms. The differences of these variants are marginally characterized so far. Here, we performed a biochemical characterization of selected allelic variants of the S. aureus SplA and SplB. Our data suggests different variants show differences in their stability, enzymatic activity, and substrate specificity. For the recently identified Spl target proteins RickULP and SseL, different cleavage patterns were observed, upon treatment with different Spl allelic variants. One SplB variant strongly differed in its substrate recognition at the P3/P4 position, more closely resembling SplE than SplB wildtype in its substrate selectivity. Our data provide valuable insights into the evolution of bacterial virulence factors and highlight the importance of including allelic variation of virulence factors to fully understand their role in host&#8211;pathogen interaction.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e0ad6c49-2178-42e3-a82d-4ccaec8aba00/cbic70183-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Staphylococcal SplA and SplB Serine Protease Allelic Variants Exhibit Different Substrate Specificities"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A biochemical characterization of &lt;i&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/i&gt; serine proteases SplA and SplB allelic variants (recombinantly produced in &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt; and purified) reveals that allelic variation adds an extra layer of complexity to the functioning of virulence factors in &lt;i&gt;S. aureus&lt;/i&gt; colonization and infection. This highlights the importance of considering allelic variation in the study of host-pathogen interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/i&gt; is an opportunistic pathogen that is persistently colonizing nearly 30% of the human population and can cause life-threatening infections. &lt;i&gt;S. aureus&lt;/i&gt; secretes a variety of virulence factors, such as a set of extracellular serine protease-like proteins (Spls). Spls are expressed by most clinical isolates of &lt;i&gt;S. aureus&lt;/i&gt;, but their pathophysiological substrates and role during infection are largely unknown. Pathogens use allelic variation of virulence factors to allow an adaption to different host cells and their defense mechanisms. The differences of these variants are marginally characterized so far. Here, we performed a biochemical characterization of selected allelic variants of the &lt;i&gt;S. aureus&lt;/i&gt; SplA and SplB. Our data suggests different variants show differences in their stability, enzymatic activity, and substrate specificity. For the recently identified Spl target proteins RickULP and SseL, different cleavage patterns were observed, upon treatment with different Spl allelic variants. One SplB variant strongly differed in its substrate recognition at the P3/P4 position, more closely resembling SplE than SplB wildtype in its substrate selectivity. Our data provide valuable insights into the evolution of bacterial virulence factors and highlight the importance of including allelic variation of virulence factors to fully understand their role in host&#8211;pathogen interaction.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Felix L. Glinka, 
Katharina Mehnert, 
Lena Koch, 
Ole Schm&#246;ker, 
Leif Steil, 
Christian Hentschker, 
Uwe V&#246;lker, 
Thor B. Johannesen, 
Dominique B&#246;ttcher, 
Michael Lammers, 
Barbara M. Br&#246;ker, 
Uwe T. Bornscheuer
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Staphylococcal SplA and SplB Serine Protease Allelic Variants Exhibit Different Substrate Specificities</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500816</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500816</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500816</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500821</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500821</guid>
         <title>Design and Fabrication of a Versatile Microreactor to Study Transaminase&#8208;Based Heterogeneous Biocatalysts in Flow</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A versatile microdevice loaded with an immobilized amine transaminase can be operated as either a packed&#8208;bed or fluidized microreactor depending on the flow direction. This setup is very useful to characterize the performance of immobilized enzymes under different reactor configurations.

Microfluidics is a very attractive discipline for implementing more versatile high&#8208;throughput screening methods to improve enzymes. However, state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art microfluidics set&#8208;ups are mainly devoted to screening enzymes in solution, while screening of enzyme immobilization protocols using microfluidics is scarce. In this work, a microreactor device is designed, fabricated and applied to test different heterogeneous biocatalysts with transaminase activity. This microsystem set&#8208;up can be operated in two different modes: packed&#8208;bed (PBR) and fluidized (FBR) microreactors without exchanging the sample. Using the same sample to run the two modes, the fidelity of the comparison is increased between the two fluid dynamic regimes. Moreover, by testing different carriers under different modes, a Histagged transaminase is found from Pseudomonas fluorescens immobilized on agarose porous microbeads functionalized with cobalt&#8208;chelates and operated as FBR maximizes the STY, and minimizes the equilibration times. This device exemplifies the potential of microreactors for prototyping more efficient heterogeneous biocatalysts.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e483a2fa-ad84-43f9-86a3-42a0983000ff/cbic70171-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Design and Fabrication of a Versatile Microreactor to Study Transaminase-Based Heterogeneous Biocatalysts in Flow"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A versatile microdevice loaded with an immobilized amine transaminase can be operated as either a packed-bed or fluidized microreactor depending on the flow direction. This setup is very useful to characterize the performance of immobilized enzymes under different reactor configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microfluidics is a very attractive discipline for implementing more versatile high-throughput screening methods to improve enzymes. However, state-of-the-art microfluidics set-ups are mainly devoted to screening enzymes in solution, while screening of enzyme immobilization protocols using microfluidics is scarce. In this work, a microreactor device is designed, fabricated and applied to test different heterogeneous biocatalysts with transaminase activity. This microsystem set-up can be operated in two different modes: packed-bed (PBR) and fluidized (FBR) microreactors without exchanging the sample. Using the same sample to run the two modes, the fidelity of the comparison is increased between the two fluid dynamic regimes. Moreover, by testing different carriers under different modes, a Histagged transaminase is found from &lt;i&gt;Pseudomonas fluorescens&lt;/i&gt; immobilized on agarose porous microbeads functionalized with cobalt-chelates and operated as FBR maximizes the STY, and minimizes the equilibration times. This device exemplifies the potential of microreactors for prototyping more efficient heterogeneous biocatalysts.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Nicolette Czarnievicz, 
Elwin Vrouwe, 
Maciej Skolimowski, 
Fernando Lopez&#8208;Gallego
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Design and Fabrication of a Versatile Microreactor to Study Transaminase&#8208;Based Heterogeneous Biocatalysts in Flow</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500821</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500821</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500821</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500880</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500880</guid>
         <title>A Two&#8208;Phase Enzymatic Cascade for Indigo Synthesis from Anthranilate</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
This five&#8208;step enzymatic cascade for indigo synthesis is derived from the natural biosynthetic route starting from anthranilate. A two&#8208;phase system addresses enzyme incompatibility, and process engineering through stepwise parameter optimization for each phase results in a titer of 183&#8201;mg&#8201;L&#8722;1 indigo. This work establishes a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept enzymatic platform that expands the toolbox for designing bio&#8208;based indigo synthesis.

Herein, an enzymatic in&#8201;vitro synthesis route to indigo, the dye that gives denim its renowned color, is described. The proposed five&#8208;step enzymatic pathway is derived from the natural biosynthesis route starts from anthranilate. In the context of the bio&#8208;based economy, this method provides an alternative to the current method of indigo synthesis, which relies on petroleum&#8208;based building blocks. First, the enzymes are assessed by stepwise addition to detect intermediate compounds, to ensure cascade function. A two&#8208;phase system is designed in response to differences in melting temperatures of the enzymes. A titer of 183&#8201;mg&#8201;L&#8722;1 indigo is reached through stepwise parameter optimization for each phase, followed by process engineering to enhance the indigo titer. Continuous supplementation of the cosubstrate phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate is necessary to maintain indole&#8208;3&#8208;glycerol phosphate (IGP) formation in the first phase. During the second phase, complete uptake of IGP by ZmBX1 remains challenging, and formation of significant byproducts is observed. Despite attempts to resolve these issues, the underlying mechanism remains unclear. Although the yield must be significantly improved for an economically viable process, an enzymatic cascade based on bio&#8208;based materials remains a potential alternative for sustainable denim dye synthesis by circumventing host toxicity observed in whole&#8208;cell approaches.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/598367e3-df61-45e9-82e4-6672825e3219/cbic70172-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="A Two-Phase Enzymatic Cascade for Indigo Synthesis from Anthranilate"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This five-step enzymatic cascade for indigo synthesis is derived from the natural biosynthetic route starting from anthranilate. A two-phase system addresses enzyme incompatibility, and process engineering through stepwise parameter optimization for each phase results in a titer of 183&#8201;mg&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; indigo. This work establishes a proof-of-concept enzymatic platform that expands the toolbox for designing bio-based indigo synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herein, an enzymatic in&#8201;vitro synthesis route to indigo, the dye that gives denim its renowned color, is described. The proposed five-step enzymatic pathway is derived from the natural biosynthesis route starts from anthranilate. In the context of the bio-based economy, this method provides an alternative to the current method of indigo synthesis, which relies on petroleum-based building blocks. First, the enzymes are assessed by stepwise addition to detect intermediate compounds, to ensure cascade function. A two-phase system is designed in response to differences in melting temperatures of the enzymes. A titer of 183&#8201;mg&#8201;L&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;1&lt;/sup&gt; indigo is reached through stepwise parameter optimization for each phase, followed by process engineering to enhance the indigo titer. Continuous supplementation of the cosubstrate phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate is necessary to maintain indole-3-glycerol phosphate (IGP) formation in the first phase. During the second phase, complete uptake of IGP by &lt;i&gt;Zm&lt;/i&gt;BX1 remains challenging, and formation of significant byproducts is observed. Despite attempts to resolve these issues, the underlying mechanism remains unclear. Although the yield must be significantly improved for an economically viable process, an enzymatic cascade based on bio-based materials remains a potential alternative for sustainable denim dye synthesis by circumventing host toxicity observed in whole-cell approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Ruben M. de Boer, 
Ditte Hededam Welner
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>A Two&#8208;Phase Enzymatic Cascade for Indigo Synthesis from Anthranilate</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500880</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500880</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500880</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500664</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500664</guid>
         <title>From Structure to Function: Development of Relaxin&#8208;3 Analogs and their Role in RXFP3 Signaling</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
This review outlines the current understanding of the relaxin&#8208;3/the relaxin family peptide receptor 3 (RXFP3) system and recent developments in peptidomimetics and small&#8208;molecule ligands targeting the system.

Relaxin&#8208;3 is a two&#8208;chain neuropeptide of the insulin/relaxin superfamily and the cognate ligand for the G protein&#8208;coupled receptor RXFP3. Since its discovery, the relaxin&#8208;3/RXFP3 signaling system has emerged as a key regulator of feeding behavior, stress responses, arousal, addiction, and cognitive function. Recent structural studies, including the first cryo&#8208;electron microscopy structures of RXFP3 bound to relaxin&#8208;3 and small molecules, have provided significant insights into ligand&#8211;receptor interactions. Together with mutagenesis and pharmacological studies, these advances have facilitated the design of diverse RXFP3 ligands, ranging from simplified and/or stapled single&#8208;chain analogs of relaxin&#8208;3 to grafted scaffolds and small&#8208;molecule modulators. Such tools have been instrumental for probing relaxin&#8208;3 biology in&#8201;vivo and highlight the system's therapeutic potential for treating anxiety, depression, obesity, binge eating, and alcohol use disorder. However, challenges remain, particularly regarding blood&#8211;brain barrier penetration, receptor subtype selectivity, pharmacokinetic optimization, and safe long&#8208;term modulation. This review summarizes current knowledge of relaxin&#8208;3 structure, receptor interactions, and pharmacology and highlights how advances in peptide chemistry, structural biology, and small&#8208;molecule design are enabling the rational development of RXFP3&#8208;targeted therapeutics.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/161827b8-9e8b-4a65-aeac-9315afaf95df/cbic70120-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="From Structure to Function: Development of Relaxin-3 Analogs and their Role in RXFP3 Signaling"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review outlines the current understanding of the relaxin-3/the relaxin family peptide receptor 3 (RXFP3) system and recent developments in peptidomimetics and small-molecule ligands targeting the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relaxin-3 is a two-chain neuropeptide of the insulin/relaxin superfamily and the cognate ligand for the G protein-coupled receptor RXFP3. Since its discovery, the relaxin-3/RXFP3 signaling system has emerged as a key regulator of feeding behavior, stress responses, arousal, addiction, and cognitive function. Recent structural studies, including the first cryo-electron microscopy structures of RXFP3 bound to relaxin-3 and small molecules, have provided significant insights into ligand&#8211;receptor interactions. Together with mutagenesis and pharmacological studies, these advances have facilitated the design of diverse RXFP3 ligands, ranging from simplified and/or stapled single-chain analogs of relaxin-3 to grafted scaffolds and small-molecule modulators. Such tools have been instrumental for probing relaxin-3 biology in&#8201;vivo and highlight the system's therapeutic potential for treating anxiety, depression, obesity, binge eating, and alcohol use disorder. However, challenges remain, particularly regarding blood&#8211;brain barrier penetration, receptor subtype selectivity, pharmacokinetic optimization, and safe long-term modulation. This review summarizes current knowledge of relaxin-3 structure, receptor interactions, and pharmacology and highlights how advances in peptide chemistry, structural biology, and small-molecule design are enabling the rational development of RXFP3-targeted therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Isabelle Riches, 
Hongkang Wu, 
Predrag Kalaba, 
Ashish Sethi, 
Tim Lkhagvajargal, 
Philip J. Ryan, 
Ivan Maslov, 
Ross A. D. Bathgate, 
Mohammed Akhter Hossain
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>From Structure to Function: Development of Relaxin&#8208;3 Analogs and their Role in RXFP3 Signaling</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500664</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500664</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500664</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500676</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500676</guid>
         <title>Advancements in Targeted Radiopharmaceuticals: Innovations in Diagnosis and Therapy for Enhanced Cancer Management</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Radiopharmaceuticals enable precise cancer diagnosis and targeted therapy by combining radioactive isotopes with carrier molecules. This review summarizes advances from 2014 to 2025, emphasizing probe design, click chemistry, novel targets, and nanodelivery systems. It highlights clinical progress, theranostic innovations, and future challenges in scalability, regulation, and AI&#8208;driven personalized treatment planning in precision oncology

Radiopharmaceuticals (RPhs) represent a breakthrough in nuclear medicine due to their ability to provide precise diagnosis and targeted therapy for cancer by incorporating radioactive isotopes into carrier molecules. This review systematically discusses the recent advances in the development of RPhs, focusing on state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art probe design strategies and click chemistry applications that accelerate RPh syntheses and improve targeting efficiency. The manuscript synthesizes literature from multiple databases spanning January 2014 to April 2025, encompassing diagnostic modalities including positron emission tomography (PET) and single&#8208;photon emission computed tomography (SPECT) imaging, and therapeutic applications utilizing alpha and beta emitters such as 225Ac and 177Lu. Clinically approved agents, such as 177Lu&#8208;DOTATATE and 177Lu&#8208;PSMA&#8208;617, are used for neuroendocrine tumors and metastatic castration&#8208;resistant prostate cancer, respectively, with significant therapeutic efficacy. The review focuses on new targets, such as fibroblast activation protein, CXCR4 chemokine receptors, and gastrin&#8208;releasing peptide receptors, and new delivery systems using nanotechnology to improve biodistribution and tumor accumulation. Challenges regarding production scalability, regulatory frameworks, and integrating artificial intelligence for personalized dosimetry and treatment planning remain crucial. Combination therapeutic approaches using targeted radionuclide therapy (TRT) in synergy with chemotherapy and immunotherapy and external beam radiation are showing promising results in refractory cancers. The potential avenues include theranostics, predictive modeling for patient selection, and new molecular targeting strategies. This review highlights the transformative potential of RPhs in precision oncology, providing an overview of the current clinical applications and future research trajectories toward improved cancer management.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e74c839e-82f9-4709-ade8-ef540a2c0739/cbic70148-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Advancements in Targeted Radiopharmaceuticals: Innovations in Diagnosis and Therapy for Enhanced Cancer Management"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiopharmaceuticals enable precise cancer diagnosis and targeted therapy by combining radioactive isotopes with carrier molecules. This review summarizes advances from 2014 to 2025, emphasizing probe design, click chemistry, novel targets, and nanodelivery systems. It highlights clinical progress, theranostic innovations, and future challenges in scalability, regulation, and AI-driven personalized treatment planning in precision oncology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiopharmaceuticals (RPhs) represent a breakthrough in nuclear medicine due to their ability to provide precise diagnosis and targeted therapy for cancer by incorporating radioactive isotopes into carrier molecules. This review systematically discusses the recent advances in the development of RPhs, focusing on state-of-the-art probe design strategies and click chemistry applications that accelerate RPh syntheses and improve targeting efficiency. The manuscript synthesizes literature from multiple databases spanning January 2014 to April 2025, encompassing diagnostic modalities including positron emission tomography (PET) and single-photon emission computed tomography (SPECT) imaging, and therapeutic applications utilizing alpha and beta emitters such as &lt;sup&gt;225&lt;/sup&gt;Ac and &lt;sup&gt;177&lt;/sup&gt;Lu. Clinically approved agents, such as &lt;sup&gt;177&lt;/sup&gt;Lu-DOTATATE and &lt;sup&gt;177&lt;/sup&gt;Lu-PSMA-617, are used for neuroendocrine tumors and metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer, respectively, with significant therapeutic efficacy. The review focuses on new targets, such as fibroblast activation protein, CXCR4 chemokine receptors, and gastrin-releasing peptide receptors, and new delivery systems using nanotechnology to improve biodistribution and tumor accumulation. Challenges regarding production scalability, regulatory frameworks, and integrating artificial intelligence for personalized dosimetry and treatment planning remain crucial. Combination therapeutic approaches using targeted radionuclide therapy (TRT) in synergy with chemotherapy and immunotherapy and external beam radiation are showing promising results in refractory cancers. The potential avenues include theranostics, predictive modeling for patient selection, and new molecular targeting strategies. This review highlights the transformative potential of RPhs in precision oncology, providing an overview of the current clinical applications and future research trajectories toward improved cancer management.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Mohd Sayeed Shaikh, 
Rupesh R. Kurhade, 
Abrar A. M. Siddiqui, 
Shaikh Shahbaz A. Majeed, 
Thomas J. Webster, 
Mohammad Intakhab Alam, 
Abdul Wasy Zia, 
Md. Faiyazuddin
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Advancements in Targeted Radiopharmaceuticals: Innovations in Diagnosis and Therapy for Enhanced Cancer Management</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500676</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500676</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500676</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500752</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500752</guid>
         <title>Engineering Biocompatible Metal&#8208;Based Nanoparticles for Advanced Antibacterial Therapy</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Effective treatment of bacterial infections requires metal nanoparticles (MNPs) that eradicate pathogens at the infection site without impairing tissue&#8208;cell proliferation or extracellular matrix remodeling. This review highlights recent engineering strategies that improve the biocompatibility of MNPs while maintaining their antibacterial efficacy.

The rapid emergence of antibiotic resistance has rendered many conventional antibiotics ineffective, complicating the management of bacterial infections and leading to severe community&#8208; and hospital&#8208;acquired diseases. This growing resistance crisis poses a major threat to global public health and the stability of healthcare systems. Metal&#8208;based nanoparticles have recently gained significant attention as alternative antibacterial agents because of their broad&#8208;spectrum activity and low likelihood of inducing bacterial resistance. However, their clinical translation remains limited by nonspecific cytotoxicity and poor biocompatibility, which can adversely affect mammalian cells. To overcome these challenges, recent research has focused on engineering strategies that enhance the biocompatibility of metal nanoparticles (MNPs) without compromising their antibacterial efficacy. This review summarizes the latest advances in the rational design, surface modification, and functionalization of biocompatible metal&#8208;based nanoplatforms for infection treatment. Themechanisms of antibacterial action, approaches to minimize off&#8208;target toxicity, and potential clinical application. Together, these insights highlight the promise of engineered MNPs as next&#8208;generation antibacterial therapeutics capable of addressing the escalating threat of multidrug&#8208;resistant infections.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/3ef6614f-2311-4501-9fef-0789a28141f3/cbic70174-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Engineering Biocompatible Metal-Based Nanoparticles for Advanced Antibacterial Therapy"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective treatment of bacterial infections requires metal nanoparticles (MNPs) that eradicate pathogens at the infection site without impairing tissue-cell proliferation or extracellular matrix remodeling. This review highlights recent engineering strategies that improve the biocompatibility of MNPs while maintaining their antibacterial efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid emergence of antibiotic resistance has rendered many conventional antibiotics ineffective, complicating the management of bacterial infections and leading to severe community- and hospital-acquired diseases. This growing resistance crisis poses a major threat to global public health and the stability of healthcare systems. Metal-based nanoparticles have recently gained significant attention as alternative antibacterial agents because of their broad-spectrum activity and low likelihood of inducing bacterial resistance. However, their clinical translation remains limited by nonspecific cytotoxicity and poor biocompatibility, which can adversely affect mammalian cells. To overcome these challenges, recent research has focused on engineering strategies that enhance the biocompatibility of metal nanoparticles (MNPs) without compromising their antibacterial efficacy. This review summarizes the latest advances in the rational design, surface modification, and functionalization of biocompatible metal-based nanoplatforms for infection treatment. Themechanisms of antibacterial action, approaches to minimize off-target toxicity, and potential clinical application. Together, these insights highlight the promise of engineered MNPs as next-generation antibacterial therapeutics capable of addressing the escalating threat of multidrug-resistant infections.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jiwon Kim, 
Khongorzul Enkhtaivan, 
Minje Kim, 
Seongjoong Lee, 
Sehee Kim, 
Seungbin Lee, 
Jaehee Jang, 
Yonghyun Choi, 
Jonghoon Choi
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>Engineering Biocompatible Metal&#8208;Based Nanoparticles for Advanced Antibacterial Therapy</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500752</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500752</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500752</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500518</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500518</guid>
         <title>From Molecule to Meaning: Click and Bioorthogonal Chemical Reporters for Plant Systems, Biological Imaging, and Artistic Expression</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
At the intersection of chemical biology, plant imaging, and contemporary art, this review introduces the concept of chembioart. By tracing how chemical reporters illuminate plant biomolecules in vivo, their role not only in advancing scientific understanding but also in inspiring transdisciplinary collaborations and visual expression&#160;is highlighted.

Chemical biology has reshaped the ability to investigate complex biological systems at the molecular level. In this context, chemical reporters have become important tools for labeling and tracking biomolecules in living systems with spatial and temporal precision. In plant biology, they provide an alternative to genetic approaches and allow the study of dynamic processes in species or organs that are not easily accessible. Through the use of click and bioorthogonal chemistry, small&#8208;molecule probes can be metabolically incorporated into specific molecular scaffolds such as sugars, monolignols, amino acids, and lipids. These probes make it possible to follow events like glycosylation, lignification, lipid turnover, or protein synthesis in living plant tissues. This review presents an overview of current chemical reporter strategies, from molecular design and synthetic considerations to their application in plant imaging. Herein, how these tools have contributed to the development of plant chemical biology by enabling precise and modular investigations of plant structure and metabolism is described. Herein, it is also examined how chemical reporters have entered interdisciplinary contexts, including collaborations between science and the arts. By converting molecular&#8208;level information into visual and sensory formats, these approaches open new perspectives for research, education, and communication across scientific and creative disciplines.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/0e0245e1-d6fb-467e-aaac-272518dede19/cbic70078-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="From Molecule to Meaning: Click and Bioorthogonal Chemical Reporters for Plant Systems, Biological Imaging, and Artistic Expression"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the intersection of chemical biology, plant imaging, and contemporary art, this review introduces the concept of chembioart. By tracing how chemical reporters illuminate plant biomolecules in vivo, their role not only in advancing scientific understanding but also in inspiring transdisciplinary collaborations and visual expression&#160;is highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemical biology has reshaped the ability to investigate complex biological systems at the molecular level. In this context, chemical reporters have become important tools for labeling and tracking biomolecules in living systems with spatial and temporal precision. In plant biology, they provide an alternative to genetic approaches and allow the study of dynamic processes in species or organs that are not easily accessible. Through the use of click and bioorthogonal chemistry, small-molecule probes can be metabolically incorporated into specific molecular scaffolds such as sugars, monolignols, amino acids, and lipids. These probes make it possible to follow events like glycosylation, lignification, lipid turnover, or protein synthesis in living plant tissues. This review presents an overview of current chemical reporter strategies, from molecular design and synthetic considerations to their application in plant imaging. Herein, how these tools have contributed to the development of plant chemical biology by enabling precise and modular investigations of plant structure and metabolism is described. Herein, it is also examined how chemical reporters have entered interdisciplinary contexts, including collaborations between science and the arts. By converting molecular-level information into visual and sensory formats, these approaches open new perspectives for research, education, and communication across scientific and creative disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Marie Hinnebo, 
Cl&#233;mence Simon, 
Ad&#232;le Tilouine, 
Corentin Spriet, 
Christophe Biot
</dc:creator>
         <category>Review</category>
         <dc:title>From Molecule to Meaning: Click and Bioorthogonal Chemical Reporters for Plant Systems, Biological Imaging, and Artistic Expression</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500518</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500518</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500518</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Review</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70191</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.70191</guid>
         <title>Front Cover: Photo&#8208;Induced Ultra&#8208;Fast Duplex Invasion Targeting Long&#8208;Range Double&#8208;Stranded DNA Using Artificial Nucleotide (ChemBioChem 1/2026)</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
This image depicts the mechanism of Photo&#8208;induced Duplex Invasion (pDI). The artwork illustrates how a single invading strand, modified with the 3&#8208;cyanovinylcarbazole nucleoside (CNVK), targets long double&#8208;stranded DNA. Under UV irradiation, this modification enables the strand to rapidly open the DNA helix and cross&#8208;link to its target sequence. This visual demonstrates the high efficiency of the pDI strategy for recognizing specific genetic sequences, holding significant potential for applications in biotechnology and genomic engineering. More details can be found in the Research Article by Kenzo Fujimoto and co&#8208;workers (DOI: 10.1002/cbic.202500626).
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/9138cb19-f007-4a72-b58e-9fe21f15fa36/cbic70191-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Front Cover: Photo-Induced Ultra-Fast Duplex Invasion Targeting Long-Range Double-Stranded DNA Using Artificial Nucleotide (ChemBioChem 1/2026)"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image depicts the mechanism of Photo-induced Duplex Invasion (pDI). The artwork illustrates how a single invading strand, modified with the 3-cyanovinylcarbazole nucleoside (&lt;sup&gt;CNV&lt;/sup&gt;K), targets long double-stranded DNA. Under UV irradiation, this modification enables the strand to rapidly open the DNA helix and cross-link to its target sequence. This visual demonstrates the high efficiency of the pDI strategy for recognizing specific genetic sequences, holding significant potential for applications in biotechnology and genomic engineering. More details can be found in the Research Article by Kenzo Fujimoto and co-workers (DOI: &lt;a target="_blank"
   title="Link to external resource"
   href="http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/cbic.202500626"&gt;10.1002/cbic.202500626&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Zumila Hailili, 
Yasuha Watanabe, 
Siddhant Sethi, 
Kenzo Fujimoto
</dc:creator>
         <category>Cover</category>
         <dc:title>Front Cover: Photo&#8208;Induced Ultra&#8208;Fast Duplex Invasion Targeting Long&#8208;Range Double&#8208;Stranded DNA Using Artificial Nucleotide (ChemBioChem 1/2026)</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.70191</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.70191</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70191</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Cover</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70192</link>
         <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.70192</guid>
         <title>Cover Feature: From Structure to Function: Development of Relaxin&#8208;3 Analogs and their Role in RXFP3 Signaling (ChemBioChem 1/2026)</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 1, January 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The RXFP3/Relaxin&#8208;3 system is implicated in behaviors such as addiction, anxiety and depression, making it an attractive pharmaceutical target. Because RXFP3 is primarily located in the central nervous system, achieving blood&#8211;brain barrier penetration is crucial. The cover depicts the relaxin family peptide receptor 3 and its ligand relaxin&#8208;3 in the bottom left corner, with key reported small molecules shown in white. The alpha helix in the background represents recently developed single&#8208;chain peptidomimetics. More details can be found in the Research Article by Mohammed Akhter Hossain and co&#8208;workers (DOI: 10.1002/cbic.202500664).
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/2e13de0c-95f4-4b67-a0c0-58cb037bfafa/cbic70192-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Cover Feature: From Structure to Function: Development of Relaxin-3 Analogs and their Role in RXFP3 Signaling (ChemBioChem 1/2026)"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RXFP3/Relaxin-3 system is implicated in behaviors such as addiction, anxiety and depression, making it an attractive pharmaceutical target. Because RXFP3 is primarily located in the central nervous system, achieving blood&#8211;brain barrier penetration is crucial. The cover depicts the relaxin family peptide receptor 3 and its ligand relaxin-3 in the bottom left corner, with key reported small molecules shown in white. The alpha helix in the background represents recently developed single-chain peptidomimetics. More details can be found in the Research Article by Mohammed Akhter Hossain and co-workers (DOI: &lt;a target="_blank"
   title="Link to external resource"
   href="http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/cbic.202500664"&gt;10.1002/cbic.202500664&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Isabelle Riches, 
Hongkang Wu, 
Predrag Kalaba, 
Ashish Sethi, 
Tim Lkhagvajargal, 
Philip J. Ryan, 
Ivan Maslov, 
Ross A. D. Bathgate, 
Mohammed Akhter Hossain
</dc:creator>
         <category>Cover</category>
         <dc:title>Cover Feature: From Structure to Function: Development of Relaxin&#8208;3 Analogs and their Role in RXFP3 Signaling (ChemBioChem 1/2026)</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.70192</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.70192</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70192</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Cover</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>1</prism:number>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>