<rss xmlns:atom="http://w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/" version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</title>
      <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      <description>Table of Contents for ChemBioChem. List of articles from both the latest and EarlyView issues.</description>
      <language>en-US</language>
      <copyright>&#169; Wiley-VCH GmbH, Weinheim</copyright>
      <managingEditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com (Chemistry Europe)</managingEditor>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:26:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>Atypon&#174; Literatum&#8482;</generator>
      <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <ttl>10080</ttl>
      <dc:title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
      <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</prism:publicationName>
      <atom:link href="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
      <image>
         <title>Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</title>
         <url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/14397633.jpg</url>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      </image>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500930</link>
         <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 22:27:53 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-02-01T10:27:53-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500930</guid>
         <title>Biocatalytic Synthesis of Diamondoid Diols by the Brown&#8208;Rot Fungus Wolfiporia cocos</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 3, February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Wolfiporia cocos cultures were tested for CH&#8208;oxidative activity using rigid diamondoid substrates. Adamantane derivatives gave typical diols similar to known chemical oxidations, while diamantane&#8208;4&#8208;ol showed unusual selectivity, forming rare 4,9&#8208; and 1,9&#8208;diols. Tests with supernatants and resting cells showed that oxidation occurred only in cells from 4&#8211;6&#8208;d cultures, active in water or at pH 2, but lost at higher pH.

The CH&#8208;oxidative activity of Wolfiporia cocos cultures of different ages was studied utilizing diamondoid derivatives as conformationally rigid models. Adamantane&#8208;1&#8208;ol and 1&#8208;bromoadamantane, traditional precursors for the synthesis of polysubstituted adamantanes, gave qualitatively similar reaction mixtures in which adamantane diols dominated. While the reactions occurred with high preparative yields, the biotransformation does not display clear differences from classic electrophilic or radical adamantane functionalization reactions. In contrast, the fungal oxidation of diamantane&#8208;4&#8208;ol occurred with unexpected selectivity yielding diamantane&#8208;4,9&#8208;diol and diamantane&#8208;1,9&#8208;diol. The latter product is quite uncharacteristic for diamantane chemistry because the most deactivated CH&#8208;position is attacked. To elucidate the active fungal component, additional experiments were performed with supernatant and resting cells harvested at various culture ages. Oxidative activity was detected in resting cells from 4&#8208; and 6&#8208;day&#8208;old cultures in pure water medium, and from 6&#8208;day&#8208;old cultures in buffer at pH 2, but disappeared at higher pH values.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e3d79f9c-75f2-475a-b7fe-05cc25bb72a5/cbic70214-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Biocatalytic Synthesis of Diamondoid Diols by the Brown-Rot Fungus Wolfiporia cocos"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wolfiporia cocos&lt;/i&gt; cultures were tested for CH-oxidative activity using rigid diamondoid substrates. Adamantane derivatives gave typical diols similar to known chemical oxidations, while diamantane-4-ol showed unusual selectivity, forming rare 4,9- and 1,9-diols. Tests with supernatants and resting cells showed that oxidation occurred only in cells from 4&#8211;6-d cultures, active in water or at pH 2, but lost at higher pH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CH-oxidative activity of &lt;i&gt;Wolfiporia cocos&lt;/i&gt; cultures of different ages was studied utilizing diamondoid derivatives as conformationally rigid models. Adamantane-1-ol and 1-bromoadamantane, traditional precursors for the synthesis of polysubstituted adamantanes, gave qualitatively similar reaction mixtures in which adamantane diols dominated. While the reactions occurred with high preparative yields, the biotransformation does not display clear differences from classic electrophilic or radical adamantane functionalization reactions. In contrast, the fungal oxidation of diamantane-4-ol occurred with unexpected selectivity yielding diamantane-4,9-diol and diamantane-1,9-diol. The latter product is quite uncharacteristic for diamantane chemistry because the most deactivated CH-position is attacked. To elucidate the active fungal component, additional experiments were performed with supernatant and resting cells harvested at various culture ages. Oxidative activity was detected in resting cells from 4- and 6-day-old cultures in pure water medium, and from 6-day-old cultures in buffer at pH 2, but disappeared at higher pH values.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Valeriia V. Nikitenkova, 
Aryna M. Sydorenko, 
Holger Zorn, 
Tatyana Zhuk
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Biocatalytic Synthesis of Diamondoid Diols by the Brown&#8208;Rot Fungus Wolfiporia cocos</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500930</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500930</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500930</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>3</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500827</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:31:48 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-30T09:31:48-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500827</guid>
         <title>Genetic Encoding of a Trifunctional Photo&#8208;Cross&#8208;Linker with a Cleavable Alkyl Ester Moiety</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 3, February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A novel noncanonical amino acid, DiZAAsu, possessing photo&#8208;cross&#8208;linking, biotinylation, and alkaline&#8208;cleavable functionalities, is genetically encoded by an engineered pyrrolyl&#8208;tRNA synthetase mutant. The alkyl ester moiety expands the design space of cleavable photo&#8208;cross&#8208;linkable amino acids.

Genetically encoded photo&#8208;cross&#8208;linkable amino acids (PAAs) are powerful tools for analyzing direct protein&#8211;protein interactions (PPIs) in mammalian cells. Cleavable PAAs are particularly useful, enabling covalent capture and subsequent release of interacting partners, which facilitates the characterization of interaction interfaces using mass spectrometry. However, the limited options for cleavable linker structures have restricted the design of PAAs. In this study, we genetically encoded a novel trifunctional PAA, DiZAAsu, which contains three distinct chemical groups: diazirine, alkyne, and alkaline&#8208;cleavable alkyl ester moieties. An archaeal pyrrolysyl&#8208;tRNA synthetase was engineered to incorporate DiZAAsu efficiently into proteins in mammalian cells. We demonstrated the in&#8208;cell photoreactive function of diazirine by cross&#8208;linking the DiZAAsu&#8208;introduced GRB2&#8201;protein to its binding partner, SHC. Using the alkyne group for biotinylation, we established a tandem affinity purification strategy that enabled efficient enrichment of the cross&#8211;linked complex, thereby reducing nonspecific protein contamination. The alkaline&#8208;based cleavage of the ester group in DiZAAsu was also demonstrated, confirming its potential for the dissociation of covalently linked complexes. This system thus expands the design space of multifunctional PAAs and adds alkaline&#8208;based dissociation to the limited repertoire of available cleavage strategies.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/7f4d856a-529b-4748-b21c-42d4795d68db/cbic70202-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Genetic Encoding of a Trifunctional Photo-Cross-Linker with a Cleavable Alkyl Ester Moiety"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel noncanonical amino acid, DiZAAsu, possessing photo-cross-linking, biotinylation, and alkaline-cleavable functionalities, is genetically encoded by an engineered pyrrolyl-tRNA synthetase mutant. The alkyl ester moiety expands the design space of cleavable photo-cross-linkable amino acids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetically encoded photo-cross-linkable amino acids (PAAs) are powerful tools for analyzing direct protein&#8211;protein interactions (PPIs) in mammalian cells. Cleavable PAAs are particularly useful, enabling covalent capture and subsequent release of interacting partners, which facilitates the characterization of interaction interfaces using mass spectrometry. However, the limited options for cleavable linker structures have restricted the design of PAAs. In this study, we genetically encoded a novel trifunctional PAA, DiZAAsu, which contains three distinct chemical groups: diazirine, alkyne, and alkaline-cleavable alkyl ester moieties. An archaeal pyrrolysyl-tRNA synthetase was engineered to incorporate DiZAAsu efficiently into proteins in mammalian cells. We demonstrated the in-cell photoreactive function of diazirine by cross-linking the DiZAAsu-introduced GRB2&#8201;protein to its binding partner, SHC. Using the alkyne group for biotinylation, we established a tandem affinity purification strategy that enabled efficient enrichment of the cross&#8211;linked complex, thereby reducing nonspecific protein contamination. The alkaline-based cleavage of the ester group in DiZAAsu was also demonstrated, confirming its potential for the dissociation of covalently linked complexes. This system thus expands the design space of multifunctional PAAs and adds alkaline-based dissociation to the limited repertoire of available cleavage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Masahiro Takayama, 
Tomoya Tsubota, 
Takao Yamaguchi, 
Kosuke Chiba, 
Takumi Yoshida, 
Yoshiyuki Hari, 
Yu&#8208;Shi Tian, 
Daisuke Takaya, 
Asuka Mori, 
Tomohito Tsukamoto, 
Kenji Ishimoto, 
Yukio Ago, 
Yoshiaki Okada, 
Kensaku Sakamoto, 
Takefumi Doi, 
Kaori Fukuzawa, 
Satoshi Obika, 
Shinsaku Nakagawa, 
Nobumasa Hino
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Genetic Encoding of a Trifunctional Photo&#8208;Cross&#8208;Linker with a Cleavable Alkyl Ester Moiety</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500827</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500827</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500827</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>3</prism:number>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>