<rss xmlns:atom="http://w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/" version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</title>
      <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      <description>Table of Contents for ChemBioChem. List of articles from both the latest and EarlyView issues.</description>
      <language>en-US</language>
      <copyright>&#169; Wiley-VCH GmbH, Weinheim</copyright>
      <managingEditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com (Chemistry Europe)</managingEditor>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:13:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>Atypon&#174; Literatum&#8482;</generator>
      <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <ttl>10080</ttl>
      <dc:title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
      <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</prism:publicationName>
      <atom:link href="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
      <image>
         <title>Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</title>
         <url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/14397633.jpg</url>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      </image>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500799</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 01:59:58 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-02-07T01:59:58-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500799</guid>
         <title>Structure&#8208;Guided Synthetic Peptide Targeting Nucleolus and Neural Progenitor Protein Nuclear Import Impairs Ribosome Biogenesis and Cancer Cell Proliferation</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 3, February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A structure&#8208;guided hexapeptide targets the R94 hotspot within the nucleolus and neural progenitor protein (NEPRO) nuclear localization signal (NLS), blocking its nuclear import and impairing 40S ribosome maturation. Peptide&#8208;mediated mislocalization of NEPRO induces translational stress and suppresses cancer cell proliferation, establishing NLS hotspots as druggable sites for peptide&#8208;based therapeutics.

Nucleolus and neural progenitor protein (NEPRO) is a nucleolar factor required for 40S ribosomal subunit maturation and is therefore essential for the high translational demand of proliferating cancer cells. Here, we identify a bipartite nuclear localization signal (NLS; aa 74&#8211;96) in NEPRO and show that residues in both basic clusters are required for nuclear targeting. A disease&#8208;associated mutation within the C&#8208;terminal cluster, R94C, abolished NEPRO nuclear localization and markedly reduced binding to importin&#8208;&#945;1 in vitro and in cells. Importin&#8208;&#945;1&#8211;NLS complexes revealed that R94 forms persistent hydrogen bonds, salt bridges, and hydrophobic contacts with importin&#8208;&#945;1 residues (A269, W273, P308, T311, P312, N350), explaining its central role in NLS recognition. Guided by these insights, we designed a rational synthetic hexapeptide inhibitor (H2N&#8208;AWPTPD&#8208;COOH) that is soluble, monodisperse, shows intrinsic fluorescence and is non&#8208;amyloidogenic. AWPTPD peptide binds wild&#8208;type NEPRO but not the R94C variant, and ab initio modeling shows peptide engagement of the R94 surface. Cellular delivery of the synthetic peptide significantly mislocalized NEPRO to the cytoplasm, reduced polysome abundance, decreased collagen secretion/deposition and clonogenicity, and induced cell&#8208;cycle arrest with upregulation of senescence markers: p16INK4A and p21WAF1/CIP1. These results validate R94 as a targetable hotspot in NEPRO's NLS and demonstrate a peptide&#8208;based approach to perturb ribosome biogenesis and suppress cancer cell growth.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/3d20b1db-9497-4977-9ffa-744b46befab7/cbic70223-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Structure-Guided Synthetic Peptide Targeting Nucleolus and Neural Progenitor Protein Nuclear Import Impairs Ribosome Biogenesis and Cancer Cell Proliferation"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A structure-guided hexapeptide targets the R94 hotspot within the nucleolus and neural progenitor protein (NEPRO) nuclear localization signal (NLS), blocking its nuclear import and impairing 40S ribosome maturation. Peptide-mediated mislocalization of NEPRO induces translational stress and suppresses cancer cell proliferation, establishing NLS hotspots as druggable sites for peptide-based therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nucleolus and neural progenitor protein (NEPRO) is a nucleolar factor required for 40S ribosomal subunit maturation and is therefore essential for the high translational demand of proliferating cancer cells. Here, we identify a bipartite nuclear localization signal (NLS; aa 74&#8211;96) in NEPRO and show that residues in both basic clusters are required for nuclear targeting. A disease-associated mutation within the C-terminal cluster, R94C, abolished NEPRO nuclear localization and markedly reduced binding to importin-&#945;1 in vitro and in cells. Importin-&#945;1&#8211;NLS complexes revealed that R94 forms persistent hydrogen bonds, salt bridges, and hydrophobic contacts with importin-&#945;1 residues (A269, W273, P308, T311, P312, N350), explaining its central role in NLS recognition. Guided by these insights, we designed a rational synthetic hexapeptide inhibitor (H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N-AWPTPD-COOH) that is soluble, monodisperse, shows intrinsic fluorescence and is non-amyloidogenic. AWPTPD peptide binds wild-type NEPRO but not the R94C variant, and ab initio modeling shows peptide engagement of the R94 surface. Cellular delivery of the synthetic peptide significantly mislocalized NEPRO to the cytoplasm, reduced polysome abundance, decreased collagen secretion/deposition and clonogenicity, and induced cell-cycle arrest with upregulation of senescence markers: p16&lt;sup&gt;INK4A&lt;/sup&gt; and p21&lt;sup&gt;WAF1/CIP1&lt;/sup&gt;. These results validate R94 as a targetable hotspot in NEPRO's NLS and demonstrate a peptide-based approach to perturb ribosome biogenesis and suppress cancer cell growth.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Abhishek Kumar, 
Suvam Saha, 
Yogendra Pratap Mathuria, 
Mukesh Kumar, 
Shailesh Kumar Gupta, 
Debasish Kumar Ghosh
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Structure&#8208;Guided Synthetic Peptide Targeting Nucleolus and Neural Progenitor Protein Nuclear Import Impairs Ribosome Biogenesis and Cancer Cell Proliferation</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500799</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500799</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500799</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>3</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500711</link>
         <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:50:06 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-02-05T12:50:06-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500711</guid>
         <title>Enhancement of Nitrogenase Activity in Recombinant Escherichia coli by Replacing Upstream Region of nif Operon from Paenibacillus Species</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 3, February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Biological N2 fixation by nitrogenase offers a sustainable alternative to the Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Heterologous nitrogenase production in Escherichia coli is a promising strategy. We engineered E. coli with nitrogen fixation (nif) operons from diazotrophic Paenibacillus species. To overcome expression limits, promoter replacement and synthetic approaches were applied. These enhancements improved activity and offer insights into optimizing nif expression.

Recombinant Escherichia coli with nitrogen&#8208;fixation activity has been constructed using a simple approach of introducing a minimal gene set of nitrogen fixation (nif) genes along with its upstream region from Paenibacillus species; however, limitations may exist in nif expression. To understand the limitations of heterologous mass production of nitrogenase in E. coli, we evaluated this approach using various nif operons cloned from Paenibacillus species. Initial attempts revealed that, despite the high nitrogenase activity observed in the parental strains, the corresponding nif operons did not consistently function in E. coli. Further analysis revealed that certain upstream regions of the nif operons function as constitutive &#963;70&#8208;dependent promoters in E. coli, and the host acquired nitrogenase activity only when the upstream region acted as a constitutive promoter. Notably, recombinant E. coli achieved high nitrogenase activity by linking a functional upstream region to the nif operon from a highly active parental strain. Additional improvements in nitrogenase activity were achieved by combining promoter replacement with synthetic biology approaches to enhance electron transfer from glucose metabolism to nitrogenase and metal cluster assembly for protein maturation. These findings provide new insights into heterologous nitrogenase production in E. coli for sustainable nitrogen fixation.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e8074d74-cb68-411e-a8a2-0d08df8e0280/cbic70219-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Enhancement of Nitrogenase Activity in Recombinant Escherichia coli by Replacing Upstream Region of nif Operon from Paenibacillus Species"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biological N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; fixation by nitrogenase offers a sustainable alternative to the Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Heterologous nitrogenase production in &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; is a promising strategy. We engineered &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt; with nitrogen fixation (&lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt;) operons from diazotrophic &lt;i&gt;Paenibacillus&lt;/i&gt; species. To overcome expression limits, promoter replacement and synthetic approaches were applied. These enhancements improved activity and offer insights into optimizing nif expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recombinant &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; with nitrogen-fixation activity has been constructed using a simple approach of introducing a minimal gene set of nitrogen fixation (&lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt;) genes along with its upstream region from &lt;i&gt;Paenibacillus&lt;/i&gt; species; however, limitations may exist in &lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt; expression. To understand the limitations of heterologous mass production of nitrogenase in &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt;, we evaluated this approach using various &lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt; operons cloned from &lt;i&gt;Paenibacillus&lt;/i&gt; species. Initial attempts revealed that, despite the high nitrogenase activity observed in the parental strains, the corresponding &lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt; operons did not consistently function in &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt;. Further analysis revealed that certain upstream regions of the &lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt; operons function as constitutive &#963;&lt;sup&gt;70&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent promoters in &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt;, and the host acquired nitrogenase activity only when the upstream region acted as a constitutive promoter. Notably, recombinant &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt; achieved high nitrogenase activity by linking a functional upstream region to the &lt;i&gt;nif&lt;/i&gt; operon from a highly active parental strain. Additional improvements in nitrogenase activity were achieved by combining promoter replacement with synthetic biology approaches to enhance electron transfer from glucose metabolism to nitrogenase and metal cluster assembly for protein maturation. These findings provide new insights into heterologous nitrogenase production in &lt;i&gt;E. coli&lt;/i&gt; for sustainable nitrogen fixation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Yuki Honda, 
Kotone Takeuchi, 
Sawako Hayakawa, 
Daisuke Koma, 
Hiroshi Fujii
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Enhancement of Nitrogenase Activity in Recombinant Escherichia coli by Replacing Upstream Region of nif Operon from Paenibacillus Species</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500711</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500711</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500711</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>3</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500930</link>
         <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 22:27:53 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-02-01T10:27:53-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500930</guid>
         <title>Biocatalytic Synthesis of Diamondoid Diols by the Brown&#8208;Rot Fungus Wolfiporia cocos</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 3, February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Wolfiporia cocos cultures were tested for CH&#8208;oxidative activity using rigid diamondoid substrates. Adamantane derivatives gave typical diols similar to known chemical oxidations, while diamantane&#8208;4&#8208;ol showed unusual selectivity, forming rare 4,9&#8208; and 1,9&#8208;diols. Tests with supernatants and resting cells showed that oxidation occurred only in cells from 4&#8211;6&#8208;d cultures, active in water or at pH 2, but lost at higher pH.

The CH&#8208;oxidative activity of Wolfiporia cocos cultures of different ages was studied utilizing diamondoid derivatives as conformationally rigid models. Adamantane&#8208;1&#8208;ol and 1&#8208;bromoadamantane, traditional precursors for the synthesis of polysubstituted adamantanes, gave qualitatively similar reaction mixtures in which adamantane diols dominated. While the reactions occurred with high preparative yields, the biotransformation does not display clear differences from classic electrophilic or radical adamantane functionalization reactions. In contrast, the fungal oxidation of diamantane&#8208;4&#8208;ol occurred with unexpected selectivity yielding diamantane&#8208;4,9&#8208;diol and diamantane&#8208;1,9&#8208;diol. The latter product is quite uncharacteristic for diamantane chemistry because the most deactivated CH&#8208;position is attacked. To elucidate the active fungal component, additional experiments were performed with supernatant and resting cells harvested at various culture ages. Oxidative activity was detected in resting cells from 4&#8208; and 6&#8208;day&#8208;old cultures in pure water medium, and from 6&#8208;day&#8208;old cultures in buffer at pH 2, but disappeared at higher pH values.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/e3d79f9c-75f2-475a-b7fe-05cc25bb72a5/cbic70214-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Biocatalytic Synthesis of Diamondoid Diols by the Brown-Rot Fungus Wolfiporia cocos"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wolfiporia cocos&lt;/i&gt; cultures were tested for CH-oxidative activity using rigid diamondoid substrates. Adamantane derivatives gave typical diols similar to known chemical oxidations, while diamantane-4-ol showed unusual selectivity, forming rare 4,9- and 1,9-diols. Tests with supernatants and resting cells showed that oxidation occurred only in cells from 4&#8211;6-d cultures, active in water or at pH 2, but lost at higher pH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CH-oxidative activity of &lt;i&gt;Wolfiporia cocos&lt;/i&gt; cultures of different ages was studied utilizing diamondoid derivatives as conformationally rigid models. Adamantane-1-ol and 1-bromoadamantane, traditional precursors for the synthesis of polysubstituted adamantanes, gave qualitatively similar reaction mixtures in which adamantane diols dominated. While the reactions occurred with high preparative yields, the biotransformation does not display clear differences from classic electrophilic or radical adamantane functionalization reactions. In contrast, the fungal oxidation of diamantane-4-ol occurred with unexpected selectivity yielding diamantane-4,9-diol and diamantane-1,9-diol. The latter product is quite uncharacteristic for diamantane chemistry because the most deactivated CH-position is attacked. To elucidate the active fungal component, additional experiments were performed with supernatant and resting cells harvested at various culture ages. Oxidative activity was detected in resting cells from 4- and 6-day-old cultures in pure water medium, and from 6-day-old cultures in buffer at pH 2, but disappeared at higher pH values.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Valeriia V. Nikitenkova, 
Aryna M. Sydorenko, 
Holger Zorn, 
Tatyana Zhuk
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Biocatalytic Synthesis of Diamondoid Diols by the Brown&#8208;Rot Fungus Wolfiporia cocos</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500930</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500930</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500930</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>3</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500827</link>
         <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:31:48 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-01-30T09:31:48-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500827</guid>
         <title>Genetic Encoding of a Trifunctional Photo&#8208;Cross&#8208;Linker with a Cleavable Alkyl Ester Moiety</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 3, February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
A novel noncanonical amino acid, DiZAAsu, possessing photo&#8208;cross&#8208;linking, biotinylation, and alkaline&#8208;cleavable functionalities, is genetically encoded by an engineered pyrrolyl&#8208;tRNA synthetase mutant. The alkyl ester moiety expands the design space of cleavable photo&#8208;cross&#8208;linkable amino acids.

Genetically encoded photo&#8208;cross&#8208;linkable amino acids (PAAs) are powerful tools for analyzing direct protein&#8211;protein interactions (PPIs) in mammalian cells. Cleavable PAAs are particularly useful, enabling covalent capture and subsequent release of interacting partners, which facilitates the characterization of interaction interfaces using mass spectrometry. However, the limited options for cleavable linker structures have restricted the design of PAAs. In this study, we genetically encoded a novel trifunctional PAA, DiZAAsu, which contains three distinct chemical groups: diazirine, alkyne, and alkaline&#8208;cleavable alkyl ester moieties. An archaeal pyrrolysyl&#8208;tRNA synthetase was engineered to incorporate DiZAAsu efficiently into proteins in mammalian cells. We demonstrated the in&#8208;cell photoreactive function of diazirine by cross&#8208;linking the DiZAAsu&#8208;introduced GRB2&#8201;protein to its binding partner, SHC. Using the alkyne group for biotinylation, we established a tandem affinity purification strategy that enabled efficient enrichment of the cross&#8211;linked complex, thereby reducing nonspecific protein contamination. The alkaline&#8208;based cleavage of the ester group in DiZAAsu was also demonstrated, confirming its potential for the dissociation of covalently linked complexes. This system thus expands the design space of multifunctional PAAs and adds alkaline&#8208;based dissociation to the limited repertoire of available cleavage strategies.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/7f4d856a-529b-4748-b21c-42d4795d68db/cbic70202-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Genetic Encoding of a Trifunctional Photo-Cross-Linker with a Cleavable Alkyl Ester Moiety"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel noncanonical amino acid, DiZAAsu, possessing photo-cross-linking, biotinylation, and alkaline-cleavable functionalities, is genetically encoded by an engineered pyrrolyl-tRNA synthetase mutant. The alkyl ester moiety expands the design space of cleavable photo-cross-linkable amino acids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetically encoded photo-cross-linkable amino acids (PAAs) are powerful tools for analyzing direct protein&#8211;protein interactions (PPIs) in mammalian cells. Cleavable PAAs are particularly useful, enabling covalent capture and subsequent release of interacting partners, which facilitates the characterization of interaction interfaces using mass spectrometry. However, the limited options for cleavable linker structures have restricted the design of PAAs. In this study, we genetically encoded a novel trifunctional PAA, DiZAAsu, which contains three distinct chemical groups: diazirine, alkyne, and alkaline-cleavable alkyl ester moieties. An archaeal pyrrolysyl-tRNA synthetase was engineered to incorporate DiZAAsu efficiently into proteins in mammalian cells. We demonstrated the in-cell photoreactive function of diazirine by cross-linking the DiZAAsu-introduced GRB2&#8201;protein to its binding partner, SHC. Using the alkyne group for biotinylation, we established a tandem affinity purification strategy that enabled efficient enrichment of the cross&#8211;linked complex, thereby reducing nonspecific protein contamination. The alkaline-based cleavage of the ester group in DiZAAsu was also demonstrated, confirming its potential for the dissociation of covalently linked complexes. This system thus expands the design space of multifunctional PAAs and adds alkaline-based dissociation to the limited repertoire of available cleavage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Masahiro Takayama, 
Tomoya Tsubota, 
Takao Yamaguchi, 
Kosuke Chiba, 
Takumi Yoshida, 
Yoshiyuki Hari, 
Yu&#8208;Shi Tian, 
Daisuke Takaya, 
Asuka Mori, 
Tomohito Tsukamoto, 
Kenji Ishimoto, 
Yukio Ago, 
Yoshiaki Okada, 
Kensaku Sakamoto, 
Takefumi Doi, 
Kaori Fukuzawa, 
Satoshi Obika, 
Shinsaku Nakagawa, 
Nobumasa Hino
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>Genetic Encoding of a Trifunctional Photo&#8208;Cross&#8208;Linker with a Cleavable Alkyl Ester Moiety</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500827</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500827</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500827</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>3</prism:number>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>