<rss xmlns:atom="http://w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/" version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</title>
      <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      <description>Table of Contents for ChemBioChem. List of articles from both the latest and EarlyView issues.</description>
      <language>en-US</language>
      <copyright>&#169; Wiley-VCH GmbH, Weinheim</copyright>
      <managingEditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com (Chemistry Europe)</managingEditor>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:16:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>Atypon&#174; Literatum&#8482;</generator>
      <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      <ttl>10080</ttl>
      <dc:title>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
      <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem (no repeats)</prism:publicationName>
      <atom:link href="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
      <image>
         <title>Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</title>
         <url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/14397633.jpg</url>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633</link>
      </image>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500915</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:51:26 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-02-14T07:51:26-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.202500915</guid>
         <title>RNA Hairpin Synthesis by RNase&#8208;Catalyzed Dynamic Covalent Chemistry</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 4, 25 February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
Ribonucleases are widely regarded as degradative enzymes, but the reversibility of RNA cleavage also enables ligation through cyclic phosphate intermediates. Here, RNase T1 is repurposed as a catalyst for RNA dynamic covalent chemistry, driving the thermodynamically controlled recombination of short strands into stable hairpins. The reaction is highly selective and functions under diverse conditions, revealing a constructive role for RNases in programmable RNA assembly.

Dynamic covalent chemistry (DCC) provides a powerful framework for assembling complex molecular architectures under thermodynamic control. Here, we extend RNA DCC by harnessing the ability of RNase T1&#8212;traditionally used as a degradative enzyme&#8212;to catalyze reversible phosphodiester exchange. Although enzyme&#8208;mediated RNA ligation has been reported previously, such reactions typically required high substrate concentrations and yielded heterogeneous mixtures without structural control. By coupling catalysis to RNA folding, selective formation of well&#8208;defined hairpin products governed by thermodynamic stability was achieved. PAGE, LC&#8208;MS, and NMR analyses confirm high&#8208;fidelity ligation at low temperatures with yields up to 61%, directed by loop stability and stem complementarity. Four distinct RNA oligomers assemble into two hairpins in one pot without cross&#8208;ligation, demonstrating RNA DCC as a programmable strategy for equilibrium RNA assembly. This work outlines an RNase&#8208;catalyzed framework for structure&#8208;guided RNA recombination, showcasing an underexplored pathway for the ligation of folded RNA polymers.
</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/29ff2441-4c54-4d63-b721-f077df88606d/cbic70194-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="RNA Hairpin Synthesis by RNase-Catalyzed Dynamic Covalent Chemistry"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ribonucleases are widely regarded as degradative enzymes, but the reversibility of RNA cleavage also enables ligation through cyclic phosphate intermediates. Here, RNase T&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; is repurposed as a catalyst for RNA dynamic covalent chemistry, driving the thermodynamically controlled recombination of short strands into stable hairpins. The reaction is highly selective and functions under diverse conditions, revealing a constructive role for RNases in programmable RNA assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic covalent chemistry (DCC) provides a powerful framework for assembling complex molecular architectures under thermodynamic control. Here, we extend RNA DCC by harnessing the ability of RNase T&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8212;traditionally used as a degradative enzyme&#8212;to catalyze reversible phosphodiester exchange. Although enzyme-mediated RNA ligation has been reported previously, such reactions typically required high substrate concentrations and yielded heterogeneous mixtures without structural control. By coupling catalysis to RNA folding, selective formation of well-defined hairpin products governed by thermodynamic stability was achieved. PAGE, LC-MS, and NMR analyses confirm high-fidelity ligation at low temperatures with yields up to 61%, directed by loop stability and stem complementarity. Four distinct RNA oligomers assemble into two hairpins in one pot without cross-ligation, demonstrating RNA DCC as a programmable strategy for equilibrium RNA assembly. This work outlines an RNase-catalyzed framework for structure-guided RNA recombination, showcasing an underexplored pathway for the ligation of folded RNA polymers.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Jonas Kaltbeitzel, 
Tejaswi Senthilkumar, 
Yazhinee Sathiyamoorthy, 
Susannah L. Brown, 
Aidan Sajowitz, 
Hsiu L. Li, 
Luke K. Marshall, 
Ravindra Kokate, 
Priyank Kumar, 
Pall Thordarson, 
Albert C. Fahrenbach
</dc:creator>
         <category>Research Article</category>
         <dc:title>RNA Hairpin Synthesis by RNase&#8208;Catalyzed Dynamic Covalent Chemistry</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.202500915</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.202500915</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.202500915</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Research Article</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>4</prism:number>
      </item>
      <item>
         <link>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70251</link>
         <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:37:59 -0800</pubDate>
         <dc:date>2026-02-14T06:37:59-08:00</dc:date>
         <source url="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14397633">Wiley: ChemBioChem: Table of Contents</source>
         <prism:coverDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDate>
         <prism:coverDisplayDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverDisplayDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">10.1002/cbic.70251</guid>
         <title>Front Cover: Protein Structure Determination by Racemic and Quasi&#8208;Racemic X&#8208;Ray Crystallography (ChemBioChem 4/2026)</title>
         <description>ChemBioChem, Volume 27, Issue 4, 25 February 2026. </description>
         <dc:description>
The Cover images shown here illustrate the diversity of protein molecular structures elucidated by crystallization of racemic and quasi&#8208;racemic protein mixtures. The protein structures range in size from rubredoxin (6 kDa) to a heterochiral protein complex of 36.5 kDa; they include proteins of novel cyclic covalent polypeptide topology, protein side chain&#8208;linked oligomers, homodimeric proteins, de novo designed proteins, and proteins of unprecedented secondary structure. Racemic and quasi&#8208;racemic protein mixtures facilitate formation of diffraction&#8208;quality crystals, simplify structure solution, and yield higher quality electron density maps. More details can be found in the Review Article by Stephen Kent (DOI: 10.1002/cbic.202500950).








</dc:description>
         <content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/4f2296f8-5c71-4af3-8a45-95928f8b1817/cbic70251-blkfxd-0001-m.png"
     alt="Front Cover: Protein Structure Determination by Racemic and Quasi-Racemic X-Ray Crystallography (ChemBioChem 4/2026)"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cover images shown here illustrate the diversity of protein molecular structures elucidated by crystallization of racemic and quasi-racemic protein mixtures. The protein structures range in size from rubredoxin (6 kDa) to a heterochiral protein complex of 36.5 kDa; they include proteins of novel cyclic covalent polypeptide topology, protein side chain-linked oligomers, homodimeric proteins, de novo designed proteins, and proteins of unprecedented secondary structure. Racemic and quasi-racemic protein mixtures facilitate formation of diffraction-quality crystals, simplify structure solution, and yield higher quality electron density maps. More details can be found in the Review Article by Stephen Kent (DOI: &lt;a target="_blank"
   title="Link to external resource"
   href="http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/cbic.202500950"&gt;10.1002/cbic.202500950&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</content:encoded>
         <dc:creator>
Stephen B. H. Kent
</dc:creator>
         <category>Cover</category>
         <dc:title>Front Cover: Protein Structure Determination by Racemic and Quasi&#8208;Racemic X&#8208;Ray Crystallography (ChemBioChem 4/2026)</dc:title>
         <dc:identifier>10.1002/cbic.70251</dc:identifier>
         <prism:publicationName>ChemBioChem</prism:publicationName>
         <prism:doi>10.1002/cbic.70251</prism:doi>
         <prism:url>https://chemistry-europe.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cbic.70251</prism:url>
         <prism:section>Cover</prism:section>
         <prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
         <prism:number>4</prism:number>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>